<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://chvck.co.uk/</id><updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Dyfi Enduro 2014</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2014/May/05/dyfi-enduro-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2014-05-05:posts/2014/May/05/dyfi-enduro-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend marked the annual &lt;a href="http://www.summitcycles.co.uk/enduro/"&gt;Dyfi Enduro&lt;/a&gt; ride, this year a choice was given 
to ride 45km or 55km. I entered the 55km with the aim of getting to the bar at the bottom of dickos within around 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul came over Thursday night and we headed to Eastridge to meet Andy so that I could show them round. We had a great ride
and Andy had no trouble at all with the steep line, I managed to crash on it twice! We rode all the usual suspects although Paul ran most
of it and freewheeled the descents as his rear mech hanger snapped just before the zig zag climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broken mech hanger" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-PHwmz-5TlCw/U2d5cMoI2mI/AAAAAAAAEMU/mgAXcL9s-fo/s640/P1000550.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After riding, Paul and I continued on to aber to Dan's house where we'd be staying the night. We met up with Joe and Nick for some food in the &lt;a href="http://www.glengower.co.uk/"&gt;glen&lt;/a&gt;
before moving on to the ship and castle for more beer than was planned. Dan, the genius, had left some chicken cooking whilst we were out so we came back to a full meal of chicken with
rice n peas. Top job! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we met Joe, Nick and a few others at Capel Dewi for a bit of a play about on some DH tracks. One side of the woods is quite lost to fallen trees
but there are still plenty of tracks. I managed to badly case a double and hit my shoulder pretty hard but walked away from it so all good but a bit sore now. Joe hit the smallest (it ain't small) of the
road gaps a couple of times and generally a good time was had by all. After riding Paul and I headed on to Mach and setup our tents etc... before being joined by Ben n Steph shortly after.
Once Jase arrived we headed off to find food and wound up with dirty kebab shop pizzas, did the job though. We had a drink or two each in the beer tent before heading off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Corners!" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-5GL7HHL5_Yc/U2d7E5g2HuI/AAAAAAAAENY/uvQKRYBpK8I/s640/P1000558.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Joe sending a road gap" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-NyG4Q8X6548/U2d9UUXO8fI/AAAAAAAAEPE/_VjCbJN0Q5g/s640/P1000576.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Double" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-rS6YfVh2f78/U2d-dWesgEI/AAAAAAAAEP0/vjivQ5dZ6m4/s640/P1000582.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Absurd sender" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jncVfC9xfIY/U2d-f6orAvI/AAAAAAAAEP8/f0ohdAANf5E/s640/P1000583.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fallen trees" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-EZodGn4KSt8/U2d-_9sX58I/AAAAAAAAEQM/Xvrh4nmvpzQ/s640/P1000585.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Setup" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-nxaogI6eQSQ/U2eABy2PlFI/AAAAAAAAEQ8/g-GdBT7V1dY/s640/P1000591.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beer tent" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-WpHKHcifxRQ/U2eAL-64qEI/AAAAAAAAERM/uF7vb2AR7zA/s640/P1000595.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beer tent outside" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-_qjgkkRGuhk/U2eASFbehoI/AAAAAAAAERc/XA_0kmZtHxk/s640/P1000597.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main event! Around 10.30 we headed to queue up for the start, already we were starting quite a way back and the start wasn't until 11! We had the rider briefing and off we went. I wanted to get
to the top of the first climb as quickly as I could to avoid the bottleneck that always occurs at the first descent. That, I managed to do - along with Paul and Harris. Shortly after the first descent I lost them
after I stopped for a wee. I was feeling quite good until I fell off on the second part of baileys. I was on some bedrock and both of my wheels disappeared as I tried to alter my line. Luckily I got away with no
major damage but did bruise both of my hands which made for some painful descending the rest of the day. Jase passed me as I was having a break at the top of World Cup and I managed to catch him on the climb so we rode together
up to the feed station. Cake, hi5 and nanas consumed it was quickly time to crack on again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we were riding with Paul and Harris again but once again they all quite quickly disappeared into the distance.
I pushed the whole of the singletrack climb up to goshawk as my legs were hurting pretty badly but I got a pretty clear run down goshawk which was ace. At the bottom I hopped into a compression and BANG, tyre was flat instantly.
I couldn't see any problems with the tyre so thought that it had somehow just burped majorly. Threw a tube in and off I went. Half way up the next climb I heard a hissing... Jumped off the bike and found that the tube was poking through
a big hole in the tyre. Balls. I'd used my only tube so started walking, a very kind chap gave me a tube so I set to work with my toothpaste tube tyre boot but, alas, it wasn't big enough for the hole. Another very generous person
came to my rescue and gave me a Park Tool tyre boot. I managed to get it all fitted (took a few goes as even that boot wasn't quite big enough) and wahey I was off again. I was quite fresh by this point having rested for
over 30 minutes fixing the tyre so stormed up to dickos. I decided that it probably wasn't a great plan to ride dickos so tried to skirt round on a fireroad. Just after I passed the first crossing on dickos the fireroad went uphill
again and I was not having that so cracked on down dickos itself. Just past the photographer and about 10 metres from the end of the track I crashed again, scraping my right hand side down some rocks. That one hurt a bit but
all the damage was superficial so I picked myself back up and got myself over to the bar at the bottom for a small beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tyre hole" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-ZaeuWwRaZo4/U2eCTi620vI/AAAAAAAAETM/izh6Y8DYLf4/s640/P1000611.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I decided that the long route probably wasn't wise with a big hole in my tyre so headed to the finish. Luckily, Paul had only just finished the long loop so we headed back together. About half way back my bike 
started to get a bit bouncy, another tube down. Paul had a large boot in the form of part of a milk carton so we fitted that and a new tube. That got me back to mach no worries where we got our mugs and caught up with everyone 
else to see how they got on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After showers we wandered over the road to where there was a smaller beer tent and a couple of food vendors. We first went for mexican from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Green-Goat-Cafe/353083144764903"&gt;the Green Goat&lt;/a&gt;.
Jolly good it was too, this beer tent was empty so we also managed to use some sofas which was somewhat nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Smaller beer tent" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-46VMWfO9jU0/U2eBU1zBmRI/AAAAAAAAESM/P3C9kCDrBeQ/s640/P1000602.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Courtyard" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-b-iDkCoZ8zE/U2eBsnF8QXI/AAAAAAAAESk/ERyI_zjTTvg/s640/P1000604.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then chose to sample the burger stand, I had falafel. This was also a win, after another drink we headed back to Dyfi HQ where we drank some more and caught up with old faces. There was also some entertainment
in the form of a fire ring with people riding through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fire ring" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-bPaIResIlSc/U2eCM1GOzaI/AAAAAAAAETE/gqy7hlOYFmA/s640/P1000610.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cracking weekend despite the actual dyfi ride not going my way. Big respect to Paul for riding it singlespeed when he isn't used to it. Big thanks to the organisers and all of the marshalls and people lining the course
in various places too. I managed somewhere around 4h30 for the 45km loop so if I hadn't had problems with my tyre then I'm confident I would have made the bar by 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="dyfi"></category></entry><entry><title>Red Kite Events Gravity Enduro 1</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2014/Apr/29/red-kite-events-gravity-enduro-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2014-04-29:posts/2014/Apr/29/red-kite-events-gravity-enduro-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend was the &lt;a href="http://redkite-events.co.uk/index.php"&gt;Red Kite Events&lt;/a&gt; gravity enduro 1 at Llanwrtyd Wells. This gravity enduro differed
from others that I've seen in that there were no strict stage start times. On Saturday stages were open 2pm-5pm and Sunday 10am - 5pm.
This meant that after finishing a stage you could wait for your mate(s) and then pedal on to the next stage in your own time (within reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Saturday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday was just 2 stages with practise in the morning. The stages opened at 2pm so I picked Rich up at around 9 and we got to 
Llanwrtyd Wells at about 11.30. We picked up our race plates and decided to crack to get in a practise loop before the stages opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We practised stage 1 and then moved onto stage 2, which was quite a long way away but the majority of the climb was on a long, shallow fireroad.
As we reached the bottom of stage 2 we met the organisers setting up the timing gate and they told us that we could do stage 2 timed before stage 
1, saving us pedalling back to 1 and then back to 2 again. Stage 2 was exposed with a short, slippery, rooty section at the top followed by a mixture of
flatout loose rocky descents and flat pedally sections all linked with sharp, open hairpins. Finishing with a grassy section into a hairpin and a sprint to the
finish. It was good fun and pretty difficult to ride the hairpins fast. My timed run went pretty well with no major issues but did stall out and have to scoot the bike on the very last corner as
it had an awkward hole toward the exit. Got down in 00:02:52 which put me at 19/25 for the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climb up to stage 1 was a long burner of a fireroad, not too steep but with a pretty viscious headwind for our practise run. Stage 1 itself
was fast singletrack with loose rock, plenty of ruts and a steep bedrock section. It was a fun descent although a bit too flat out for my tastes 
with a bit of a very short, sharp climb toward the end. In my timed run I hit a realy slow line at the top that had me hitting a large grass tuft and nearly coming to a stop. 
I also managed to get stuck in a rut that I didn't want to be in and crashed trying to get out of it. That left me turning into the bedrock chute a bit too sharp and hitting another big grass tuft,
I stayed on the bike but it all got a bit wild. Other than that the run went pretty alright! Got down in 00:03:04 which put me at 18/25 for the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all we managed about 34km, quite glad we managed to cut out about 15km by not having to go back to stage 1. After the stages we headed back to race HQ where Neil (the race organiser) 
provided us with a beer each and we had a good chat before another beer and then getting changed. I managed to pick a shower that
didn't go hot at all - a cold shower after a cold, wet ride (did I mention that I also fell off in a river?) was not the one! There aren't many showers in my life that I would describe as emotional but that was one of them.
After getting ready Rich n I headed to the pub for a couple of drinks before heading to the pasta party! As part of the event we had a free pasta meal at the &lt;a href="http://www.food-food-food.co.uk/"&gt;Drovers Rest&lt;/a&gt;. I opted
for the spag bol and good it was too. The results for the day also appeared, I was coming in at 18th with a time of 05:56:28 (bear in mind that 4 of the 25 riders weren't riding Saturday so just got a flat 5 minutes for each stage). 
Rich was in 13th with 05:03:78. That result was good enough for me! A couple of beers and it was time for bed. Camping in the rain, joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Sunday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up at around 8 and ready to go by 9.15, we were the first people to head out. We got to the top of stage 1 at about 10.05 and cracked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This went much better this time, despite being much more slippery from the rain. I hit the same crap line at the top as I totally forgot about but managed to keep it together for the entire run. It felt slower than Saturday
but I didn't crash and hit better lines so hoped for a better time. Turned out that I got 00:03:08 so slower despite not crashing! This time got me 21st for the stage and still 18th overall. Rich must have had a bit of a problem
as he came in slower than me and lost a couple of places to 16th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This run also felt slower than Saturday but I gave what I could in the sprints and managed to hit a better line around the bottom corner which cut off the actual corner. I had no idea how to stack this one up time wise. 
At the bottom of this stage we bumped into a fella called Chris who had an identical net time as Rich for Saturday. We continued to ride with him until stage 4. He's into his XC racing and seemed to be pretty rapid.
This stage I managed 20th in 00:03:06, another time slower than Saturday. This dropped me down to 19th overall. Rich managed to claw back to 15th after this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stage was ridden blind and was a good old pedal from stage 2 but after pedalling back up to the top of stage 2 it stayed on the top of the hill which was pretty nice. There was a short, rocky non-stage descent too :). Stage 3 could be described
only as utterly flatout. The surface was man made and ridiculously fast, mostly quite wide and straight with a couple of corners and hairpins. It went on for quite a while and as I was starting to feel a bit tired a climb appeared.
This was bad news. I dropped several gears and sprinted as well as I could (not very well) before it dropped into descent again. The finish was quite steep with a couple of big corners before the finish line. It was good
but really, really tiring! At this point we found out that one of the timing wands had broken and that we'd have to wait for all riders to come through stage 3 before we could ride stage 4, luckily there was a cafe nearby serving
hot food so we chilled out there for a while (we were the first people to reach the bottom of stage 3) before pedalling up to stage 4. I came in at 00:04:40 in 22nd for the stage keeping me in 19th overall. Rich had gained another place
to 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another blind stage. A couple of minutes after we got to stage 4 Neil turned up with the person doing the timing for the stage and told us to ride the top of stage 4 and loop back round as they'd be a few minutes.
This gave us a quick taste of what was to come. The top section was singletrack, wooded, really rooty and really slippery. I was happy! After we looped back round to the top we got ready to go.
I was going to be first off, there was a bit more of a delay and almost everyone was around before I went, including a few who had wandered down into the woods. Bit of pressure! But having people cheering in the woods felt good
and I kept it together. After doing the top section the track got a bit more difficult, less roots but a bit steeper with some steep, sharp corners. This section dropped onto the fireroad in a pretty horrific rut before going really steep
with a few steep, sharp corners. Unfortunately I came unclipped and rode at the finish line with 1 foot on the pedal, no problem BUT there was a bridge just before the finish and I missed it. This meant that I had to get off and 
run to the bridge and on to the finish. This was definitely my favourite stage! The track continued downhill to the cafe after the finish and that bit was pretty good fun too. This was my best stage (relative) to others despite
losing a bit of time at the end, I came in 1s behind Rich at 00:02:09 which was 15th for the stage. Despite this I dropped a place overall to 20th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stage 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to stage 5 was back the way we came from stage 2 (stage 5 and 2 were the same track). Starting with a steepish, longish climb back to the top of the hill. We made our way back until the route diverted off from the way that 
we came. Everything suddenly went very Dyfi. The track was quite undulating and all bedrock with some massive, deep puddles. It was quite fun but I wouldn't have minded not doing it by that point! We eventually made our way to the
top of the stage and cracked on. I believe the phrase is "had a mare". On the top rooty bit I managed to somehow come off. On the next section which was fast and loose into a hairpin I managed to just not be able to stop and overshot
the corner. Further down I crashed again! Remounted to find my bars were pointing nowhere near where the wheel was so had to dismount and pull them a bit straighter. I was also pretty shot for the sprints but gave what I had.
Definitely my worst run of the day but despite the crashes still finished in one piece which is a win in my books! As expected my time for this one wasn't good, 00:04:05. A minute slower than my run down stage 2 earlier in the day,
and 23rd for the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday turned out to be around 48km so a good size ride. We got back, cleaned bikes, selves and got changed. Had a cup of tea (beer for Rich) and then headed off with a couple of freebies - mucoff silicon spray and an ID system that attaches to your helmet. 
Despite the weather being horrible for pretty much the whole weekend it was a cracking event. I really enjoyed the format, being about to chill out a bit and ride the transitions with Rich. 
The event was quite small which meant that you recognised pretty much everyone when you saw them and made for a nice vibe. Overall I came 21st out of 25 with a clear indicator that to do better I need to be braver on the fast descents. 
Rich finished in 13th a couple of minutes up on me. Overall, I learnt some of the area and didn't muller myself so I'm a happy bunny. Bring on rounds 2 and 3, which apparently will have more stages like 4, woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="riding"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Playing in the Dyfi</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Oct/11/playing-in-the-dyfi/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-10-11:posts/2013/Oct/11/playing-in-the-dyfi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dyfi forest is always a highlight to any of my weeks or weekends. The riding is top notch.
I designed a route that took in every (very nearly anyway) descent that I knew on the Corris
side of the forest, including a bonus descent that I didn't know. We started off parking
just below the climachx car park (it was closed) and span our way up toward Elephant. On the way
up I spied footpath which I had thought had been logged so I decided that we'd throw this in as a bonus too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time that I did footpath was quite a long time ago now, it was a pretty wide, quite muddy descent. Pretty
average steepness for the dyfi. It's now a narrow, rocky descent but none-the-less still rather good. It is a bit of 
a short one though. Next, spin back up to Elephant! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Footpath" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-G5-Et8cD0AY/UlkVjLccBBI/AAAAAAAADn0/T1AJShHwAlU/s640/P1000420.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Elephant" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ziPSnPAuNPg/UlkVmLpz2hI/AAAAAAAADoE/WGciKjIZaHM/s640/P1000421.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always a classic, starts out with a fairly long flat out as you dare blast down a rut before hitting
a big bermed corner after which the trails unruts a bit and gets a bit rougher with a few small
drops. We skipped the new Gravity Enduro but that they recently dug and popped out of the fireroad.
We span along to the new bottom of Elephant (built for the enduro). This bit of trail is really, really
awesome. They've added a descent that the dyfi really needed IMO. It's almost all dirt, unlike all of the 
descents which are very rocky. After the enduro the descent is now very rutty but that makes it a bit like
riding on rails! I had to dab once going round a corner where my tyre scraped the inside of the rut but managed
to clean the rest including the pretty steep and slick bottom section. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Very bottom of Elephant" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-cNoshdUdxjc/UlkW80OtdnI/AAAAAAAADoQ/OTtGQRbVZ-8/s640/P1000423.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next it was back up to the top of this bit to tackle Builth which was riding the same as it has done for years. Fast,
rocky and pretty wild! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Builth" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-zOl3VbXX_8Y/UlkXBy53_KI/AAAAAAAADoY/pBYxxXn4KBk/s640/P1000425.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We span on up to the top of Dicko's which, again, is a Dyfi classic. With a mixture of rocks,
mud and (since the gravity enduro) a bit of loam. As always, it was errr fast, rocky and pretty wild. Back up the climb
past Builth and on Rocky Horror 1. I'd only done this once before and last time it was overgrown with brambles so I was prepared to
have to do some clearing, only had to clear 1 bramble! The rest of the run was clean. It's steep and very, very rocky down this one.
A few interesting bits where line choice matters quite a bit but yet another cracking descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dickos" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-YgasPQyudYQ/UlkYd5UQDEI/AAAAAAAADo8/ZPDdTRdxpVI/s640/P1000428.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Rocky Horror" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-tGCjA2U_ksA/UlkZrmifI2I/AAAAAAAADpQ/Zk8FyQwh82U/s640/P1000429.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back up the climb past builth yet again and we did the short Dyfi Warm Up enduro descent. It's a bit of fun, not too steep but rocky with
wheel grabbing holes if you pick your line wrong. We span back up past builth again (for the last time!) and cracked on to Nemesis. We found it
quite a way up a technical singletrack climb. I hadn't done this before. Wow! It's great. It started out a bit twisty and very steep before developing
out in a bit more of a flatout and then getting steep and tight again. Mixture of rocks and mud this time, mostly rocks! It dropped us out onto
a fireroad a bit in the middle of nowhere so it was a bit of a trek back up to Tony. Despite this, Nemesis is getting added to permanent list of 
Dyfi trails that need riding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nemesis" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-3P3i6mXMyWE/UlkZqq6LhII/AAAAAAAADpM/k57eVV6aFuE/s640/P1000431.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nemsis bottom" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-EgLNTEs6ysU/UlkbHjdBUrI/AAAAAAAADpk/d1z2KIabhdo/s640/P1000434.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished up on Tony the Tiger, the climachx final descent. Once again very rocky but also very long. Starts out in the woods and then opens up to 
where they've been logging before dropping back into the trees traversing back and forth along the hill before a load of tight(ish) switchbacks leading to the bottom.
A nice way to finish out a ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View near rocky horror" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nzXAx6HPiY/UlkbTcKSl0I/AAAAAAAADp0/iwLWn08Zxcw/s640/P1000435.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View from tony" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-JFIw0tlmA0o/UlkcI68XqBI/AAAAAAAADqE/gV0mBfGnsYM/s640/P1000437.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, I love the Dyfi.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="riding"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Marin &amp; Penmachno</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Oct/09/marin-penmachno/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-10-09:posts/2013/Oct/09/marin-penmachno/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before starting the guts of this post I just want to mention that after previous riding
this week my body was pretty sore and aching so that may bias my opinions on these trails. Pedalling
downhill pretty much just wasn't an option either. Going to be utterly ruined by Sunday - got Hopton, Dyfi and Eastridge to ride yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mbwales.com/en/content/cms/bases/betws_y_coed/marin_trail/marin_trail.aspx"&gt;Marin trail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Harris at the Marin car park at about 11.15, the reason we didn't go up together
was that he went via coed-y-brenin carpark to try find the rear maxle he lost on Sunday.
He did indeed find it, huzzah! I'd done the Marin a few times before but not for a long time.
Despite what a lot of people say on the internet I remembered really enjoying the Marin and it
being one of my favourite trail centres. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Marin map" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-9ZYtT8kZihI/UlWVQrJbSGI/AAAAAAAADj4/NSmbgEpxRYc/s640/P1000392.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite starting out with a singletrack climb, most of the Marin climbs are just nice fireroad spins.
I know that some people seem to dislike climbing on fireroads but to me it's the best way to do it, spin
away and conserve that energy for descending. Even on the first climb I could feel that my legs were still
recovering from the coedy enduro, a bit sore and hollow feeling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fireroad" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ojmQxcTsJPc/UlWVWBID9QI/AAAAAAAADkI/1LeHpEE8JTA/s640/P1000393.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part singletrack on the Marin trail is descending and good descending at that. There are some cracking descents there, the final one (Ride Fast Ride Free) being
really quite excellent - and pretty long to boot. Another couple of descents that I can actually remember (so must
have been of note) were "Pigs might fly" and "Dragon's Tail". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took us 2 hours to do the 23km at a casual, sore pace so it'd be doable for us in well under that. It's a cracking
bit of trail and is staying there as one of my favourite trail centres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stone structure" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-VNCOgYu4L5A/UlWWq-dtlUI/AAAAAAAADkk/9DuPz5P1fvs/s640/P1000396.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Good view" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-5KpdVSPNN_o/UlWXZ94428I/AAAAAAAADk8/a1jmFM4e37o/s640/P1000398.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mbwales.com/en/content/cms/Bases/Betws_y_Coed/Penmachno/Penmachno.aspx"&gt;Penmachno trail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Marin we headed down to Penmachno unsure whether we'd do just one or both loops. By this point
it had started to try to rain a bit but was generally still decent weather. We started out on a fireroad climb,
rounded a corner and &lt;em&gt;WHOOSH&lt;/em&gt; very gusty wind right into our faces, luckily this wind seemed to disappear at this 50m section!
This trail has a lot of singletrack, it also has its share of fireroad but the ratio of ST:fireroad was higher than
most trail centres that I've ridden. Unfornately, a lot of that singletrack is uphill or flat and the entire thing is
very rough. Harris was having a hard time of it on a hardtail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Craig Wen" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-npAQhas3IY8/UlWYrJCIFNI/AAAAAAAADlY/2KldNjwWhe0/s640/P1000403.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ben" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ypuW0d4t19A/UlWaI3EGVsI/AAAAAAAADl8/tOjVV-FvvkY/s640/P1000407.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the split for loop 1 or loop 2 (does an extra loop + loop 1) we had done 1 descent, and it was mediocre at that.
This led us to a decision that we'd only do loop 1 as this sort of trail just isn't our cup of tea. Luckily, it got 
better. Something worth mentioning is that this trail has a lot of fantastic views which at least redeems some of the horrible
climbing. There were 1 or 2 more decent descents before the final 2. The final 2 descents were good, the final 1 being
really good. Rocky, fairly challenging and fast. Oh, no need to pedal to feel fast either, just pumping - that's always high on my list
of desireable things from a descent. They were fast enough to pretty exciting (especially if you didn't hit your line right) but also
technical enough to be fun and a bit challenging. I love the feeling of barrelling along on trails that have a bit of something about them, 
really good feeling that is. The last 2 were what I've come to expect from Wales - they were very wet and very rocky with some steepish bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Penmachno first climb" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-U-ZlOhnSd68/UlWWuM4LFXI/AAAAAAAADks/wKWoXR3oM9E/s640/P1000399.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Waterfall" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-W1s5nuutbKU/UlWYNhHSzMI/AAAAAAAADlQ/nYhrbDZFRgo/s640/P1000400.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Yet more panorama" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-QHLZNx_Ic7A/UlWXFP9iQmI/AAAAAAAADk0/tM0u5E0ruyQ/s640/P1000401.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that I'd go back and do either of them but I'd take the Marin over Penmachno. If you go and only have time to do one then don't do either!
Instead, just do the final descents of both :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="riding"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Pelican Github Autopublish</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Oct/09/pelican-github-autopublish/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-10-09:posts/2013/Oct/09/pelican-github-autopublish/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This isn't strictly development but could be handy for someone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog uses a piece of software called &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, if you hadn't
guessed. Pelican is a static blog generator, this means that it takes a theme (some
HTMl like templates and some css), blog posts (mine are written in &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;)
and some settings and it creates a static html output ready to be hosted somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the hosting I use &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt;, mostly because I already
use github and it means that hosting is free. I'm a huge fan of free. These two marry
together quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do the publish I use &lt;a href="https://github.com/davisp/ghp-import"&gt;ghp-import&lt;/a&gt; and just push to my
gh-pages branch. &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.3.0/tips.html#publishing-to-github"&gt;The pelican docs actually describe how to set this up&lt;/a&gt;.
I use the post-commit hook approach and it's brilliant. BUT I don't want to have to run this stuff everytime,
I have to ssh into my server and then do a git add and commit. This is where my autopublish process comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step that I did was to move my blog post folder to dropbox and create a link within my blog folder to that.
This means I can write posts anywhere so long as I can upload to dropbox and it'll be visible to pelican to do it's
magic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step I thought I would do is just to add some form of watcher for git so that when content in the source
folder changes it'd add and commit and hey presto the hook would do the rest. Git doesn't follow links. That's that one dead then.
However, Pelican has a --autoreload option so that you can leave it running and it'll auto regenerate the output
whenever it detects a change, OK so I'll use that. Next I changed my post-commit hook so that it'd only run ghp-import
and do the push to gh-pages, not create the content. I downloaded &lt;a href="https://github.com/nevik/gitwatch"&gt;Gitwatch&lt;/a&gt; and ran it
to look at my blog folder (not the source folder, the whole thing). Final step, I setup ssh-agent so that I wouldn't
have to supply password each time git tried to do a push.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that I now stick a file in my github folder, pelican picks that up and regenerates the output, gitwatch picks up
the new output and does an add and a commit firing the post-commit hook. The hook runs ghp-import and pushes to gh-pages. Hey presto,
my new post is on my blog!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="dev"></category></entry><entry><title>Tipping chicks</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Oct/08/tipping-chicks/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-10-08:posts/2013/Oct/08/tipping-chicks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Dad owns a chicken farm where he takes chicks from a couple of days old and grows them
until they're about ready to start laying eggs. At the point where they're old enough
to lay they get taken off to another farm and he then gets a new batch of chicks. As I'm currently
on holiday and on the farm I got roped into "tipping chicks" today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is basically that chicks arrive in stacked plastic baskets on trolleys in a lorry. The trolleys
are rolled into the shed and we then put the baskets out on feed on the shed floor. Once this done someone sprays
the chicks with a vaccine and we wait for them to dry. Once that's done we (gently!) tip them out onto the feed,
stack up the empty baskets and roll the baskets out to be reloaded back on to the lorry. Simple!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so great when your body is aching from riding and the temperature in the shed is 27C though...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="baskets" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-abCaLdreuBs/UlQb7rZE3NI/AAAAAAAADjM/3PAs_assVJU/s640/P1000390.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="chickens tipped" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-O1_50R1maEc/UlQb8lOkfJI/AAAAAAAADjQ/MyX4UXfkcTY/s640/P1000391.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>Coed-y-brenin 2013</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Oct/07/coed-y-brenin-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-10-07:posts/2013/Oct/07/coed-y-brenin-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend marked the annual Coed-y-brenin Enduro, a 60km mountain bike endurance event. Last year Ben and I did it, it took
us 8.5 hours (according to my gps) and we were nearly dead last. Felt utterly destroyed at the end and swore to never do it again.
Somehow, we wound up doing it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been talking about Myherin to the others for a while now so put a plan in action to get it done. We met Dave Reed and Pete
in the arches car park and set about waiting for Ben and Rich to turn up. Which they did, 40 minutes late! Unfortunately, I wasn't 
feeling great so the descents were a bit hairy and the climbs just hurt. I cut the loop a bit short with Dave, we just skipped Blaen
Myherin whilst the others went off that way. We cut off at the steep climb and just headed back via Brashy Dive. I then met the others in
Aberystwyth. I think that they enjoyed the ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After grabbing some food for the evening we headed off up to our log cabin near Coed-y-brenin. It was pretty snug but had everything we needed
and was really comfy. At this point we also met up with 2 of Ben's mates who we were sharing the cabin with, Conrad and Nath. We cooked a big
ole pasta bake and then watched utterly dire films until bed time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The cabin" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-GZNerN0dt7w/UlJ5vlO1zyI/AAAAAAAADfQ/zPVT01EoZds/s640/P1000364.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting out how all big bike days do - porridge and a cuppa tea. We packed up all of our stuff and headed off to coedy to sign up and get riding.
The sign on had moved this year down to the newly kitted out visitors centre, although we didn't go inside to have a look. By the time we got there 
and signed on, met up with Jase etc... it was about time to go join the starting queue. We opted to queue about 3/4 of the way back as we had no plans to go racing.
The first few km were slow and a tad stop/start until the pack thinned out. The first descent (cane &amp;amp; abel) was a fair queue although completely 
cleared by the time we hit the actual descent. This may have been because we pointed out a path near the descents and joked we should go ride that. A lot
of the people around us decided that, in fact, that was exactly what they were going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Signed on" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-3oMwMgUBOMo/UlJ95O-9hQI/AAAAAAAADgg/50tdLfhQchI/s640/P1000373.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The start" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-SrzynTAgh58/UlJ-vGFyviI/AAAAAAAADgw/qlLOrloPhus/s640/P1000374.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="First descent queue" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ivsqw7Es2HQ/UlKAv6GIPII/AAAAAAAADhc/PGdJysu_kA0/s640/P1000379.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride had some great descents and a few tough climbs mixing up both fire track and singletrack. Of note were the steep, slippery, rad descent down to the river
(not trail centre) although I did hit a tree causing our mini-train to stop and then hit my pedal on a rock just before a chute causing another stop, although still
managed to ride them out. Sorry guys! Rocky horror near the end was also a good bit of trail although by that point my body felt like I'd been in a fight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chute" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-GsTuoXSONy8/UlKC-5FTj2I/AAAAAAAADiE/2Z4gNUB7RGM/s640/P1000383.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The end" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-5B3oP2s7R4w/UlKDcRKQepI/AAAAAAAADiU/6uPz0L_53VE/s640/P1000385.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an awesome weekend full of good riding. Will probably do the coedy again next year too, didn't feel nearly as bad this year - although didn't feel that ride during the ride.
Thanks to all the Summit crew who made it happen as well as the people manning the feed station and the emergency services crew(s?), and everyone else involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The mug" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-nm5z8CJ_smM/UlKDpV2Sb9I/AAAAAAAADic/88uGP-eFKv8/s640/P1000386.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Feed station" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-7ZR3trPAV5g/UlKDXaPS0YI/AAAAAAAADiM/znjckafQESA/s640/P1000384.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may expand this write-up as the week goes on!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="riding"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Weekend at Rich's</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jun/02/weekend-at-richs/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-06-02:posts/2013/Jun/02/weekend-at-richs/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Friday we leave for Scotland so some of us have been scrabbling to get a last
bit of riding prep in before Bean utterly destroys our legs. Harris, Rich and I
decided that we wanted to get a long ride in this weekend. As Rich lives near
good riding and now has his own house we decided to go ride there and stay for the weekend.
Unfortunately, Harris had been ill for a lot of last week and I got the text on Friday afternoon
saying that he wasn't going to make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning Maura and myself set off for Rich's place, which is only about an away. We arrived
at about lunch, chilled out for a bit and then Rich and I decided we'd better go ride in the Lickey's.
The aim was for a decent sized ride but with the longer ride being Sunday. Gotta say I thought that the
Lickey's were pretty awesome, not a lot of elevation but loads of stuff to ride and a lot of it pretty
steep. Even some small drops and the like. There's plenty of potential there for a bit of cheeky building away from the
beaten path too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View from Lickey's" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-AiONVnsKKpU/UaxLU5ctR8I/AAAAAAAACgA/TkQDjpiicYo/s640/IMG_20130601_151854.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;View over Birmingham from above the golf course&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as we hit the first climb I could feel something was amiss, my legs were still aching
from Harris destroying them the Saturday before! Whilst I could happily spin away I felt like
I had no actual strength in them and that they were hollow. Luckily, most of the climbs were steep
but not too steep so I could spin them in 1st gear. We did about 26km and it took us 2 hours although
a reasonable chunk was on the road to and from the woods. I'm keen to get back there and explore some
more. The SLX brakes proved themselves to be a worth investment impressing me all the while. The rubber queens
were also good, less draggy as the high rollers but just as grippy - think I'll be using the larsens for
most of my riding over Summer though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rubber Queen" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-QZgvr32iPAE/UaxK_QUskSI/AAAAAAAACf4/M18OnJCbRNA/s640/IMG_20130530_121319.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Second hand RQ, plenty of life - bargain!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we went for a curry which was pretty nice and then a couple of pubs. We wound up in a pub
near to Rich's house that had a live band which was a pretty awesome end to the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday, we had arrange to meet another Ben (Bish) at the Wyre at 11. Weeeell, that didn't happen - Rich and I
set off at 11 so we told them to just ride on and we'd bump into them somewhere. We actually wound up
arriving at the Wyre at 11.40. The Wyre was really dry and the descents there are pretty much all fast, flat out. Whilst that isn't
majorly my cup of tea (I prefer more techy stuff) it was awesome fun. There are a couple of pretty techy, steep descents that kept
the bag varied and the climbs are steep but fairly short. My legs felt much better for this ride and Rich was aching from the
previous ride so we had a pretty nice pace. I previously hadn't enjoyed riding the Wyre but 
it's certainly on my list of things worth riding now. In the end we did about 30km in about 2.5 hours (runkeeper managed 
to lose gps signal so not really sure!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lovely day" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-_PGpk6ooiUQ/UaxLuXyMyGI/AAAAAAAACgI/A7eDrqqQ65g/s640/IMG_20130602_120907.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A lovely day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dry singletrack" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-oQ-8BuAZRwA/UaxL1Gw3SlI/AAAAAAAACgQ/EFJXNC2fJ88/s640/IMG_20130602_120913.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lots of dry singletrack!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ice creams" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-6OG4M8GpuSM/UaxL4CknUrI/AAAAAAAACgY/3dqabaj-TgY/s640/IMG_20130602_123836.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Brief brake for ice creams&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shockless bike" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-94KJPg8YAeo/UaxL77Cd8FI/AAAAAAAACgg/qqoBwUti3kE/s640/IMG_20130602_154438.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;My bike doesn't fit Rich's rack with the shock on&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got back and chilled out for a bit before playing the bike fettling game. I bled my rear brake to try get it
as good as the front, I was not successful in that although it feels no worse than before. Rich decided to try
track down the horrible creak/cracking sound under load on his bike. We took his freehub off and it was pretty obvious,
the bearings quite literally fell out of the body in a number of pieces. So he's got some work to do before Scotland!
Rich then cooked a great chilli and after eating Maura and I returned to Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great weekend and hopefully many more to come in Rich's new place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Freehub" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-8oGi_Hu1ucU/UaxMBSnEVjI/AAAAAAAACgw/C-aqtWYJo70/s640/IMG_20130602_182053.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;That doesn't look right&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Loose bearings" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-rhbftj2VkUQ/UaxMDgQ_jjI/AAAAAAAACg4/X3FnDNASyks/s640/IMG_20130602_182252.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;That's definitely not right&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Odd bike" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-vOzet7jl8Lo/UaxL_PqHjsI/AAAAAAAACgo/513emXFP13Y/s640/IMG_20130602_153119.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Not sure how this guy slows down or stops?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/188659549"&gt;Runkeeper log Saturday&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/189022744"&gt;Runkeeper log Sunday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Prospect Big Bike Ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/28/prospect-big-bike-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-28:posts/2013/Apr/28/prospect-big-bike-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dyfi Enduro is now a week away today it's been ages since I last did a real big ride.
Therefore, I set out to plan a ride for this weekend and came across the Prospect Hospice 
Big Bike Ride by chance, a 50km ride over Swindon way. Ben came over on Saturday
so we did a quick 25km ride round Boars Hill and also had a bit of a play on the 
Dean Court dirt jumps - they're better than I been expecting. Good news!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we headed over to Swindon and signed on for the 50km loop, turns out
that we had about 25 minutes to spare before the event started so had loads of
time! The start was staggered into small groups but we didn't have to wait long.
The first few km were on the croft trail which, from what we rode, seemed like pretty
good fun. It was long until we (us and the guy in front of us) caught up to the group 
in front and had to go a bit slower but pretty soon we were on double track off the trail
so could ride at our own pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the ride was on double track with a few single track descents (and one climb) and a bit
of road. We were pretty surprised by how hilly it was. There was even one road climb where, whilst
we were going up it, I was the only person who stayed on the bike! It was really good fun and a nice
day on the bikes. We were pushing quite hard to try to treat it as a bit of training for next weekend and
it fit the bill pretty well! Unfortunately I did have a crash, about 100m from the finish line. There were two
trees that we had to ride through and I found out the hard way that my bars didn't fit, oh well - no 
harm done :). Bring on the dyfi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/173105396"&gt;Runkeeper log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>JQuery Hackday</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/20/jquery-hackday/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-20:posts/2013/Apr/20/jquery-hackday/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday marked the &lt;a href="http://events.jquery.org/2013/uk/"&gt;Jquery UK&lt;/a&gt; conference 
which was hosted by &lt;a href="http://www.whiteoctober.co.uk/"&gt;White October&lt;/a&gt; in Oxford.
Unfortunately I didn't go to the conference but today they also hosted a hackday
along with &lt;a href="http://jsoxford.com/"&gt;JS Oxford&lt;/a&gt; which I did make it to! The idea for the 
hackday was to have remote control cars that we could control from our laptops, phones etc...
but also control using javascript run under nodejs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The car" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-43up7VqMoro/UXQmzkJGetI/AAAAAAAACMA/YdxAlpSadaw/s640/IMG_20130420_114428.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The car!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at about 8.45 and by 9 was sat on a table with 2 others and starting to hack.
I'd already managed to install something called &lt;a href="https://github.com/chrisjameskirkham/libkoki"&gt;libkoki&lt;/a&gt; which we used for some machine 
vision stuff but unfortunately had the wrong version of node installed to build the node 
bindings for it that the White October guys had written for us. 2 versions of node later
and I had it working along with being able to run code on the car, pretty exciting stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a team with 3 others - Sunil, Phil and Toby. We were using the Blackberry sponsored
car for the day. There were no real restrictions on what
we could do with the day and with the cars although there was mention of a race at the end
of the day. As we all had the koki stuff working we decided that we'd try to navigate around 
the race track using that, going from marker to marker. Libkoki is a library used in
&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/"&gt;student robotics&lt;/a&gt; competitions. The idea behind it is that
there are a number of markers that the library can detect and extract some static and some
dynamic information from using a live camera feed. The markers provide information such
as which number in a series it is as well as distance from the camera, rotation etc....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Koki marker" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-jTCkMUftkDY/UXQm_VoSD3I/AAAAAAAACMQ/t_zHFV6-t0Y/s640/IMG_20130420_155934.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;One of the koki markers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The track" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-lf6sZbv3bCA/UXQnC1hCpJI/AAAAAAAACMY/voDDL5gGjVw/s640/IMG_20130420_155940.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The track&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The koki markers on the inside of the track were even numbered ones and on the outside odd.
We decided to use a pretty simple approach of just turning anti-clockwise when we detected and
got close to an even marker, and the opposite with an odd marker. I had tried to write a bit of logic
to avoid hitting walls by using the angle of the car to the marker to work out the distance
to the wall that the marker was on. I have a feeling that the value that I was using from the marker information
wasn't actually the angle that I thought it was and this approach was never going to work if we didn't
have a marker in sight anyway! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in my masters I did quite a lot of work navigating a maze with a rover but for that
I used sonar. Whilst the sonar that I used back then was quite noisy it was still
remarkably easier than using a live camera feed! If your vehicle is sat in front of a wall
that's 20cm away then that's pretty easy to tell with sonar, not so much with a camera. Whilst
we did have koki at our disposal that only worked if a marker was in sight, which 20cm from a wall
quite often is not the case. I was pretty shocked by just how hard dealing with no
extra information such as that given by sonar was, certainly made it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, over the day our approach slowly developed (and our car hit many, many walls - they were
only made from cardboard, luckily) and by the end we were bouncing between markers and working
round the track relatively well, I think that we even managed half the track at one point.
By the end of the day there was only one other team left and they had used an approach
of edge detection on the tops of the walls. Their car was quite good at navigating some bits
but not so good at other sections. In the end there was a race but the cars were controlled by
people on phones instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ready to race" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ccsEq-JeHog/UXQnFYc9n7I/AAAAAAAACMg/4unBSqrpNC0/s640/IMG_20130420_174409.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ready to race&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Race is on" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Gw_dWX68fqs/UXQnIGPDziI/AAAAAAAACMo/t5XYsXUyF-Q/s640/IMG_20130420_174533.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The race is on&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pile up" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-4CbEkkRq3Hc/UXQnLRPW5zI/AAAAAAAACMw/hgQ6DCOkkjk/s640/IMG_20130420_174549.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;That dent in the wall wasn't there before...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chicane" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-_7AM3DXWsuk/UXQnVG_CncI/AAAAAAAACM4/8YkZw01etMo/s640/IMG_20130420_174744.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The chicane&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an excellent day and I had a lot of fun. If they ever put on another then I'll
definitely try to be there. Big thanks to the guys who set it all up so that we could
do what we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beer" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-06s1vCzv1XE/UXQm9Ip0NOI/AAAAAAAACMI/j4uguzksdnc/s640/IMG_20130420_155109.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Can't go wrong with free beer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dev"></category><category term="hackday"></category></entry><entry><title>Pro Ride Guides Airtime Course</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/14/pro-ride-guides-airtime-course/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-14:posts/2013/Apr/14/pro-ride-guides-airtime-course/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back Ben and I decided that a skills course could be a good idea. 
He found a jumps and drops course at Forest of Dean that is run by
&lt;a href="http://prorideguides.com/"&gt;Pro Ride Guides&lt;/a&gt;. We found a date and sent the info
on the others, it ended up being Ben, Taylor and myself booked onto the course.
Today we did the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to the Forest of Dean at about 9.30 and Taylor n Ben showed up shortly afterward.
Some faffing occured and we headed over to meet the 2 other guys and the coach - Dave, Chris and Al
respectively. We had a brief chat and did some basic bike checks so that Al knew that we weren't
riding death traps. We set out for a short spin on the blue route just to warm up a bit
and get a fresh feeling of our bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we'd done that we were at the top of a fireroad. Al explained how to correctly get into the 
attack position and how it should feel - he wanted us to be in that position with the rear brake 
covered for most of the day. Next he showed us how to correctly bring the bike into a manual (seems to be the key!) so we practised
that for a while before progressing it into a bunny hop. An emphasis over the day was landing softly so we
also had a go at that with the bunny hops. This part felt pretty good and already it was
pretty clear I've got a nice collection of bad habits!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then moved onto a small drop onto a fireroad to practise the technique for that. I was having some trouble with
not pogo-ing upward at this point, something of a bad habit there as well. After that we pedalled up to the top of the hill
and spent some time on a tabletop getting to grips with the jumping correctly part. This was also pretty difficult! We all
started to get the hang of it though. Then it was time for lunch so we continued down the trail to the bottom trying practise pumping and
jumping on our way down. He also told us to keep as light as possible on the bars so that front wheel can track better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch we returned to the small jumpy section where we had pactised the drops and setup on a jump that we could land
on top of but had a distinct take off and landing. We put what we'd learnt into practise gradually adding more speed to try clear
the jump. Ben managed to get the hang of it pretty quickly although he did almost attempt to superman off the front of the bike
at one point. I was finding that I was getting the technique right more often by now and could tell when I had as it felt much
better. Gradually adding speed it was all beginning to sink in. Once Al was happy that we were all capable of doing that he moved us onto
a pretty small drop into a relatively steep slope.  We spent some time putting into practise what we'd done earlier and everyone managed it
with no problems what-so-ever. During these 2 sections it was also interesting to watch other people (not on the course) coming down and
see how they were doing it wrong - with Al whincing almost every time in case they nailed themselves! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we'd got the hang of that drop we pedalled back to the top of the hill and played on a tabletop up there. At this point
Al also showed us how to manual tables so we had a crack at that - Chris was pretty good at it and Taylor managed to get it 
really well on his last attempt. Ben and I weren't so great - more practise needed! We then did the descent we had done earlier
trying to put into practise everything that we learnt but we said our goodbyes and headed off home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I got a lot out of the course. Whilst I don't feel like I cracked it during the day it's given me 
the knowledge and theory that I needed so that I can come away and practise, practise, practise. Trying to practise
jumps and drops around Oxford might be difficult but I can certainly practise the manuals and bunny hops - so I will be!
Al was great - he was friendly, approachable and cracking jokes all day. He never seemed to get fed up of labouring
the same points so that they hit home with us. A majorly key concept from the day seemed to be to relax!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Boars Hill Ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/07/boars-hill-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-07:posts/2013/Apr/07/boars-hill-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely day today so I decided to go out on the MTB as planned. I was going to be riding alone so
couldn't really be bothered with driving anywhere - that left me with Boars Hill. It was pretty bone
dry and really fast. Not a very demanding route and a fair bit on road but a couple of short, steep climbs and
one descent that's actually pretty good. It's just off the main path and is actually pretty technical and hard
to go fast on. There are also some impressively massive houses up the top of boars hill and as I passed one there
were 2 Ferrari's waiting to pull out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed about 20km and took just over an hour, pretty fun little ride and ideal for after work! This was also
the first ride in aaaages where I've taken no bag so no tools, no water etc... Felt quite nice not having
the bag on my back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bike on boars hill" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-GGOcQy6XGFA/UWGeSoQb4uI/AAAAAAAACE4/BwCW6PSfyNE/s640/IMG_20130407_165302.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>On the road again</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/06/on-the-road-again/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-06:posts/2013/Apr/06/on-the-road-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today the sun's shining and the skies are blue, it's still a bit nippy out but it's a lovely day. Obviously, this means
that I had to do a ride; question being did I go out on the roadie or the MTB. In the end I decided to do road today and
head out on the MTB tomorrow. I very nearly just sat on the turbo but decided to actually put the turbo away along with the turbo
tyre! Might be a bit optimistic but got to hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set out with no aim of where to go or how long/far but knew that I'd follow the road down through appleton and just keep on that
as it's pretty nice and quiet. I wound up riding to a little past Pusey, about 48km in total there and back. Lovely ride and I'm pretty happy
with the average speed too. Quite glad to be back outside not on the turbo even if it does mean dealing with cars!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Furthest point" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-v4eR6fu_Ltw/UWBLDDbz5BI/AAAAAAAACEE/qkgI4W-_y-E/s640/IMG_20130406_160654.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Aberystwyth Easter Trip</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/01/aberystwyth-easter-trip/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-01:posts/2013/Apr/01/aberystwyth-easter-trip/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Easter weekend we had decided to rent out a caravan and do the nant-mach-nant ride. There would be Ben, Rich,
Jase, Pete, Rob and myself staying in the caravan and we'd do the ride with Dave and the ystwyth MTB crew.
We also planned to do a bit of Clarach and maybe Myherin too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early start, packed the car and was en-route to Ben's at 6.20am. The drive was good and I turned up
at 8.20, I had to wait 5 minutes for Ben to turn up but then we cracked on with the bike fettling. On my list of
things were to do were: cut down steerer, check damper circuit for fluid, change brake pads, perform volume
reduction mod on shock, bleed front brake and change chain ring. Not a huge list but these things always take time,
surprisingly we had an hour to spare before Rich turned up at about 11.30. A bit of fettling on his bike and we
were on our way to aber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fettling with my bike" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/5271_10151819648193765_874543417_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A bit of fettling with my bike!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shimming my shock" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/66853_10151819648513765_1327594937_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Adding a shim to my shock for the volume reduction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather on the drive over to aber was sunny the whole way and aber itself no different. We checked in at
&lt;a href="http://www.aberystwyth-holidays.co.uk/"&gt;Aberystwyth holiday village&lt;/a&gt; and headed over to the caravan to
get changed and drop stuff off. The caravan was pretty big. Basic but everything we needed. We did everything
that we needed and cracked on over to Clarach woods for some mini-DH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Driving to aber" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/543703_10151819649293765_892519870_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The drive over to aber&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trails were dry and riding brilliantly.
We spent a couple of hours there riding various tracks before heading back to the caravan. This was the first proper
downhill stuff that I'd ridden on my full sus and it was taking a bit of getting used to but felt really good.
We got back to the caravan park just after the other guys pulled in which worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Caravan" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/164983_10151819649823765_950997680_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The main living space in the caravan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Clarach" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/57959_10151819650313765_128179108_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dry as a bone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Berms" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/521747_10151819651068765_1133602810_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Berms" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526561_10151819650758765_237109502_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/539242_10151819653353765_390480424_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/534124_10151819653938765_1899181661_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Clarach Bay" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/6746_10151819654173765_1866672761_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Bay" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/558936_442109679197562_1498288363_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt; Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big ride day. We were going to do the nant to mach and back with the ystwyth mtb guys. We managed to get to
Morrisons at about 9.15 to get some breakfast at the cafe and grab some riding food. The cafe food was somewhat
less than average! We turned up to Pendam car park at about 10 to find Dave and Pete already there ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/564739_10151819654738765_811641672_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A bit of breakfast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of faffing and we were off out away from nant on the conti loop. At this point I feel I should mention
that the fresh brake pads meant that my front wheel wasn't spinning freely at all! Anyway, we got to Anglers Retreat in fairly good
time but there was a bit of snow on the ground. Dave and Pete made the decision to try a different route out to the mach 3
as they expected too much snow on the other. We cracked on and were met with deep snow and icy conditions everywhere.
Dave floated the idea that we maybe abandon the plan as it'd just be a slog and not much fun. In the end we came
up with the idea to ride to the mach 3 and then back to nant on a slightly different route to make a bit of a loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lovely day" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/733889_10151819654963765_2082049772_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A lovely day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nant-y-moch" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734492_10151819655828765_1119090350_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Looking out over nant-y-moch resevoir&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/48116_10151819656598765_31869313_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;It begins...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snow didn't improve, we spent quite a lot of time hiking the bikes through the snow with the odd bit of riding where
the snow was conpact enough to allow it or the trail went downhill. I had a nice lie down/slide on my arse going
round a corner and had thought I'd broken my lev but it turned out to be a bit of outer cabling had got stuck, phew!
We got back to Anglers Retreat via scaletrix and most of the ride back to the conti loop was actually ride-able. We did
the ace descent back down to the conti loop and returned to nant via sidewinder and hippity hop. At this point
Dave and Pete headed off home but Ben was keen to go do a bit more riding. There was a general lack of motivation
within the rest of the group though. I was shot but if everyone else wanted to keep going I was happy to do so on the conditions
that I'd probably have to walk the worst bits of climbs. In the end we decided to call it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A bit of a walk" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734571_10151819657043765_1569007908_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;There was plenty of this!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Blazing Bikes" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/46872_10151819657683765_475132321_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Represent&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sideways" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/392589_10151819658598765_876990918_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Jase getting it sideways&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dry" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/483697_10151819660983765_659377075_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;What, no snow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fantastic day out that, whilst it didn't go to plan, was still great fun and a bit of an adventure. Big thanks to
Dave and Pete for guiding us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we wound up in Lopburi Thai Restraunt for food and as always the food was top notch. I had a chicken
panang curry made "as hot as you can". It was most excellent. We popped along to spoons for a pint to start the night out.
After said pint we wound up going back to the caravan park due to everyone being knackered!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frozen" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/305946_10151819656773765_2054192978_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/485160_10151819658158765_1498120005_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Log stack" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/488273_10151819658933765_1101820806_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/299168_10151819659258765_1853766489_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/65763_10151819660133765_2014661651_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/73358_10151819661123765_114172002_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nomad" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/537222_442109772530886_159775249_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt; Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Riding" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734533_442109969197533_241260023_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt; Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had no plans for Sunday other than to just ride something. We had a bit of a slow morning getting up late
and tidying the caravan/packing our stuff away. We wound up having a Spoons breakfast and we about ready to go
ride at midday, destination: Clarach. Having seen how dry it was on Friday and we had such a good laugh we decided that
we had to go back and to also show the other guys who hadn't been there before. We spent a good 4-5 hours in the woods
and had a brilliant time. Rob, Ben and I did the big double which was a big thing for Ben as it managed to get in his
head and he's spent about 3 years trying to get up to doing it. The trails were riding brilliant and were all
really fast, was a brilliant way to spend the afternoon and I think that the only crash was mine too! Luckily I got
out unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Eyeing up" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526546_10151819668003765_1073678688_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Classic stand and look at it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ben" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734390_10151819673608765_1860750977_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ben overshooting it like a boss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jump" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/5344_10151819664933765_611946596_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/575815_10151819665633765_1139055512_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Me" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/58054_10151819665863765_1471258651_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Clarach" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/299198_10151819666248765_1339011001_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Rob" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/72696_10151819672993765_2081129368_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Me" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/483481_10151819673288765_2016999412_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Standing about" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/46888_10151819674083765_1709532522_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Corner" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/529170_10151819674618765_1533253125_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nomad" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/392723_442110122530851_413810993_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt; Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a brilliant weekend of bikes and big thanks to everyone who made it what it was.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Hat Tournament Creator</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/17/hat-tournament-creator/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-17:posts/2013/Mar/17/hat-tournament-creator/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to write something about this for a little while now and 2 days ago
I received an email from a tournament organizer in the states so that's prompted me to do this.
He'd found my code on github and wanted to know how to go about running it, well it just so
happens that I actually have it hosted at &lt;a href="http://www.hattournamentcreator.co.uk/"&gt;http://www.hattournamentcreator.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;
so I just pointed him at that. I got another email saying that it did what he wanted and that he'll pass the word
on to other organizer. I'm pretty happy that it's helped out at least 2 people in the world now! If it's helping even
a small number of people then it's worth it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how it works. First, I'll explain the UI and then a little bit about the back end (at a high level). 
The site allows you to select manual or csv entry, along with an example csv to try to help people out a bit.
Manual entry is frankly crazy as it'd take ages to add any reasonable number of players, I also haven't
tested it as well as I've tested the csv stuff. Anyway, we've selected our csv file (which we already have as we
have to keep a record of players anyway...) and we hit upload. The site then loads all that player data in a big
grid. You can edit players in the grid to change names, metrics, etc... in case of any mistakes. The grid is 
pretty flexible and you can reorder the columns and set the sort order on any of them. You've got your players all setup
so now we need to setup the metrics. This is the important bit, this is how the app will assign points
to players. Each attribute that defines a players skill is given a multiplication factor. Stolen from the site itself:
For example if I was doing this for Ultimate Frisbee then I'd maybe give Cutting a value of 2 and Handling a value of 2 then I'd hit generate formula. 
This'd give me (Cutting * 2) + (Handling * 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Bob who has 3 cutting and 4 handling gets 14 points but Dave who has 1 and 2 respectively gets only 6. At this point we also
need to define how many teams we want creating and whether or not to balance the genders so that all teams
have the same number of girls and the same number of guys. We hit Generate teams, some magic occurs and we get a csv back
that has all of our teams set up for us :). A little example - using the example csv on the website. This example has 4 skill
attributes: cutting, handling, years since playing and years of experience. Years since playing is a negative skill as people get
rusty as the years go by and they haven't played... so I'm going to give that a value of -1. It's not a hugely important attribute
but I want it taken into consideration. I give years of experience 2, it's not that important - I mean you can have played for 10 years
and be rubbish but experience does mean that you know how to react to given situations. Cutting and handling are the big guns,
I'm going to give them 4 each as I feel that they're equally important as one another. 
The point generation formula that I get is: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Handling * 4) + (Experience * 1) + (Cutting * 4) + (Years Since Playing * -1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That looks fine to me. I'm going to have 6 teams in this tournament and I want to balance the genders too. 
I hit generate and get my teams back. The teams file also includes a few little extras like the average points
per player for each team. In this example my averages per team are: 16.95, 17.9, 17.4, 18.35, 19.63 and 20.52. That's not 
a huge variance and should make the teams pretty even making for a fun tournament. I feel a bit sorry for Name 68 who has been assigned
-4 points, that's gotta sting! As the player data for this example was literally random numbers (I wrote a script to generate it) I'd expect
real world data to give closer points per team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto how this thing actually works then. The grid is just &lt;a href="http://www.trirand.com/blog/"&gt;jqgrid&lt;/a&gt; which, tbh, I don't recommend.
When I get round to it I'll rewrite it to use &lt;a href="http://www.datatables.net/"&gt;datatables&lt;/a&gt;, although I haven't actually tried it yet 
so it could be rubbish! Jqgrid does all the work for the grid stuff so I won't cover that. The algorithm for the team creation is the meat 
so let's talk about that. In my opinion I've used a pretty naive approach and it's probably not the most
optimal way to do it but it works, which is the important bit here. Just to mention, this site uses python and a load of javascript.
The team creation stuff is all in python. My javascript skills are much strong but I like to keep dipping into python just to remember
how it works! Anyway. First we deal with our metrics, we create a dictionary of the attributes that actually map to skills - 
just cast the value to a float and if it's 0 and doesn't throw an exception we class it as a skill! Next up is sorting out the gender stuff,
just determining which gender format is used really. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto some of the fun stuff then, the next step is to iterate over every player and work out their points value before adding
the player to the relevant gender array (we need to balance them remember). We quick sort each array so that the highest ranked
players are nearest the "top" (index 0). The next step is to split the array(s) of players into equal sized lists (plus one for
the players that don't fit into the equal lists). The reason for this will become clear now, this effectively means that we have several
lists and each list contains similar skilled players. We now do the actual "teaming". We iterate over our new lists of players one by one. For each
list we generate an index using a weighted random (the weight is linked to how many points the team has, the random is just to add a bit of variance) and then remove the player at that
index and add them to the current selected team. We do this until we've run out of players and then we create and serve the file up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite hard to explain and the easiest way to see how the algorithm works is to just look at, it's kinda commented!
You can find the code at &lt;a href="https://github.com/chvck/Hat-Team-Generator"&gt;https://github.com/chvck/Hat-Team-Generator&lt;/a&gt; and main.py and utils.py are the
key files for this stuff. At this point I should probably actually mention why this app was created! A couple of years ago I played
Ultimate Frisbee at Aberystwyth University and the club had its 15th year anniversary. To celebrate this they put on a hat tournament and I
was approached to see if I could make something to create the teams so that the committee didn't have to do it manually. The result
was this web app. Oh, the team I was on also won! No, I didn't fix it either!  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dev"></category></entry><entry><title>Scoopfree Litter Tray</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/15/scoopfree-litter-tray/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-15:posts/2013/Mar/15/scoopfree-litter-tray/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a bit off the beaten path of bike related things that I usually write about. 
This post is about a cat litter tray system called &lt;a href="http://www.scoopfree.com/"&gt;Scoopfree&lt;/a&gt;, it's
one of those things that actually makes a difference. As the name suggests there's no scooping
cat poo with this machine, you simply insert a cartridge and off you go until it's time
to fit a new cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way that this thing works is that it has a sensor (light beam I think) that when crossed triggers
what I'd called an event. Once this event has occured then the litterbox counts down for 20 minutes (light
blinks to let you know) and then it self-cleans. The self-clean process is simply a rake that runs down the
tray and deposits the cat poo, dirty litter etc... in a compartment and then it runs back up. You'd think that
this would smell pretty bad but it doesn't! They send a special form of litter that absorbs the smell, obviously
it does start to get a bit stinky if you leave replacing the cartridge too long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cartidge lasts about a month for us with just Tesla to worry about and each one costs about a tenner
from &lt;a href="http://www.vetuk.co.uk/"&gt;Vets UK&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of a work day when you're tired it's nice to come home and not have to 
muck about with cat poo. It's expensive for what it is but I do like having it around, especially as Tesla still insists
on attacking it every time that it rakes! We've had it a few months now too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NWcrZGTnoco" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>KS Lev seatpost</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/13/ks-lev-seatpost/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-13:posts/2013/Mar/13/ks-lev-seatpost/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I ordered one of those from &lt;a href="http://superstarcomponents.com"&gt;Superstar&lt;/a&gt; yesterday and was pretty impressed
when it turned up today. It feels like a nice piece of kit and is well finished. I also go free
Haribo, yay! Anyway, on to the fitting, the instructions say to cut the outer into 2 pieces to 
enable you to fit a barrel adjuster, I chose not to bother and to see how it faired without it. 
Cutting the cables to size is slightly fiddly as the end piece has to be very exact and can't have
cable sticking out. It took me a good while to get this bit right and get it fitted but wasn't too difficult.
As a little bonus the lever can also act as a lock-on for an ODI compatible grip which is pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lever" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-XPK_98JvAgc/UUDtQONsDZI/AAAAAAAABtM/MturoBao0i4/s640/IMG_20130313_205850.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was the saddle, this is a lesson in why not to skip several pages of instructions as I wound
up with my saddle pointing 90 degrees to where it should have been so I had to take it back off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sideways Saddle" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HMMHSt-HgKM/UUDtLKgunVI/AAAAAAAABs8/SqD9Qm7M7yU/s640/IMG_20130313_204355.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that the cradle for the saddle can be turned to various positions, bonus. To do this you have to take the head
of the seatpost apart and unscrew the valve cap for the air - I took this opportunity to add a bit more air 
also. Once done I refitted the seatpost and wadda ya know, pointing in the correct direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works well and feels smooth going through the travel. Thus far impressed - can't wait to take it on a ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Saddle Up" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/--ioQA0FGlSY/UUDtNPulIRI/AAAAAAAABtE/aTFIWs8A0kE/s640/IMG_20130313_205828.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Saddle Down" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-uV6k3fFhzxE/UUDtSo6B1SI/AAAAAAAABtU/yO28V6RXxb8/s640/IMG_20130313_205843.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Nettlebed Ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/10/nettlebed-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-10:posts/2013/Mar/10/nettlebed-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I was due to head over to Christmas Common to do the route in Rough Ride Guide with Ben. Last night I got a handful of texts from him saying that he'd
locked himself out of his room and then another this morning saying that he was still locked out and not going to make it.
I suggested to George that we headed out for a ride in the afternoon and he agreed, I didn't fancy the full 40k of the
Christmas Common ride so chose the 30k Nettlebed ride. The guide suggested that this route holds up pretty well in the wet so it sounded
fairly ideal. We headed over at about lunch time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got there, got out of the car and it was bloody cold! We set off and pretty quickly picked up an offroad trail. The first half of the loop
was pretty great, there we lots of fast descent although not too techy but with little bits to try jump off etc... It was also almost all off-road
which was pretty nice. About 1/4 of the way in we bumped into a lady who flagged us down to help work out where we were. Turns out that she'd walked
a lot further than she thought and kept saying that she always walks too far and doesn't realise how far she's gone! We helped her work out where she was
and then continued on our way. At this point we did another fast descent that was also really quite long. This dropped us into Henley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rode through Henley and picked up a trail the other side, this is where it started getting really muddy. This bit of trail was a quick downhill
followed by 2km of uphill, not very steep and should have been simple. But no, it was majorly churned up and muddy. In quite a few areas we just gave up
and walked. We also stopped here for a spot of lunch next to this: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Boundary marker" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-HcijLqlJ3wY/UTzrMBbDa4I/AAAAAAAABpI/kSQRjMC8Sn4/s640/IMG_20130310_155115.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked the map and it seemed that the second half of the ride was to be uphill, it wasn't wrong. It was also pretty muddy most of the way.
Although, we did go through a pretty flat wood that would be good fun in the dry. We managed to hit the last bit of road and go the wrong way, 
I misread the map so we wound up heading away from Nettlebed, not toward. Due to this and it starting to get a bit dark we skipped the last bit of 
offroad and just followed the road all the way back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a good ride, pretty good fun and should be pretty awesome in the dry! Since starting injecting meds I'm finding hills to be a major 
issue, there's just nothing in my legs. I'm hoping that I can just ride through it! We wound up doing 30km so not a bad effort. I'm also really enjoying
the bike, it just feels great and really inspires me to want to have fun on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/156028587"&gt;Runkeeper log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bike" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-Smq2jPuMVpw/UTzrZadH1NI/AAAAAAAABpE/NsZPzdsQLIU/s640/IMG_20130310_155124.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="chilterns"></category><category term="rough-ride-guide"></category></entry><entry><title>Superstar Excel Grips</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Feb/28/superstar-excel-grips/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-02-28:posts/2013/Feb/28/superstar-excel-grips/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I had to take to my old Oury grips with a hacksaw due one of the bolts on
a lock ring getting rounded. I took this as a sign that it was time for new grips
in my new colour scheme. I decided to give the superstar excel grips a go, went for
yellow cartridges (replacable too) with green lock rings; they also come with black
end caps. They arrived today and on first impressions they look good. The compound is soft
and they feel really grippy and nice n fat. They're also really, really long! The colours
are pretty vibrant and they look nice, the photo doesn't really do them justice on the vibrancy. 
For a tenner I think that they might be a bit of a steal,
time will tell how well they get on, the Oury's are going into the toolbox as spares just in
case. Only negative thing I can say is that I didn't get any Haribo with my order!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Superstar Excel Grips" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-x6CH10peUi8/US_AH7lvDoI/AAAAAAAABno/jKtrUPvhj_E/s640/IMG_20130228_203627.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Chilterns Night Ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Feb/26/chilterns-night-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-02-26:posts/2013/Feb/26/chilterns-night-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've recently got back in touch with a guy called Roger who I emailed when we first moved to Oxford about riding.
He's part of a riding group who ride areas around Oxford, he passed me onto another guy called Ainsley. They
had a ride planned for Tuesday riding in the Chilterns starting from Watlington, only downside being that they
were starting at 6pm. It's about 18 miles away but involves going on the Oxford ring road - to be there for 6
that also meant going during rush hour. No matter I said that I'd be and started work early so that I could leave
the house at about 5.15pm, I got a bit lose in Watlington trying to find the car park so got there about 6.05. Turned
out that there were only 3 of us; Ainsley, Matt and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did introductions, setup bikes and headed out. To begin with we had a fairly long, decent gradient climb. This had
me suffering, it takes me a good while to get warmed and this just wasn't the ideal way to do it! I had to take a couple of
stops on the way up but wound up at the top, not too long a climb really. There weren't any really bad climbs on the ride, there were a few 
really muddy bits but not too many although the ground in places was quite draggy anyway. We did a couple of pretty cracking, fun descents. Nothing
technical this time but i'm assured that there is plenty of steep, technical stuff in the area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of the ride there was a small set of steps that I managed to totally OTB down, I started without any run in and there was a bit
of a depression before the wooden holdy bit in the step so I wound up doing my best superman impression.
After that were a couple of steep little ladder things that were pretty good fun though. About a mile before the end my light just completely
cut out with now warning which wasn't so good so I need to investigate if there's a loose connection or something. I think that I'll also
buy a spare battery pack as they're so cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a really fun ride and I'm really glad that I got out there, hoping for more rides
with these guys to come!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="chilterns"></category></entry><entry><title>Catching up</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Feb/18/catching-up/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-02-18:posts/2013/Feb/18/catching-up/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Firstly I'll start off with the demise of my photo a day. Quite simple - I just don't do enough varying things
in my day to day life. I found myself remembering that I hadn't taken a photo and having to hunt for something around the house.
That wasn't the way that I had wanted to do it, I'd wanted to just take a photo of something significant each day and not
had to think about taking the photo, just doing it. For that reason, I stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let's talk bikes, surprise surprise. The Intense is pretty awesome and I'm very much enjoying riding it. I recently did a ride around
Boars Hill which is local to me and has very little elevation. Despite being on a totally inappropriate bike it was still good fun
and the Intense pedals much better and easier than I had expected. I've also changed my drivetrain and accidentally bought an 11-32 cassette, this
hasn't been an issue yet either which surprised me a little. I really need to get the bike over to some Welsh trails I know well to give it a proper
good testing.
    As we're on the subject, a couple of weeks ago we went to Forest of Dean which was pretty rad. We started out doing the blue loop which was quite flowy
and undulating. The final descent of it is pretty awesome. We also rode a few of the DH tracks; really good too! The weekend just gone we went to explore
around Birdlip near Gloucs. That was not so great, really deep thick mud everywhere. We did 25km in over 4 hours! I also swear that we didn't even do a single
semi-decent descent. We did quite a bit of hiking with the bikes too, which really destroyed my legs where I've recently jabbed. It turned into one of those
rides where I just wanted to be back at the car. Best bit of the ride was a pint &amp;amp; fish n chips in the pub!
    On the jabs note, I recently discovered that my pack came with a cooling pad that lives in the fridge and you put on where you're about to jab.
Wow, I was pretty amazed at just how effective that thing is! Really takes away any pain at the time of doing it, doesn't stop it aching the next day mind but
that doesn't happen to me often anyway!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 22nd Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/22/photo-a-day-22nd-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-22:posts/2013/Jan/22/photo-a-day-22nd-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New frame! For a while now I've been keeping a loose look out for a full suspension bike somewhere between 140mm and 160mm
in travel. For a while I've had my eye on the Tomac Vanish but really couldn't find anywhere to buy in the UK so I moved onto the
latest model of the Cove Gspot which &lt;a href="http://www.chainreactioncycles.com"&gt;CRC&lt;/a&gt; have at 1150 or 999 for the 2010 model. This
was quite sorely tempting but a little more than I wanted to spend so I was still on the fence about it. Then I stumbled across
an Intense Tracer 2 on &lt;a href="http//:www.singtrackworld.com"&gt;STW&lt;/a&gt; for 700 that looked to be in really good condition and looked
well looked after too. After a few brief questions I bought it and it arrived today. It's a great looking bit of kit and is in
really good nick!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Intense Tracer 2" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-7ogQKA_STy0/UP7r7NMSlJI/AAAAAAAABfc/15QgNNQEVHU/s640/IMG_20130122_193740.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 21st Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/21/photo-a-day-21st-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-21:posts/2013/Jan/21/photo-a-day-21st-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New shoes! During Bens Aber weekend my 5 10s utterly died. The sole on the left shoe came off all down one side of the shoe, the
right shoes is also going the same way. My plan was to get a pair of shoes from a different brand this time round but found
some Freerider Spitfires for 45 quid on &lt;a href="http://www.chainreactioncycles.com"&gt;CRC&lt;/a&gt;. They're much, much less bulky than my old ones and I could probably get away
with wearing them as ordinary shoes. My main concern is that they're made from leather and might fall apart given the UK
weather - hopefully not. I've only done 1 ride in them so far but they're comfortable and seem to have plenty of grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Five Tens" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-jXj-6Z8Plm8/UP2OrTGMhfI/AAAAAAAABfA/Z8uZ1WBAL6U/s640/IMG_20130121_183710.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 20th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/20/photo-a-day-20th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-20:posts/2013/Jan/20/photo-a-day-20th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ben and i decided that we'd do a snowy, local, loop going up over Boars Hill. It was a pretty short loop and we just took the main
bridle way across the top, I had worked out a different route back but we somehow managed to miss the turning and in the end came back
on the road from Wootton. I had meant to take a picture whilst out riding but my hands were freezing, gears were driving me insane
and my jab sites were hurting, leg on pedalling and arms on going over rough stuff. Hopefully my body cuts that shit out soon! But, for
those reasons I couldn't be bothered to get out my phone and take a picture so instead here's one of my new Techno Lime Green headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Headset" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-eFNxA_n_2J4/UPwrqYydIeI/AAAAAAAABeg/EcKwCN-Qzwk/s640/IMG_20130120_173531.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 19th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/19/photo-a-day-19th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-19:posts/2013/Jan/19/photo-a-day-19th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ben decided that the roads looked OK and decided to come over for the night. It was getting on a bit (2ish) by the time
that we actually got round to doing anything so decided to not bother riding but to go to
&lt;a href="http://www.mhs.ox.ac.uk/"&gt;The Oxford Museum of the History of Science&lt;/a&gt;. Neither Maura or I had been there before and Ben certainly
hadn't. It was pretty good, it's mostly scientific instruments and most of those were also things like tools for measuring or
for celestial stuff. It was quite interesting although there are only so many microscopes and brass discs (can't remember the
name for them) that you can look at!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Museum of Science" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-N_MkQa1lPac/UPsHPTGV7dI/AAAAAAAABdo/XW9_eiX8Dsc/s640/IMG_20130119_154013.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 18th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/18/photo-a-day-18th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-18:posts/2013/Jan/18/photo-a-day-18th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was so determined not to take a snowy picture today but, well, that failed! This is overlooking the small close that we live in
and was taken at about lunch time. There's a good few inches and I'm glad that I didn't bother driving into work today. Ben
was due to come over for the weekend but has decided to postpone until the morning to assess the roads then. The Chilterns
ride with Beeline Cycles has also been cancelled. Hopefully we'll get a short loop in locally at ssome point over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-KX-L9gGtZzU/UPsHd374oBI/AAAAAAAABd0/gxsF-hnSUHQ/s640/IMG_20130118_121146.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 17th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/17/photo-a-day-17th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-17:posts/2013/Jan/17/photo-a-day-17th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scotch eggs. I'm a big, big fan of scotch eggs and last night I decided to create my own. I followed a &lt;a href="http://allrecipes.co.uk/recipe/388/baked-scotch-eggs.aspx"&gt;really simple recipe&lt;/a&gt;
with nothing fancy in the sausage mix as it was my first time. Next time I'll throw some chopped chillies in and some
herbs, I also want to experiment with mini ones and fill them with black pudding and other various fillings. Instead of
buying sausage meat I also bought some OK quality sausages and just removed the skins, seems to have worked quite well.
They taste pretty damn good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scotch Eggs" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-6sbagkHPIQ8/UPhXgVRUDpI/AAAAAAAABck/-1Tdtws-ZdU/s640/IMG_20130117_193033.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 16th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/16/photo-a-day-16th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-16:posts/2013/Jan/16/photo-a-day-16th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another post lacking in any inspiration. This is my "office". So far this week I've managed to work from home 3 times what with
the hospital appointment and potential recovery. It's nothing fancy but gets the job done although it's bloody cold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Office" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-O0zBgziEOU4/UPb3PDQ2dKI/AAAAAAAABbM/zMAn-Hhors8/s640/IMG_20130116_183109.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 15th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/15/photo-a-day-15th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-15:posts/2013/Jan/15/photo-a-day-15th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the view from Neurologoical Out Patients at the John Radcliffe hospital. It appears that I've accidentally
managed to get some reflection from the window in it. Today I was there to get shown how to use my meds and to have my
first injection. It's actually really easy to do and there's a little tool that I use to do it, although I don't have to
and I can just use the needle directly if I want. It's also surprisingly not at all painful although afterward there is
a slight ache/stingy feeling but that went away pretty quickly. Unfortunately it seems that I'm one of the 90% who gets
the flu-like side effects although I just had a headache and raised temperature which made it a bit hard to sleep but nothing
I can't live with and get used to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-zBXNngNkoMs/UPWWphHvlAI/AAAAAAAABbE/mVydRbn62zk/s640/IMG_20130115_161315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 14th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/14/photo-a-day-14th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-14:posts/2013/Jan/14/photo-a-day-14th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This isn't a very exciting post. Last night it snowed a little so there was a fine dusting around. It was enough to
make everything look nice but not be annoying, it'd also all melted by lunch time. I'm not really a big fan of snow so if it doesn't
snow again this year then that suits me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-laqQH2CmAGs/UPR0PNk7HnI/AAAAAAAABao/DLKUJTFTDZw/s640/IMG_20130114_085226.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Ben's Aber Weekend</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/13/bens-aber-weekend/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-13:posts/2013/Jan/13/bens-aber-weekend/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Monday was Ben's birthday so he organised a trip to Aberystwyth with plenty of riding involved. Plan being to ride
Nant-y-arian on Saturday and then something suitable to hangover states on Sunday. I went to Rich's house on Friday night
as Saturday morning was to be an early start. At Rich's we did a night ride in the Lickey Hills which were muddy but good
fun. I started out with my light attached to my helmet but it pretty quickly became evident that the level of fog around was
not ideal for a helmet light so switched it over to my bars which was much better. The light is a tad spotty but is generally
really good and there was plenty of light for me to see by. Definitely going to have to ride those trails in the dry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday, we made our way to Ben's, loaded up his van and set off to nant. We were running late but that was OK as the other
guys were running later (expect the other Ben who, as always, was punctual). There were Ben, Ben, Rich, Taylor, Rab, Jase,
Pete and myself. I'd never met Pete before but had been to the alps with Rab and Jase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Vans" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-o-AjCano134/UPchd6ToroI/AAAAAAAABbo/fpMKYJj1GjA/s640/IMG_20130112_115846.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, once we'd sorted ourselves out
we set out on a Summit + extras loop. The extras we threw in were White Fridge and a few did Reaper, I went off in hunt of another
track that I've done before but wound up riding down a steep, rocky track until I bumped into Zorro and did the bottom half of that.
Nant was, as always, a blast and I felt pretty good, although slow, on the climbs too. As a first I also took a hip flask on the
ride, filled with port. Why had I never done that before?! It was a great idea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sending it" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/734841_10151624410798765_255312670_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed to the Tiddly Widdly for a pint before going to aber and at this point said bye to Ben and Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pint" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/309668_10151624416393765_1474277726_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we got back and got the keys to our rooms in Maes y mor we showered etc... and set off to Lopburi for food. Lopburi was
good as per usual, I had the jungle curry - tasty. After that we headed to spoons for coffeebucas. That was a bit of a warning
sign that it was going to be a bit of a drunken night. We hit several pubs before venturing into pier pressure. That place
has not improved although it has got stickier. I'm pretty sure that it hasn't changed since we were at uni, even the drinks are the
same - just more expensive. At about 2 Jase, Rab and Pete headed off; I decided to stay with Rich and Ben but I quickly decided
to leave too. Unfortunately it was midway back to the guest house that I realised Rich had the key and my phone was dead, no matter
I just went for a short walk and then sat against a wall for a while - it was quite warm out. We'll certainly be using Maes y mor again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday, we all woke up quite late and after paying for the rooms and having breakfast we managed to get into the vans about 12ish.
We headed up to nant again but this time parked up near white fridge so that we could go out the top and do some of the conti
loop and up into anglers retreat. I felt much better climbing than on Saturday, not really sure why - possibly the lack of
drinking port on the ride. We went out on a normal conti loop but cut out the loop to the reservoir and back as we'd do the good
descent there later on. We stopped 3/4 down Bont Goch and did the descent there, it was pretty wildly cut up and fairly
hard to predict what was coming up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bont goch" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/226670_10151624428393765_1109049718_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that was the long old climb that goes on and on! We did the techy climb followed by descending
the slab which was ace. After that we headed back to the conti loop and rode it backward to get back to nant. We chose to skip
hippity hop in favour of doing white fridge whilst there was still light. It was a fantastic ride although majorly cold. I also
made the choice of going through every water obstacle - that didn't make it any warmer and several times I was in upto my axles!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that was home time, 4 hours back to Aberystwyth! It was a great weekend and I'm looking forward to the Dyfi warmup for
more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bottom of Zorro" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-DxAbFF1JOL4/UPcha5hxQaI/AAAAAAAABbg/pGKpAaiHT7Y/s640/IMG_20130112_140813.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Seafront" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-XGwjGSoJo_w/UPchkJgv-gI/AAAAAAAABbw/fROR7s3-LPE/s640/IMG_20130113_103755.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="More seafront" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Hyaj5CNu8qs/UPchmQYnXqI/AAAAAAAABb4/XNAg912GvzE/s640/IMG_20130113_103802.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View from near white fridge" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-WVUEmJ53XZc/UPcho3bv6TI/AAAAAAAABcA/5QKtqxTOXNE/s640/IMG_20130113_162856.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Not sure" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/408497_10151624407733765_722909297_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Group photo" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/537456_10151624413318765_185315862_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/68687_10151624425923765_416509796_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Lake" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/398052_10151624435163765_1629698850_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Another group photo" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/734285_10151624434093765_659982223_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="boozing"></category><category term="nant-y-arian"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 13th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/13/photo-a-day-13th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-13:posts/2013/Jan/13/photo-a-day-13th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a night out last night to celebrate Ben's birthday we managed to fail to get out of bed until 10am. On the way to breakfast,
to stoke our engines ready for another ride, we decided to go have and visit the seafront. We didn't stay there long, the wind
was pretty chilling! Nice to be there though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Aberystwyth Seafront" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-QU01f1RSRDI/UPPGK4AjSeI/AAAAAAAABZ8/Hh6aBQa2eeg/s640/IMG_20130113_103755.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 12th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/12/photo-a-day-12th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-12:posts/2013/Jan/12/photo-a-day-12th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of Ben's Aberystwyth biking weekend. We did the Summit loop at nant-y-arian plus a few little extras.
This was the first time that I'd ever carried a hip flask on a ride, why have I never done that before?! It was a great ride and
I felt fitter than I have for quite some time although I was at full on pootle pace. This photo is from midway up the leg burner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Water" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-H1xBuP6ee1o/UPPFr9eHpaI/AAAAAAAABZw/cludjQEJ-_M/s640/IMG_20130112_144252.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 11th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/11/photo-a-day-11th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-11:posts/2013/Jan/11/photo-a-day-11th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend is about bikes. It was Ben's birthday on Monday so he's organised a weekend in Aberystwyth. I came to Rich's tonight as he lives closer and we have an early start. We decided that we'd do a night ride around the lickey hills. Prior to tonight I'd never even ridden here before. The ride was really muddy but really good fun, can't wait to ride here in summer! This was also the debut for the light and it was really good, very impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Night ride" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-7yF3dJ5w-8I/UPFA3AakCRI/AAAAAAAABWg/nsD3x0nqYkk/s640/IMG_20130111_210322.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 10th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/10/photo-a-day-10th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-10:posts/2013/Jan/10/photo-a-day-10th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tiny, fatty cat. I got given a massive bean bag for christmas from my family, and I mean massive. It is ridiculously comfortable.
I'm not the only one who thinks this, it's become Tesla's favourite place to hang out; she loves it! Our current mission for the
next month or two is try get her to lose weight, about 1/2kg down to 4kg. On new years day we went along to our local
Pets At Home who run a free weight &amp;amp; nutrition clinic. The guy gave her a check over to check she looks OK and took her weight.
He then worked out a feeding plan for us, 30g twice a day, dropping to 25g twice a day after a while. Pretty good service and it
was free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-cg7eRm7PiYI/UO8vlWhv2CI/AAAAAAAABVk/i1tyO0DqnyE/s640/IMG_20130110_211413.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 9th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/09/photo-a-day-9th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-09:posts/2013/Jan/09/photo-a-day-9th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Iddy biddy coffee machine. As part of my mission, and yes it really is a mission, to get up earlier
in the mornings I purchased this tiny coffee machine. It's a filter drip so was a pretty safe bet as you can't really
go too far wrong with that! The two cups hold about the volume of 1.5 espressos each which is pretty good for a morning
wake up call. Hopefully I can persuade myself to wake up a bit earlier from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tiny coffee machine" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mpzq-v0R-IY/UO3g-Lj1A2I/AAAAAAAABVM/uW_x9DFO5AU/s640/IMG_20130109_203226.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 8th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/08/photo-a-day-8th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-08:posts/2013/Jan/08/photo-a-day-8th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my new mtb light arrived at the office and I picked it up today, given that it had an expected delivery date of
2nd Feb I was pretty surprised! It cost me 20 from &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006RHB41Y/ref=pe_217191_31005151_3p_dp_1"&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;.
At 20 quid I wasn't sure what to expect but 2 of my mates have the same unit and have had it for quite a while so I confident
that it was a good gamble. I was expecting it to be plastic and a bit rattley but it's actually metal and feels nicely solid.
The battery pack hasn't convinced me that it'll hold up to any serious rain but as i plan on throwing that in my backpack anyway
it isn't a big deal. Seems like it should be plenty bright enough - the case claims 1200 lumens but I know that's not
gonna happen. I'm fairly certain it's a cree T6 LED which has a theoretical maximum of 1200 lumens but I've also
seen lab results of tests on it, in ideal conditions in the lab they don't really even reach 1000 lumens! None-the-less
it looks like a good little unit and I can't wait to get out and use it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bike light" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-lT_-G7px7b0/UOxvoGHA7ZI/AAAAAAAABUk/lB_VTHidXjQ/s640/IMG_20130108_190939.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Let's talk MS</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/07/lets-talk-ms/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-07:posts/2013/Jan/07/lets-talk-ms/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No, not Microsoft; I'm talking about Multiple Sclerosis. I was diagnosed with this back in October, part of the reason for
writing this is so that anyone who I tell who has no idea about it can be directed here. Another part is so that in the future
I can log any relapses that I have and keep a record. So I'd best start out with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiple_sclerosis"&gt;what it is&lt;/a&gt;.
At a very basic level if we think about electrical wiring then you have the core wire that carries the signal and a coating that
prevents anything messing with that core wire, causing short circuits. This is kinda like nerves, you have the nerve and it has a sheath of something
called Myelin. In MS something causes the immune system to attack this Myelin sheath leaving the exposed nerve open to damage.
This can have (what I understand are) fairly random effects with varying levels of severity. There are also 2 types: relapsing remitting
and progressive. I have the former and don't ever want the latter, for further reading the &lt;a href="http://www.mstrust.org.uk/"&gt;MS Trust Website&lt;/a&gt; has proved fairly
invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's move onto how it's affected me. I've had a handful of relapses now although none have been what I'd call severe, none of
them have altered my lifestyle. Trying to pinpoint when it started is pretty difficult but for ages I had slightly less sensation
down the left hand side of my body and I also had tingling in my feet, legs and sometimes my torso when I looked down.
The tingling is known as &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lhermitte's_sign"&gt;L'hermitte's sign&lt;/a&gt;, naturally I ignored it for ages!
When I did finally go to the doctor they sent me off for MRI scans of which I had 2 in Aberystywth and 1 in Swansea. The Swansea
machine is much, much nicer - the one in Aberystwyth was actually painful, the head cradle has pointy bits and I was once in it for 1.5 hours! I never
followed up the one in Swansea until September when I went to a GP in Oxford and they chased it, the GP suspected MS and referred me to a specialist. I've had a few other things too,
my eyesight in my right eye has gone blurry twice and I lost pretty much all skin sensation on my left leg once, each of these relapses
has only lasted a week or two. I can't remember if I've had anything else. To be fair I can live with loss of sensation, it's loss of use of limbs or the like that I'd rather
not ever get! Typically after a relapse the symptoms go away or at least do for the most part. Currently the only thing that I have
is that my finger tips have lost some sensation and that seems to be fairly permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the drugs, as I've had more than 2 relapses in a year I'm eligable for disease modifying medication. These drugs are meant
to reduce the number of relapses. The consultant told me that typically people have 3 relapses a year and with the drugs that
tend to drop to 2, given that the effect of a relapse seems pretty random reducing them seems like a good idea to me. The drug that I've chosen
is something called &lt;a href="http://www.mstrust.org.uk/atoz/betaferon.jsp"&gt;Betaferon&lt;/a&gt; of the Beta Interferon family. I'm not going to
pretend that I have a clue about what it does or that I really made an informed decision about which drug to use. My choice
was made on what I thought fitted my lifestyle/impacted upon it the least which is what I was told to make the decision on. Each drug has a nice list of side effects but the most
common for this one appears to be flu like symptoms for the first 3 months or so. My appointment to find out how to use the drugs
and my first injection is a week on Tuesday so I guess that Wednesday will be fairly revealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far the nurses and doctors of John Radcliffe Hospital and DK Earley and Partners have been fantastic and explained everything really
well to me. No doubt I'll be seeing plenty more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So all that is certain is that the future is rather uncertain but, hell, whose isn't?! I'll continue to live my life as I always
have and deal with any obstacles as they happen, much like everyone else does...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ms"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 7th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-07:posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to write much about this here as I plan to write another post about the whole thing. This is my first batch
of meds and next Tuesday I find out how to use them, that Wednesday could be interesting... I even got given a bin though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meds" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-JYb2HhlaE3Y/UOsTJftcj5I/AAAAAAAABUA/rWFvSsH8QRc/s640/IMG_20130107_180630.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 6th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-06:posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I went to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultimate_(sport)"&gt;Ultimate Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; training with Oxford Sharks. We chucked about
until enough people showed up and then did a couple of leading pass and throwing to beat the mark drills. After those we went straight
into pickup games - we were out for about 2 hours. It was pretty good fun, as usual, but my legs were really feeling shot after
playing yesterday and the turbo trainer during the week. Speed felt went down compared to normal and I just generally felt knackered and 
couldn't think right. Going to start going to fitness training some Thursdays though so hopefully that'll help with that! All in all though,
a good session and I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also finally managed to contact the Witney MTB club yesterday so as soon as my lights come I'll be on night rides with them too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frisbee" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-pAOb9U3aL04/UOmisrlFvtI/AAAAAAAABTw/79FijfPkGEQ/s640/IMG_20130106_155110.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="ultimate"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 5th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-05:posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes I know that I did a food photo yesterday too. I didn't do a lot of note today so I had to use something. I have a book
called "The Curry Secret" that I suspect is likely as old as I am. Pretty much all of the curries use the same base so I made
a couple of litres of that to freeze down and with some of it cooked a standard spicy curry. I only had 2 chicken thighs to use,
 I coated them in paprika and slowly fried them whilst I cooked some other bits, I also added in some potatoes. All in all
a good tasting curry, made completely from scratch, even if I say so myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Curry" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-emY_BTiXWFU/UOiFkBiFfQI/AAAAAAAABTI/5Eh5wfDG-nU/s640/IMG_20130105_194621.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 4th Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-04:posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Todays photo is something that I am rather fond of - food and cooking. I was pretty desperate for ideas so loaded up
&lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/"&gt;all recipes&lt;/a&gt; and whacked "sausages" and "squash" into the recipe finder. To my surprise there
were actually results, I settled on a recipe of &lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/recipe/chef-johns-stuffed-summer-squash/detail.aspx?event8=1&amp;amp;prop24=SR_Title&amp;amp;e8=Quick%20Search&amp;amp;event10=1&amp;amp;e7=Home%20Page&amp;amp;scale=5&amp;amp;ismetric=1"&gt;Chef John's Stuffed Summer Squash&lt;/a&gt;.
I had to make a couple of alterations, cheddar for goats cheese, butternut squash and I also added mushrooms and a couple of chillies; I also
decided to cook up some pasta to have with it. Oh, I also have no idea what Merguez sausages are so I just used standard
ones. As I had some stuffing left after filling the squashes I mixed it into the cooked pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stuffed Squashes" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-0GxFD2EN9SY/UOc19DVON5I/AAAAAAAABSk/d1_dh-fai6A/s640/IMG_20130104_200042.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 3rd Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-03:posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the cat is purely bonus material - the actual focus of the photo is the exercise mat. As a part of my getting fit
kick I'm doing a 30 minute body weight exercise programme thing, 90 seconds per exercise. It's pretty simple to do as it's
&lt;a href="http://dailyworkoutapps.com/dailyworkoutapps/Daily_Workouts.html"&gt;a mobile app&lt;/a&gt; that displays each exercise with
a timer and a video showing what to do. It has a variety of body weight exercises such as push ups, crunches, planks, squats
etc.. I'm doing this on the days that I'm not going on the turbo or doing something else.
So far it's going well, been on the turbo for the last 3 days and hoping that I get into a bit of a routine and it becomes
part of my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat n a Mat" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HM8mL_r0vKU/UOXtg2QezrI/AAAAAAAABRw/yRP2FB9tPjc/s640/IMG_20130103_203053.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 2nd Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-02:posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I picked up my new phone from work (it was delivered on Friday but I've been on leave), it's a Google Nexus 4.
I haven't had much of a play with it yet as I don't yet have a micro sim, I kind of overlooked that small detail. Luckily
one of the guys at work has a cutter and is bringing it in tomorrow. I've setup my Google account on it and whacked
it on our wifi. So far it seems great, I really like the latest versions of Android anyway. The build quality is more
than just a little better than my Wildfire, it feels solid and has a nice weight to it. It's also rather noticably faster.
I haven't tried the camera on it yet but will be doing so for tomorrows photo - here's hoping it's better than the one on
the Wildfire! As of tomorrow the Wildfire is going to Maura. Should also be interesting to see the battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nexus 4" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-SBA93yoj8rA/UOR_eUJh0WI/AAAAAAAABQk/YJnqcIEub7k/s640/IMG_20130102_183909.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>2013 Photo a Day</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new year has rolled round and so I'm once again going to attempt to take a photo a day.
I've tried this for the past 2 years and just failed so this year I'm going to attempt
to write a short blog post about each photo to try to make myself think about what my photo will be.
Hopefully, this year I'll actually manage to do it!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category><category term="photo-a-day-2013"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 1st Jan</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bikes. Since moving to Oxford I have done little on the biking front and this year I would very much like to
rectify that. I've reached out to a local MTB club to see how I go about joining them for rides and I'm
going to try to spend more time on the turbo to improve my general cardio. I should note that this is not
a new years resolution, I believe that making those is just setting yourself up to fail. As of next week I'm
going to have to pack in booze for the most part for medical reasons so getting back on the bike now seems like
an ideal time. Put in the effort now it'll be worth it for Summer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Machines" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-eWDhFsF-RpE/UOLmiAL8G2I/AAAAAAAABQE/F_jpJx1VxII/s640/IMG_20130101_132504.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Back in the Saddle</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Dec/16/back-in-the-saddle/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-12-16:posts/2012/Dec/16/back-in-the-saddle/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last time that I rode the mtb (prior to today) was the coedy enduro back in October.
That is seriously way too long to spend off the bike. This weekend Rich came over to Oxford to hang out
and we decided to ride somewhere. I still don't know much riding in the Oxford area but figured that
the Ridgeway was probably a decent bet for a bit of a pootle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bikes out and ready to go. Sun shining, no rain, small amount of wind, ideal. Off we went. Within about 50 metres
we discovered the general theme of the ride - MUD. So much mud. Oh and deep puddles with ice still in them, they were nice
too. We decided to ride both sides of the car and all in all it was a good day out, we did about 25km in about 3 hours,
so not exactly blistering pace but the mud was pretty much everywhere and fairly similar in characteristics to super glue.
The area of the Ridgeway itself that we rode was pretty flat, rolling hills is the phrase; I suppose. I'm hoping
to get back up there sometime soon but, ideally, when it's a bit drier! Come Summer I think that it'll be good fun
up there - it'll be very, very fast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, first ride in about 2 months and my legs were really hurting by the end. Despite a lack of hills I think that
the mud had a similar effect on my legs that hills do. Not ideal condition but nice to get out on the bike
and it was a nice day with some nice views!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="ridgeway"></category></entry><entry><title>Coed-y-brenin Enduro 2012</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Oct/13/coed-y-brenin-enduro-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-10-13:posts/2012/Oct/13/coed-y-brenin-enduro-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, Friday I hitched a lift up to Coedy with Jimbo and Richard (who I hadn't met before) to meet up with Ben,
Jimbo and Richard were staying in a nearby B&amp;amp;B but I opted for the cheaper option of Bens van. The drive up went well
and traffic was good, once in Dolgellau Ben and I grabbed some food at a pub which was also pretty good! We headed
 back to the campsite and it was pretty dead so we just grabbed a couple of beers before heading to sleep. 
The night in Bens van was pretty cold but all things equal was fairly comfortable. By the time we got up cars were
slowly arriving and by 10 the place was packed. Race plates fitted, breakfast eaten, bikes put together, riding time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone gathered for the race briefing and there was about 250 of us in total. Briefing over and off we went,
Ben and I had decided to stick together and take it easy, Jimbo went roaring off ahead of us. We rode with some of
the abermtb guys for quite a while during various sections too. The climbs were often long but just fire roads so
just grinding up wasn't so bad, although by the end they were making me feel pain somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good - some of the off piste descents were truely cracking, steep and due to it being wet very muddy. Really,
really good fun those were, some flowly singletrack too. Everyone on the day were really nice and most people pulled
 over to let us pass on the descents. We ended up bumping into 3 guys from Birmingham quite a bit and they were an
excellent laugh, could hear them a mile off! Unfortunately I did go OTB in front of them which was a tad
embarrassing but nothing was hurt bar my pride. Some of the actual trail centre descents were also pretty good fun,
 what i believe is the final descent on the trail centre of the road was a hoot. Also, the food station was cracking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad - To be fair at the time I thought that there was a lot of bad but realistically not that much sticks in my
mind. There was a section that was a long old climb through fields and really bad muddy wooded bits. In all fairness
to the course designers the rain didn't help and from what I've heard they couldn't link everything up without it. We
 had a brief chat with some marshalls and they said that not even the top guys managed to ride the wet grass bits.
Other than that bit not a lot sticks in my mind as being bad except...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ugly - After the final descent of the trail centre side of the road we crossed over to the Tarw side. This I did
not enjoy, by this point I was pretty tired and just wanted to finish, what actually happened was another 15km or so
of riding round the Tarw trail with a few big old fireroad climbs. The descents were roughy and rocky so were hard
work as I was already pretty knackered. Had I been less tired I think that the descents would have actually been
cracking. Also worth going in the ugly is that Ben had 4 punctures, he used up not only all his spare tubes but mine
too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I really do not know if I'll do it again, at the time had you asked me then I most certainly would have said
 no but I'm not sure. I think that next year I really need to work on my fitness as that would go a long way to
helping enjoy it. It was much, much harder than the Dyfi enduro which I had not expected. End of the day though it
was a day riding bikes in Wales so can't be that bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position - 254th out of 269 overall, 134th out of 140 in category, Duration 7hr 46min 29sec. All you can do is laugh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/121776226"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/121776226&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dunno why so happy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-wCa0ggKYL5s/UHl-G_2yCEI/AAAAAAAABOI/oYvWNVuTKtA/s640/121001035345_R.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Why we're so happy here and everyone else is not, I have no idea!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The end, at last" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-eIRt458REbk/UHl-dNy_LeI/AAAAAAAABOQ/DGKS1ZMefro/s640/121001223523_R.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Finally, the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="wales"></category></entry><entry><title>The Alps</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Aug/30/the-alps/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-08-30:posts/2012/Aug/30/the-alps/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Destination: Morzine. This trip had been in the pipeline for a fair few months
and I was looking forward to it. We were due to fly out on Saturday 4th.
George had kindly agreed to drive us to and from Heathrow on the Saturday in his parents' estate.
Ben and Taylor arrived at my place on the Friday night to get bikes sorted and generally get ready for
packing in the morning and getting to the airport. About 10 minutes after arriving Ben
realised that he'd forgotten his passport... he wasn't best pleased about that. He went home
to get it (2 hours to get here and then straight back again!) and decided to come back in the morning
after sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning, all kit ready to go and car packing time. So, 3 bikes in bike bags don't fit
in a Mondeo estate. Problem. In the end we managed to squeeze everything in by taking Taylors
bike out of the bag and playing quite a bit of bike tetris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bike tetris" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/559242_10151343880853765_1697281874_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bike tetris" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/297334_10151343881108765_1615736305_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;T'was a bit of a squeeze...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all that faff was done and dusted
we actually managed to get to the airport with plently of time to spare. We checked in etc... and didn't
get charged for the bikes which was nice! A pint and something to eat later and it was boarding time.
We flew with Swiss air and during the flight we got given ice cream and Swiss chocolate, pretty good.
Other than the ice cream and chocolate the flight was a flight. We collected baggage and did all that jazz
before meeting up with the other three guys we were there with - Jase, Rab and NC. I hadn't met
these guys before and they were sound. Transfer from Geneva to Morzine and we arrived at the chalet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="In the air" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/391489_10151343882083765_1038870302_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;In the air&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sorting everything out at the chalet" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/533069_10151343882638765_1332865463_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Sorting everything out at the chalet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The chalet" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/391561_10151343883323765_1509336136_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The chalet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I feel that I should mention that we were catered for. The chalet was massive,
big enough to hold 26 (I think it was). Upon arriving we met Paul, the chalet manager/chef and he
told us that it was just us and 3 other guys for the whole week. Oh, there was also a hot tub, that's
worth a mention. We unpacked all our stuff and sat down for our first meal of the week. Well,
the food was excellent and stayed that way for the duration of our stay. First night there so we
went out for a few in Morzine, it was fairly quiet but we had a pretty good night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday, rain, lots of. Slightly hungover and not a good forecast for the day we decided to hold
off on starting the riding for a day, no point in buying a lift pass to find the lifts shut for most
of the day due to storms. Instead we wandered into town for a bite to eat and to get our bearings.
After we'd eaten we had a bit of a wander round and during this time some form of street procession
started up, it was really pretty random. It was mostly vans and large vehicles covered in trees and
tarps etc... To mind I remember there being 101 dalmations - kids on skates being caught by a bloke who put
them into the back of a van. Loads of classic rally cars and a dragon. Yes, a dragon. It was a tractor with
a grab on the front that was covered in a tarp (no, the driver could not see where he was going), the grab meant that
they could move the dragons head which was actually pretty cool! Anyway, that excitement over we bought some beers
and headed back to the chalet where we just chilled out for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Randomness" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/599463_10151343885143765_1970476067_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Randomness" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/426626_10151343885913765_2042967216_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Randomness" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/386849_10151343886573765_1320966890_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday, bikes. We rolled out of the chalet about mid morning and decided to hit up the
Pleney. We bought our lift passes (93 euros for 6 consecutive days I think) and made our
way up to the top via chair lift. Chair lifts are utterly awesome. First run in we
decided to take the blue run just to ease us in. It was fairly bumpy, pretty steep in places and
fairly slick. I think that it's safe to say that we were all a little bit worried about how hard
other tracks would be if this was a blue. It wasn't a blue, it was a black. Taylor had somehow managed
to take us down the wrong one, oh well - at least we felt better that it was black!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The crew" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/400420_10151343887973765_860735645_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The crew for the week, except Ben&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Second time lucky" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/394464_10151343888863765_1050098128_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Second time lucky&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up we did the blue. This was mostly double tracky fireroad type stuff and was seriously bumpy, braking bumps
were a recurring theme for the week and were not fun on my hardtail. It was a pretty boring track really.
Next up we tried the other black track, this was a good'un! It had steep bits and was twisty and drops and
was fun! It wasn't full of braking bumps as bad as other tracks for some reason and was one of
my favourites of the entire trip, certainly my favourite in the Les Gets &amp;amp; Morzine areas! It also
had a short section called 10% which was just a steep run into a berm or 2, I really thought that I was going to
lose a wheel in the braking bumps going down that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we stopped for some food and a drink and decided to head over to Les Gets. We rode the linking
section from Morzine and popped out at the top of the bottom section of the Les Gets red line main run.
It started out with a few jumps and then worked it's way down through loads of berms. Pretty fun. By this point
it'd started raining again and the chair lift up to the top was not fun, wet and windy. We pretty swiftly headed
on down the main line. It was jumpy, bermy and wide. Oh, and FULL of braking bumps. Not just a few around corners
and what not but a constant stream of small bumps with a few big ones thrown in for good measure. It was really, really
hard work on the hardtail, gave me a pounding and was difficult to keep up any speed. None-the-less a pretty
fun track that would be a great laugh without the braking bumps! At the bottom of this we were all utterly plastered
in mud, most of us had given up with goggles due to them instantly getting covered. A couple of the guys
were only wearing XC jerseys on their upper half and were getting pretty cold so we decided to call it a day
and ride back along the road to Morzine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cold chairlifts" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/418479_10151343890173765_438921370_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mudded up" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/557532_10151343890418765_1861521024_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mudded up" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/284952_10151343891428765_1706957253_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mudded up" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/422488_10151343890653765_1613981663_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;No shortage of mud&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow Ben and I got left for dead going down the road (suspect super tacky
tyres had something to do with it) and we decided to throw in an extra run of the fun black line down Pleney. I really
did like that track! After that it was home for showers, hot tub, food and chilling out. Rab, Jase and NC also managed
to spend 3 hours in the hot tub!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Winding down" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/557328_10151343892203765_1210675953_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Proper way to wind down!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday, dry! Tuesday we decided to head straight over to Les Gets and explore the area a bit more. We got there
and did the main line to warm up, it had dried up a bit and was even bumpier than I remember, didn't hugely enjoy it.
After that run we headed over to the jump park and did a couple of runs over there, they were mostly just berm after berm and
ridiculously bumpy, not ideal for me! A bite to eat and we headed back to the main Les Gets lift to
check out the canyon run. At this point Ben and I also swapped bikes. Wow, the top of the main line was suddenly a lot
more fun! DH bike just took out most of the buzz of the smaller bumps, it was great. We did the top and headed over to the canyon.
This trail was also great, it was rooty, steep in bits, small drops and fairly tight (as the name suggests). There was
another track that ran down with the canyon but jumped across it back and forth, we gave that one a miss! After that track
we decided to try out the other side of Les Gets, this only really had 1 track. It was a good track that was pretty easy
but fast and steep. Oh, and full of braking bumps (getting the theme yet?) but it was still good even though
my arms did die at the bottom each time. We did that a couple of times before calling it day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had said that most of the guides and chalet guys etc... had Wednesdays off so we decided to head into town
for a few drinks again. It was even quieter than Saturday! We had a few drinks and then Rab, Jase and NC headed back,
I decided to stay with Ben and Taylor but to switch to energy drinks as I didn't fancy getting battered. We had a couple of
drinks before deciding to try Opera which seemed to be the main club, not only was that utterly, utterly dead but also
10 euros for a shot or bottle of beer. We gave up without having a drink there and headed home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday, rest. Taylor, Ben and I decided to have a day off and just chill out. Not much happened. The other guys went up
Super Morzine and said that sections were some of the steepest stuff that theyve ever ridden, that made it high on my agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday, disaster. We decided to head up the Super Morzine and then explore over the other side of the mountain and maybe head
to Chatel. The top of Super Morzine is a separate chair lift so you can lap it, we decided that we'd do a single lap of it
before heading further afield. One lap done and I realised that my forks had broken, I had no travel and they were just clunking up and
down. That was that for me, I headed down on the road and headed for the Scott shop which Paul had recommended to us. As chance would
have it Paul was getting ready to go for a ride there and gave me the name of a mechanic at a different shop to
go and have a chat to. Unfortunately he wasn't there so I headed to the chalet and set about fixing the forks. After a lot
of swearing and effort I got the air unit apart (most stupid, stupid system ever). It all looked OK until I realised that
the positive air piston wasn't attached to the rod, it'd blown off - blowing a circlip off in the process. Simple to fix at least,
I put it all back together and too kthe chance to remove the spacer and make them 160mm again. That took me the best part of the
day so I just chilled out until the others returned. Had a bit of a chat about where they'd been and it sounded pretty ace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday, disaster again. Exact same as Thursay, top of Super Morzine I lost all travel. Not happy. Headed into town
and headed straight for the shop Paul had suggested to talk to the mechanic, as luck would have it he was in. His
opinion was that the rod was damaged (I was pretty sure it wasn't) or that the circlip was on upside down. Wait, what?
Yeah, so turns out that circlips aren't all symmetrical and that they have a rounded and a flat edge, flat edge takes the load.
Learn something new every day! Back to the chalet and repaired forks again, by the time I'd finished it was getting on and I'd
lost confidence in the fork so I just chilled out again with the aim of getting a hire bike for Saturday. I asked Paul where
to hire one from and he told me to use his bike (Iron Horse DH bike). Brilliant! What a legend! The other guys
had been over the same as Thursday and had a pretty good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday, aaaaace! We headed straight over to Les Linderettes which the guys had said was good. It really was. Having a downhill
bike made so much difference, the braking bumps were still noticeable but the ability to just plough through them at speed
and not lose all control and speed really made the difference. We mostly rode 2 tracks over there, one of which was the
old French national - this was one of my favourite tracks - it was fast with a bit of tech thrown in. We also headed up
the Marmotte on the chair lift, that was a long old lift. Once up there we had a choice of black or red descents, the black seemed
to take us down the wrong side of the mountain so we went for the red. It wasn't amazing, it started out really pedally and then got
a bit more fun although quite wide. Ideal for a hardtail ironically. We spent a good portion of the day riding Les Linderettes before
riding back to Morzine via a goat village (I kid ye not) and a nice lake to swim in for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Top of Marmotte" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/526093_10151343906378765_1915620457_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Top of Marmotte" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/297039_10151343907023765_1169206647_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Top of the Marmotte&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lake" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/551650_10151343903228765_208682321_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lake!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday, home :(. Nuff said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a great holiday, big thanks to Paul for that. Next time I won't be taking a hardtail, it's just not the tool for the job
out there for this sort of riding. Next time I think that we're thinking of going somewhere more off the beaten track
too and making more of a road trip out of it, should be ace! Now, to find a full sus frame....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More pics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/418748_10151343893018765_1167674611_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Menu" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/530935_10151343895293765_102983494_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Menu" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/428951_10151343895483765_47824736_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Some of the evening meals that we had&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chair lift" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/394410_10151343896293765_794718411_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Avoriaz" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/284915_10151343899263765_1902979752_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Cow" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526361_10151343901588765_1603000478_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Case" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/406266_10151343902898765_1920650553_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Going to need a lawyer...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beer tube thing" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/539216_10151343909333765_1594853442_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Cage dancing" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/292962_10151343909913765_873756733_n.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="alps"></category></entry><entry><title>I'm not dead!</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-07-24:posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been a little while since I made any posts, about 3 weeks in fact - feels a lot longer I can tell you.
May as well start at the beginning - the move. Well, actually there's not a lot to say on that front,
it all went rather well really. Everything was packed and in the vehicles (Ben came to help with his van) by about 2pm
I think. The drive itself was fine, no mishaps or owt. Upon arriving at the new house we pretty much just got everything
out of the vehicles and dumped it all in the house before shooting into Oxford for some food. Sunday we went and rode
Aston Hill, wow that place is slick in the wet! My brakes were still binding terribly so the push up was pretty damn
unenjoyable though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, 3.5 weeks on and the house is a bit more presentable and has a touch more furniture - we're still sleeping
on a sofa bed though. We managed to get a book cake and a bureau from one of my work colleagues and just yesterday we picked
up a small cupboard Maura spotted on freecycle. I have an office setup in the spare bedroom which is serving me well. (ha, we've just had a power cut
as I type this) The cat appears to have settled in no problems and has tackled the great outdoors of the back yard.
Not a lot else to say on this matter really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's happened in the time period since moving here? Actually, not really that much again. Seb got married the first
weekend which was pretty cool and was fun! I've been on one road ride with Jimbo and will hopefully increase the frequency
of the road rides by joining a local club called Zappi's. I went on the speed awareness course because I got caught speeding
(might actually write a post about that...). Most of the time has just been spent working or sitting around really!
But all is going well and hopefully Maura will find a job soon which will take the financial strain off!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>Final Ride Out</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jun/24/final-ride-out/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-06-24:posts/2012/Jun/24/final-ride-out/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The move is almost upon us and I decided that I wanted one last long ride. So I decided that for
old times sake a ride out was in order, no real plan - just ride up to nant and do whatever. Ben H asked if
he could tag along too, he didn't quite realise that i was going for a bit of a long one at the time though!
Anyway, Sunday morning rolled round and Ben arrive around 10.30, we waited for the episode of True Blood (yeah, I know)
I was watching to finish and then headed out, the weather was good - cloudy but not wet and it was a nice temperature too.
I had organised my thoughts into which way to get up to Nant so we headed out on the A44 until the road that
leads off and climbs up to the Waunfawr - Capel Dewi road. We went along that and continued to Capel Dewi before heading on
up to Nant through Banc-y-darren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once up Nant we headed down Zorro and played the no pedal game, always a fun one! Once down we had a spot of lunch
before heading up the leg burner. About halfway up we came across the landslide that I'd heard about. Wow, wasn't expecting
that much damage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Landslide" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-oNy9qYlbf_s/T-d7UKs9mUI/AAAAAAAABJU/Nfdd44AeV0Y/s400/IMG_20120624_122237.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Landslide" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-Kx6Pwq2Yx68/T-d73T4VjMI/AAAAAAAABJ0/yxYw8ZWaWWI/s400/IMG_20120624_122335.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Landslide" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-rlq3kGiwWwo/T-d66UTqGcI/AAAAAAAABJE/kYEuXXkC5WM/s400/IMG_20120624_122301.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not even sure that stream was there before and if it was then it certainly wasn't as open as it is now. Pretty
incredible what water can do! Once we'd finished marvelling at the landslide we carried on up and over to Hippity Hop then
Drunken Druid. At this point we turned off and went through the gate to do a rather rocky descent that I hadn't done in
a while. Wow, water had taken its toll here too, some bits were more like riding trials than a descent - it was
pretty wild! At this point I decided that we'd head out on Joe's Back Garden and hit an obstacle...a stream that
was just a little higher than normal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stream" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Z-PRCQSdk7Y/T-d7pNCTuOI/AAAAAAAABJk/ZbbVt_ZMLzo/s400/IMG_20120624_132029.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Stream" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-BQadexuNr3E/T-d8U3omc3I/AAAAAAAABKg/ix6x9qiDRbY/s400/IMG_20120624_132036.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a place to leap over and continued out along the stream bed which actually had a stream in it and was rather rutted
and rocky. Once on the road we went over to the resevoir and over the dam before going round to link back up with the
Conti trail and continued along that. The puddles on the inward part from the resevoir were ridiculously high and the mx-ers
have made a right mess of the banks going around them. The first descent on that part is also rather wild now and really good fun!
The Bont Goch climb hasn't recovered since the last time I went up there and is still very scarred from the water with a fairly
decent sized stream running down it in a massive rut! Once up the top of the climb we took the bridleway down instead
of the Bont Goch descent, just for something a bit different!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued along the road and then followed the Conti loop back to nant. By the time we popped out up the top
of Hippity Hop we were both feeling the distance in our legs and decided to do Hippity Hop and then head back home via White Fridge.
At the bottom of White Fridge I decided to take my rear brake pads out to have a look at why they were making such an odd noise. Yeah,
no pad left and rubbing metal on metal, that old one! Unfortunately the spring was also utterly dead and so I couldn't fit the pads
back in, luckily the only downhill we had left was on the road so a front brake only would suffice. We descended down to
Penrhyncoch before climbing back up to Capel Dewi along the little back road, Ben was off and pushing this point and I was
feeling knackered! Neither of us fancied climbing up the Capel Dewi to Waunfawr road so we decided to return via the roundabout just
out of town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a nice ride with good weather. Certainly a great ride to remember the area by with some great views. Going
to miss these hills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/97340393"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/97340393&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-wqMYIqeWwHg/T-d6nnZzRII/AAAAAAAABIw/WT5e3CjbtAQ/s400/IMG_20120624_151717.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-9BKfe8v0fWA/T-d6qXCYHqI/AAAAAAAABI4/KtoPmc3eIVI/s400/IMG_20120624_145003.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-h84Xf2JXqJ8/T-d6-C0MXxI/AAAAAAAABJM/iaf-L5mE2j8/s400/IMG_20120624_144957.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-RLM0RdOnBEg/T-d7Z9bZSmI/AAAAAAAABJc/2dSyAjtx1V4/s400/IMG_20120624_141716.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-KHMhER11BYA/T-d7tQyTETI/AAAAAAAABJs/DUuVDDq1_K8/s400/IMG_20120624_141711.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Kfn_eMMl_oE/T-d79KNgHaI/AAAAAAAABJ8/ztFIhahxz64/s400/IMG_20120624_135806.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-akqbpd9zo5w/T-d8GQKDeTI/AAAAAAAABKQ/G53Hd5LBapI/s400/IMG_20120624_132051.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-L503x8Bc4Bg/T-d8K6SEIYI/AAAAAAAABKY/EwMT1dignWM/s400/IMG_20120624_135659.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ywbhjAYbsoU/T-d87PZCkTI/AAAAAAAABLA/BXRuiNnPKVI/s400/IMG_20120624_134626.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-IrQxyhrTn28/T-d9Di87LRI/AAAAAAAABLQ/geIqLZ1gFlY/s400/IMG_20120624_154013.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-_Epis7YhtAM/T-d8_0gxyOI/AAAAAAAABLI/9oytMkLMWHE/s400/IMG_20120624_151722.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really need to buy a bloody camera!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="nant-y-arian"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Mach n Back</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jun/09/mach-n-back/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-06-09:posts/2012/Jun/09/mach-n-back/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The time for us to leave Aberystwyth is rapidly approaching. Ben and I wanted to do a 100km
mtb ride before that time arises so using the &lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/77580855"&gt;Mach &amp;amp; back route that I did with Dave Reed and
the Ystwyth gang&lt;/a&gt; I plotted a new route adding in
some different bits to get the distance up. The basic difference was to be that we'd kick out further on the way out
by going further along the
Conti loop doing most of the Bont Goch descent before doubling back on the rocky descent and then doing the long
slog of a climb up to Anglers. Then on the way back we'd climb up to the Bont Goch descent again but take the bridleway
down and then come back to Nant along the usual Conti Loop and do a Summit loop too. Oh, we also parked in the forestry
car park outside of nant so that would add a reasonable amount of distance too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the days running up to this were wet to say the least. Friday saw the beginning of flooding in the area but Saturday was
due to be sunny all day. The morning came round and it was wet but the rain had stopped. &lt;a href="http://www.cambrian-news.co.uk/news/i/24955/"&gt;A quick look online showed
massive flooding in the area&lt;/a&gt; but we decided to go out anyway and
got to the forestry car park at about 10.30. It wasn't exactly nice out and getting out of the van I stepped into a stream that
had never been there before! I wasn't feeling stoked at this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Me not looking best impressed" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-Ksi_Wky28HI/T9SHag6SJsI/AAAAAAAAAvo/gmpIkUKcPOA/s640/P1010171.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trundled over toward Nant and got to the bottom of the Pendam climb that pops us up near the base of Hippity Hop.
Wow! There was an unreal amount of water flowing down the track and the stream nearby was completely white and very
rapid. Climbing up this bit of the climb there was a constant rut that went to about 3 foot deep in places - utterly, utterly
crazy. The photo below shows the water streaming down the track, never seen it like that before. We thought that this was
a lot of water, little did we know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Water!" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-NGZ2TjGFNCA/T9SHdooujlI/AAAAAAAAAv4/98JSw5wcPhg/s640/P1010172.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward we went and kicked out onto the Conti trail, as soon as we came across the first lake we noticed that it was ridiculously high
with water everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-c_iRkvSdqR8/T9SHbt94nOI/AAAAAAAAAvs/TMSkWi8cDgk/s640/P1010173.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-rq8BoxXuW4Y/T9SHhtxALhI/AAAAAAAAAwA/z9IacXJl06U/s640/P1010174.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point a Forestry Commission 4x4 came along and we had a brief chat with the guy who told us that
Nant-y-moch resevoir had received 10 inches of water the previous day and that they were struggling to stop
the dam from overflowing! The epicness of this ride was rising pretty rapidly! Onward we went until we hit the first
bit of a river crossing which has a bridge. The path to the bridge itself was flooded and we had to find a bit of an alternate line
to it but the path away from the bridge was flooded in all directions and we had to jump the fence and trudge through
a bit of shallow bog to get back to the path. Unreal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-GADXEstLmPM/T9SHimAAlGI/AAAAAAAAAwE/RoEL8L_jVyQ/s512/P1010176.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-BdMpwGN6msA/T9SHrnbgL5I/AAAAAAAAAwc/kDwIlZX1sek/s640/P1010177.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-vsihmz3fUd0/T9SHryjmiJI/AAAAAAAAAwg/YF1sDnaGajQ/s640/P1010178.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided that we'd continue on the route that I had planned which cut off the Conti trail at this point onto a bit
of track that I'd done before with the Ystwyth guys, a fair amount of this track was now a stream but rideable! We continued on
and did the ridiculous grass descent down to the resevoir where the Conti loop joins. Ben managed to hit a tuft of grass and have
a bit of a comical off too. Back on the Conti trail we rode the bit that leads to the resevoir backward and we'd then cross another
stream and cut down to where one of the Conti trails descends to from the resevoir (we'd do this descent later). First major issue of the day!
As we approached the stream we could see a group of motocrossers stood about and as we passed them one was walking back toward us. His sole comment
was "Good luck with that", I didn't think much of it and figured that we'd find a way across. Uh, no. The stream was way, way
too high to get across and despite back tracking down the river for a while we couldn't find anywhere to cross. We bikehiked back across directly to the trail
that we'd just come along and rode back along it and started following the Conti trail the correct way again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was expecting the puddles in this section to be quite bad but they looked deep enough that we decided to skirt around
the sides of all of them. We hit the descent and it was pretty wild, streams running down it everywhere and big rocks all over
the place. Just as we got to toward the end we overtook 2 of the motocrossers we'd seen earlier, putting us down a really crap line
with a lot of water running down it and some big, sketchy looking rocks. No matter we made it down fine. At this point
we had to wait aaaages for the motocrossers to get up the start of the climb to the Bont Goch descent, they were taking forever. In the end
we just gave up and passed them, not often you overtake crossers going uphill!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Ij4ocpbrBOo/T9SH1Squ_sI/AAAAAAAAAxE/s8gPppyNhBQ/s640/P1010182.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bont Goch descent itself was really, really hard work with a stream running down it and massive rocks all over the place. Most of
the previous lines that i knew were totally gone. The rocky descent just off the Bont Goch descent was just as bad with line choice being
pretty key to not either going down a hole or smacking into a big rock. We got down unscathed and started on the long climb
up to Anglers Retreat, the start of this road was underwater too (below) but the actual fireroad was fine and there was
even a bit of sun starting to show! At the top of this climb there's usually a stream crossing followed by a short, sharp technical
climb. We had a brief discussion and decided that the stream crossing would likely be uncrossable so skirted around that section
on the road...into the wind which was really starting to pick up now! We continued on up the fireroad to the start of the next descent which
actually started off fairly dry but I felt that sudden feeling that the rear of the bike felt dead. Rear tyre totally flat.
Quick swapping of tubes and we were off again, following the standard set so far this descent was also soaking but most of the lines had stayed intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-bi2Cmcapn3I/T9SH8NzscaI/AAAAAAAAAxQ/DK_Whwk2gsU/s512/P1010184.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-YtCOrxWnvZs/T9SIBejBfgI/AAAAAAAAAxc/XRIKX6LjDp0/s512/P1010185.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-3EFYzJH6FsM/T9SIFfwNhSI/AAAAAAAAAxo/Xf5dcj68xbo/s640/P1010186.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was the bit that links Anglers to the Mach 3, I'd only done this once before but we picked it up easily enough and
skirted around a couple of puddles before hitting a stream crossing. This was completely and utterly unpassable. It was very deep
and looked really fast. Quick look at the OS map and we decided to head back up to the start of the previous descent and pick up
a fireroad there. Once we got to the point that marks the start of that previous descent we stopped for a bit of lunch and
decided that we'd head back to Nant as we didn't know if we'd actually be able to get to Mach and it was getting to be fairly late
already. The usual way back has a deep crossing that we decided wouldn't be a good idea so we picked up the road and headed back that way
before picking up the Conti loop backward again and riding the same bit of trail for the third time! What really struck
us at this point was that the water level had gone down loads. We actually make it across the afore-mentioned bridge with
no problems and even the lake had gone down a fair bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-VdbnhOPkjj8/T9SINyROoLI/AAAAAAAAAyA/B4pb8G65qwM/s640/P1010189.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ckYanT2gcP0/T9SIR5Bl0GI/AAAAAAAAAyM/1vYEXQwpxCk/s640/P1010190.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-6p-la4URrPk/T9SIUQbdGnI/AAAAAAAAAyU/pdWhumMjyj8/s640/P1010191.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once back at Nant we picked up the Summit loop and did Hippity Hop, Drunken Druid and High as a Kite before a brief break at the visitors
centre. We left off from there and headed up to the Italian Job and saw a sign stating that the Summit trail was closed due to a landslide,
this we later learnt was on the leg burner, a section had collapsed. We had no intentions of going down toward the bottom end of the
trail anyway so pushed on and did Italian Job and Hippity Hop. All of the Summit trails that we did were running fine and felt good
as usual. We did the really eroded climb from earlier backward which was pretty wild in bits and continued on to and did the top
of White Fridge which was also ace before heading back to the van.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ace ride that despite not getting us either Mach and back or 100km was great fun, a bit of an adventure and 60km! Thanks
to Ben for the photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/93963151"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/93963151&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-sXk_GO3ypWQ/T9SIZYitFGI/AAAAAAAAAyc/LEqKS9RMumM/s640/P1010192.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-SXGSGByHoPs/T9SIrlBIrrI/AAAAAAAAAzM/GodaPrjyFyA/s640/P1010197.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Dc-6of6cURU/T9SIikYkqlI/AAAAAAAAAyw/rbPu5n1R59Y/s640/P1010194.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-5C7SLqhWAkA/T9SIjuSym-I/AAAAAAAAAy4/_9uF_BHh2l0/s640/P1010195.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="nant-y-arian"></category></entry><entry><title>Eastridge XC</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jun/02/eastridge-xc/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-06-02:posts/2012/Jun/02/eastridge-xc/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I'm back on the farm and so we planned a ride over at &lt;a href="http://www.forestry.gov.uk/website/recreation.nsf/LUWebDocsByKey/EnglandHerefordshireTheMarchesEastridge"&gt;Eastridge to do the XC loop&lt;/a&gt;.
It's worth mentioning at this point that Ben and I did a 50 mile road loop up to, around and back
from Lake Vyrnwy. It was pretty nice but the SPDs caused a lot of pain behind my right knee which was
still very sore today. Anyway, earlier in the week I looked at the length of Eastridge XC loop and it
turned out to be 8km, rather short and probably a 2 lap job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We turned up to the carpark and waited about an hour for Bean, standard really. The loop took
us 2 hours! 8km took us 2 hours! This was a mixture of my leg hurting a lot and Bean taking
ages to repair his snapped chain, this was Ok though there was a little double just next to
where he snapped it so I played on that trying to clear it for a while, managed it in the end!
The Eastridge XC loop is pretty damn good, OK it is short BUT it's pretty much all singletrack with
no fireroad so it's pretty demanding and definitely not an easy course. Really, really good fun though and
will certainly be going back there, hopefully next time we'll get in 2 loops and there are also the old DH tracks so
plently of stuff to play about on too.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="eastridge"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Week Summary</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-19:posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past week I've managed to get out on the mountain bike 3 times which isn't bad really! On Sunday
Ben and I drove to Rich's place after leaving the hotel from Seb's stag do. We spent quite a lot of time tinkering with
bikes and for once we didn't have to tinker with mine! We headed to the Wyre Forest, somewhere that I'd not been before.
After a bacon sandwich from the cafe we set off riding, this place reminded me quite a lot of Swinley Forest. The surface
was quite sandy and I could hear my drivetrain grinding as we were riding round. It was quite an enjoyable little blast,
none of the hills were particularly big but there were lots of short little descents and climbs which was quite fun. A few steep bits
but for the most part it was just flat out with very little tech, which suited me having had a few beers the night before. Ben
managed to have a pretty decent sized crash off the side of one of the trails that saw his bike go pinwheeling off down the
side of the hill but he was OK. Pretty fun place, good singletrack! Once again we managed to resemble a Cotic fanclub as
the image below shows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Brace of Cotics" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-4y1gahqJ_Fc/T7diyQyMf-I/AAAAAAAABHU/cl2cw2CntEo/s400/IMG_20120513_131943.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other two rides I've done this week have both been up Nant-y-arian. Wednesday night I popped up with Andy and
we did the usual Ystwyth loop, climbing up to Hippity Hop car park, doing the Summit loop and then back via White Fridge, my
favourite loop! It was a pretty uneventful ride but, as ever, top fun. I played the no pedal game down most of the descents
as I'm trying to develop my skills to gain speed from the trail and try to brake less. We managed to get round the 25km in just
under 2 hours which we were pretty happy with, we didn't ride especially quick we just didn't take any breaks. The other ride we
did on Friday night, again with Andy but this time with Tom too. We started at Hippity Hop and just did a standard Summit loop.
For some reason this was a really, really fun ride. We took our time (16km in just over 2 hours) and just generally messed about.
Following Andy really is great fun, he jumps off loads of little things and is very stylish to watch. Taking his lines and
trying to do all the little jumps that he does is ace! That boy really is rather good on a bike. We had a bit of a mechanical
midway up the leg burner when Tom's chain went bang but other than that it was fairly plain sailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nant-y-arian viewpoint" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jAxPNMnOOx8/T7di-TLRZfI/AAAAAAAABHc/TAeHUHXIPR0/s640/IMG_20120518_195035.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this week I've playing with nodejs for work. I'm pretty impressed, using the express framework I've managed to knock
something together for our platform pretty quickly and easily! I'm also very much loving using javascript on both the back and
front end. As a part of this I've also been learning to use Jade templates, this has meant no static pages and each page generated
on the fly. This has also enabled me to do some pretty funky stuff although unfortunately can't really go into detail.
I do have 1 tip for using couchdb. If you want to access it from anywhere that isn't localhost then you need to go into the
local config file and change the bindings to 0.0.0.0 from 127.0.0.1, this may be a little less secure as it opens couchdb up to
requests from any interface but it took me about 2 hours of trying to get a proxy to use work before finding that out! I also
wound up using this nodejs proxy server that is pretty simple and works: &lt;a href="http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/"&gt;http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="nant-y-arian"></category><category term="javascript"></category></entry><entry><title>Sebs Stag</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/12/sebs-stag/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-12:posts/2012/May/12/sebs-stag/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Saturday was Seb's stag do which was set to be go-karting, comedy club and a night out. I left home at around 9am bound
for Ben's place and from there we continued to &lt;a href="http://www.cannonraceway.co.uk/"&gt;Coseley Go karting&lt;/a&gt; (via a few wrong turns because Ben knew better
than the sign that said "Go Karting this way"). Yes, their website does have a video that starts playing loud music as soon
as you load the home page, no I do not know who thought that was a good idea. We managed to somehow arrive bang on time and met a few new faces
and saw a few old ones too. It had been a very long time since I had last seen Rob and Seb, about 2 years!
We wandered in and got suited up, registered etc... and George managed to turn up mid-briefing so we were all sorted and
ready to go. The karting consisted of 10 seeding laps followed by a 60 lap race. The karting was pretty good fun
and I was pretty surprised how much it made my arms hurt, drifting over the small bumps in the floor really, really
hurt! Unfortunately I had to pull off after about 20 laps (was in 4th at the time, out of 10) due to my back bneing in
agony. It's probably worth mentioning that I had a massive crash on my mtb Friday evening...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I'd pulled off I stood in the spectator area and watched everyone else. There were plently of spins and crashes and
quite a few diagonal flags were shown. This was the flag that signified that you were driving too recklessly and to
calm it down or you'd get pulled into the pits for a "chat". About 40 laps in I saw someone get the diagonal flag and then
hit someone else pretty hard mid-lap, sure enough they got the special yellow and orange checked flag and had to pull in.
Probably could have already guessed who it would be and the number 2 on the front confirmed my suspicion - it was Ben. Sadly for
him he was in first at the time! A few more uneventful laps and the race was over. Rob won with Seb in second place, Ben managed 6th despite
having been pulled into the pits! I, obviously, came in last!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karting over we headed into the centre of Birminham to the hotel. This took quite a while longer than planned too. Rob and
George were following us in the car behind and after driving for quite some time rang through to ask if we knew where
we were going because they thought that we'd passed where we wanted to turn off about 10 minutes before. At this point
we had to admit that no, we didn't have a clue! But, no harm done, we turned around and headed back int he right direction,
we parked up in the very busy multi-storey carpark next door to the travelodge for a pretty sum of 3 for 24 hours, can't
complain about that really - pretty good! Travelodge was as expected, a travelodge. We showered, changed etc... and headed
to Jimmy Spices. This place was an all you can eat buffet of a load of different cuisines. I tried quite a variety of
the food on offer and really enjoyed their butter chicken. Somehow, despite taking it easy, managed to eat too much
and felt pretty bloated for the next hour or so after, fairly typical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we'd been fed we headed toward the &lt;a href="http://www.thehighlight.co.uk/"&gt;Highlight&lt;/a&gt; comedy club via a pint or 2 in Spoons. We arrived in Highlight
to find that Paul had ordered the Stag package so we had a table right at the very front of the stage, could already
see the fear in Seb's eyes! We also had table service which we all cunningly managed to forget time and again. Ben bought
a 4 pint pitcher for the 2 of us and that did us for the duration of the time that we were in there. I'm not going to lie,
I can't remember the names of any of the comedians. Tell a lie I just remembed the compere was Rudi Lickwood. He was very good,
loads of laughs and kept coming back to pick on Seb a bit and tell him the woes of married life. The other comedians were also
very good including a sort of slap stick duo who had a very, very clever act. I was quite amazed at how little heckling there was,
anyone who tried pretty rapidly got shot down and made to look a fool by the act that was on at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the comedy club we headed to Gatecrasher, this was the part of the night that I hadn't been looking forward to so much!
Once we were in we went for a short walk to see what rooms etc... there were and wound up at a bar overlooking the main dancefloor.
We were quite quickly joined by a group of very skimpily dressed girls with very odd makeup and cans strapped to their heads. They
turned out to be the dancers, still no idea what the get-up was all about - very odd! Ben, Rob and I bought a round of JD and cokes each,
at 12 quid a round, 1 round was enough! At about 1am everyone headed to the dancefloor so George and I decided to head back
to the hotel, Gatecrasher wasn't really our scene, especially not the dancing part! Ben came back a while after us and then Rob
came in later on, Rob had come back with the others and somehow Paul had managed to get his phone stolen, he was rather drunk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we had a pretty average breakfast in the hotel but at least it was unlimited and had a coffee machine! Once we'd
eaten and grabbed our stuff we all said our goodbyes and headed off. Next time I'll see Seb will be his wedding in July I suspect.
All in all it was an enjoyable day, a bit pricey but I had fun and I'm pretty sure that Seb did too so job's a good'un!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="boozing"></category></entry><entry><title>Clarach Shred</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/07/clarach-shred/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-07:posts/2012/May/07/clarach-shred/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dyfi enduro was yesterday so Ben and I decided that a bit of downhilling was in order,
had enough of riding uphill. We took the morning fairly easy and chilled before heading over
at around lunch time. We started out by hitting the top of the main line a couple of times, neither
of us really in the mood for a full push back up. It was riding fast and fun. We decided to try the new line
that the freshers have built as neither of us had ridden the full thing. Fair play to them, really, really
fun blast of a track. Nothing too technical but fast and jumpy. Since I had last ridden it they'd
added 2 massive berms and a big jump in at the bottom. The berms are big and ace to ride, the jump on the other hand
just isn't quite right. The takeoff is somewhat steep and short and the landing is tiny and too close! Every time
we hit it we were overshooting the landing to uphill which isn't all that great on a hardtail I can tell you!
But all in all they've done a good job, there are a couple of tricky bits that are slippery and off camber, I also managed
to have a bit of a stack trying to ride out a really cheeky bit of a line!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also hit up the top of the wall ride track and spent ages working down a couple of the tracks taking photos
and generally messing about. Rad shred and great way to finish off the 3 day weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few photos from the day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-92rWHYv67nA/T6mqJt6UnlI/AAAAAAAAAs0/bGKZPrYsHgE/s661/P1010129+%282%29.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Ben going off the wall ride kicker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-nOnSMrDq6CA/T6mrOAB2jaI/AAAAAAAAAtM/7dJaLiHRufI/s661/P1010132+%281%29.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Blurry one of me on the same kicker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-U6XVY_35QFI/T6mrrSzXcUI/AAAAAAAAAtc/ufjmaMpgD9A/s595/P1010135+%281%29.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Ben hitting the small drop on the new line&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-47ekAkQFuQM/T6msUvD14wI/AAAAAAAAAts/tpHPkc0nOUo/s661/P1010137+%281%29.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-qMPPohfoXWQ/T6msrAWb1gI/AAAAAAAAAt8/Dil-SlmFGGw/s661/P1010140+%281%29.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="clarach"></category></entry><entry><title>Dyfi Enduro Weekend</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/06/dyfi-enduro-weekend/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-06:posts/2012/May/06/dyfi-enduro-weekend/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend marked the annual Dyfi Enduro event. A couple of the old abermtb group were coming
back for this and it was shipping up to be a good weekend of riding. Ben was, as usual, staying with
me and we arranged to meet Joe, Stu, Paul and Andy over at Capel Dewi at 11 for a bit of downhill
before heading to Nant-y-arian at 2. Before setting out in the morning Ben and I had the simple,
single, task of changing my brakes pads. As is always the way, this was not a simple task.
The brake pads themselves took a lot of convincing to get in and even after letting some oil
out of the system there was no way the rotor was going in! After much wasted time, I remembered that
I had a partially worn set of contaminated pads. With a bit of convincing we got the rotor to go in
with these pads fitted. However, we had cunningly managed to let air into the system so we pissed about
bleeding the brake for a while till we had a fantastic lever but a rear wheel that didn't spin freely!
We figured it'd do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En-route to Capel Dewi (running late) I received a fun phone call from my Dad informing me
that I'd been caught speeding when I went down to Oxford. This was shaping up to be a bit
of a crap day. I couldn't get my head in the game at Capel Dewi but we hit up a few runs
and I still had fun. The ride up Nant-y-arian went much better! We met up with a group of
Paul's mates from Norwich in the carpark and set out. The trails were riding really nice
and the climbs felt pretty good, we even snuck in secret Zorro. Such a fun descent featuring
drops, singletrack, scree slopes, jumps, all in all pretty rad! First ride in a while where I
came bvack totally dry too, always good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bright and early Sunday morning we headed for Machynlleth to park up and sign on for the event.
Race plates fitted (701 here) and bikes ready to go we (Ben and I) joined the ever growing queue of riders
and their bikes waiting for the starting gates to open. After a bit of a light hearted briefing
the gates opened and the riders were off. After the usual stop and starting we managed to get through the gates
5-10 minutes later! Letting off 7-800 riders in one go through a small gateway is never going to be a smooth flow
really! We hit the road and Ben had already managed to get ahead of me so I rode as quickly as
I could along the road overtaking people where I could and being overtaken plenty too. After a few miles
we hit the first offroad climb, I knew that there was no way I'd be catching Ben now so I decided to
just sit back and enjoy myself and ride at my own pace to try see how quickly I could get round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MOQ9DQ352sw/T6mm5lsOHDI/AAAAAAAAAr0/0dfh0Zb0H9Q/w464-h348-k/P1010117.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Riders waiting for the gates to open&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first climb was a long slog of a fire road but I knew that it was coming and paced myself
to sit and spin away, think I even managed to overtake more than I was overtaken! Managed to have a brief chat
with Dave Reed before he raced off ahead. Just before the
top the climb switches back on itself in a big open corner, they usually have a band here but this
time round they had a harp being played - pretty cool! At the top of the climb saw a group of cheerleaders
urging us on, I was contemplating stopping for a rest but decided to push on to try get to
the top of the first descent as quickly as possible to try get a clear run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top of Elephant I was ready to go and even though I was following someone we were going
quick enough for me to hit the first kicker. Unfortunately overtaking opportunities were pretty
scarse on this descent as it's rather narrow. Before even reaching the first corner we somehow
found ourselves queueing up stationary. Still not sure why but eventually we started moving again,
we hit the first corner and the guy in front of my looked somewhat out of his depth and managed to fall off!
I quickly checked he was OK and then set off again before getting stuck behind someone else. No matter,
got the end of the descent and prepared myself for climbing for quite some time. The course took us fairly directly up to the
field climb where the uphill gets a bit more technical. For some reason my camelbak resevoir was refusing to
let me drink anything so by this point I was getting a bit parched having not drank anything since before we started. I made it most of
the way over the field before stopping and draining half of my water bottle. I then hit the really steep bit of the climb and
just as i hit the top I heard a familiar voice and Andy and Stu appeared. Despite them both saying they'd be really
unfit and slow they must have been going pretty quickly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to try to stick with them and following them down the descents was rather good although Andy is
still somewhat reckless and made some rather interesting overtakes. The descents were all running nicely
and plenty of overtaking was on the cards. I lost them at the new technical climb, I was off and pushing, as
was everyone around me - not a fun climb really. The next time that I saw them was at the bottom of the World Cup descent which was, as always, utterly
rad. The big dipper before it was quite entertaining with some massive puddles and plenty of people complaining, I
managed to ride through the middle of the lot (well, walked one after stopping in the middle). Between big dipper and World Cup
is a small climb through some trees, as I rode into the trees I could hear the iconic Star Wars music getting louder and louder.
I rounded a corner and there it was, a group of people dressed up in Star Wars outfits and battling with light sabres, it was
a nice distraction and helped to keep things interesting! I kept up with Andy and Stu
for the start of the long, grueling climb from World Cup to the feed station but they pretty quickly shot off in the distance.
After quite a long time I hit this final leg of the climb and got a bit of a kick and picked up the pace, just as I hit
the top I bumped into Ben. Unfortunately his seat post clamp had exploded at the bottom of World Cup so he'd been
riding the entire climb stood up - not much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the feed station we found Andy and Stu again and stocked up on food and liquids (Stu left with more food than he started with!), we ended up being there for
about half an hour! During this time we bumped into a couple more faces we knew and Paul also turned up. At this point
the 5 of us set off together and pretty much just rode the rest of the way together. Ben was still pedalling stood up
right through to the end which kept him reigned in riding at our pace! A couple more descents and another crap climb or two saw
Paul and I at the top of 3in1 having been told that this would be the end we decided we'd take it easy down and just try to stay
in 1 piece. Paul flew off and I knew that there was no way we were taking it easy. We hurtled down and it was grins all round at the bottom,
despite Paul taking us through a tree. At the bottom we were greated by a pretty surreal sight of a beer tent with a disco.
We were given a free beer each and we couldn't be happier! We waited for Ben and then rolled down to the finish line. We finished in one
minute under 5 hours, not quite as quick as I'd planned but still my best time by quite some way! It was also unfortunate that
we didn't get to do the final descent but seeing that arrow pointing to the finish area not a big old climb up to
the final descent was very, very welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-QSaVjg4ETvM/T6moM51EQlI/AAAAAAAAAsQ/JtdojT-kfwU/s661/P1010122.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Welcome sight of the disco and beer tent!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ikqM4CnGtkM/T6mpjsL6t9I/AAAAAAAAAss/OCmyow4-z70/s496/P1010124.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;Always a good sign!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pedalled back down into Machynlleth to the main event area to get our Dyfi Enduro mugs and to have a bit of a sit down and a natter
before heading back to Aber. An ace day of riding was topped off with a lovely meal in the Tynllidiart Arms in Capel Bangor.
A really great couple of days riding with a great group of people. Here's looking forward to next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rider number:    701&lt;br /&gt;
Rider name:  Charles Dixon
Category:   Male 18-40
Position (by route):     301st out of 508&lt;br /&gt;
Position (by category):  170th out of 275&lt;br /&gt;
Team: &lt;br /&gt;
ClusterFUNK
[700] Ben Powles Finished at 15:58:53 (Duration 4hr 58min 53sec) [702] Chris Taylor No result recorded
Route    Main Loop&lt;br /&gt;
Finish time  15:59:00 (Duration 4hr 59min 0sec)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fastest time of the day was from Matt Page in 2h34 and he did the longer loop (that we didn't do) too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/86270115"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/86270115&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-5M5lD2ADfao/T6mpZhoNgNI/AAAAAAAAAsc/Y9g1FlQxgFA/s661/P1010123.JPG" /&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size: small; text-align: center;"&gt;A bonus photo of Paul looking dead!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Ben for the pictures!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="dyfi"></category><category term="nant-y-arian"></category></entry><entry><title>Nant-y-arian evening ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/03/nant-y-arian-evening-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-03:posts/2012/May/03/nant-y-arian-evening-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past few xc rides I've not really been feeling the downhills. They've felt
slow and forced to try make any speed on them, it's been fine over Clarach but for
some reason Nant and even the Dyfi just haven't felt right. Last night that changed,
I seemed to get my mojo back, the trails started to flow again and the speed was just there.
I think that dropping the forks down to 140mm has played a part in that as has having
a little less stress on my mind due to finding a place to live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, last night I met up with the ystwyth guys at our usual spot up at Nant. I'd elected to
use spd's for this ride, my second offroad ride with them. I decided to use them as I
know the trails well and there isn't anything that I'd be worried about riding in them at all.
The first climb up the pendam climb felt pretty good, could notice the front end flicking up
less with the lower travel and I got up it feeling fine, but still the slowest! We rode over the
moorlands and headed to zorro. Zorro was good and felt fast, the last bit through the trees is
always nice and felt a bit faster this time than my last few rides. One very noticeable thing
so far into the ride was that my rear brake was squealing A LOT and not really doing much
in the way of slowing me down, no matter the front was getting the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up the leg burner, I found the guys stopped at the 3/4 mark. This was the fastest time
I've got up the 3/4 so far and also felt the best so far, fitness is certainly still
increasing at a fairly good rate. Upto Drunken Druid which felt significantly faster than
the last few times that I've ridden it and I cleared the short, sharp climb after it with
no problems, spd's doing their part there I think. Midway down High as a Kite I had a
bit of an incident with both ends washing out, to my amazement I clipped out without
even thinking about it and got in a dab. That single dab has upped my confidence in the spd's
no end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Italian job, Hippity Hop and the top of white fridge all rode great, although I did nearly
spd dump at the top of hippity hop! Back at the cars
I felt good. Most enjoyable nant ride that I've had in a while, everything just felt good!
At this point I decided to investigate that squeal, wheel off, pads out. Well, the picture below says
more than I can in words!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-X6YH2LQQbQ4/T6OdzVM2EkI/AAAAAAAABGY/rTLRYtCvIds/s400/IMG_20120504_101304.jpg"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/85611258"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/85611258&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="nant-y-arian"></category></entry><entry><title>Dyfi Trail Repairs</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Apr/29/dyfi-trail-repairs/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-04-29:posts/2012/Apr/29/dyfi-trail-repairs/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Dan, Gaz and I met up with the some of the locals to do some repairs
to a couple of the Dyfi enduro descents. We split into 2 groups and our group
went off to the top of the world cup descent to fill in a bit of a rut. The reasoning
behind this was that the 2 jumps near the beginning of the trail have been built up
a bit and the only real line leads straight into them! As such we filled in a bit of a massive
rut to provide a nice line that leads around the jumps. Think I'll have to hit the jumps
next Sunday, will be severely punished if I come up short though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After filling in this rut we moved over to a piece of trail that I've not seen before
that will be used as a climb. It's fairly, steep and loose-ish, no surprises there. 
About midway up we met the second group clearing back some brash and draining a massive
puddle. Nothing much to do so we headed back down again. I get a feeling that I will
be off and pushing for this climb, it's hard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up we headed to 3in1 to cut in a bit of a new line at the top to get round
the huge puddle there. Lots of raking and general moving of bits and pieces and there
is now a nice line that should be quite good to ride over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, also - the weather was utterly, utterly gopping! Howling wind and tipping down for the
most part. Dyfi Enduro is going to be weeeeet!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category><category term="trails"></category></entry><entry><title>House hunting</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Apr/28/house-hunting/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-04-28:posts/2012/Apr/28/house-hunting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I've spent Wednesday-Friday flat/house hunting for a place to rent for
when we move down to Oxford. I had about 7 places lined up to go look at over the 2.5
days which increased to 9 whilst I was down there. Tuesday night I drove down to Georges
where I would be staying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday I only had 2 bookings and in the morning that got reduced to 1 by an estate
agent bailing out. As George was feeling a bit crap I gave him a lift into Oxford to work which
was surprisingly easier than I had suspected it would be, I also ended up taking him in and picking
him up all 3 days! At midday I went to my first booking which was in Kennington which looked
to be a pretty good location for getting into Oxford, upon arriving I noticed that there
was also a pub pretty much the other side of the road, always a good thing! This flat was furnished
and was quite nice but incredibly small and on the second floor so the road bike would be a bit
of a hassle both to fit and get in. It was pretty much 2 rooms, a living area with the kitchen attached
and a bedroom with en-suite. At this point it's worth mentioning that Oxford prices are bloody
insane! I couldn't quite see how the price of this place was justified given the size of it, guess the price
reflected the location. I managed to get from the door of the property into the centre of Oxford, including
parking and getting on the p&amp;amp;r bus, within 15 minutes - not bad going! Naturally, being in Oxford, I had 2 burrito's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday I had 6 bookings lined up starting from 10am so I dropped George into work and headed back to Abingdon
and set off to the marina. This flat was in a nice development area and wasn't a bad sized flat (ground floor) with a communal
garden type area. I wasn't massively taken with it though unfortunately, the location was right at the bottom of Abingdon
so not as good for Oxford or the A34 as the other properties I had lined up. I can't even remember how this place
was laid out! After the viewing I followed the estate agent to my next viewing at the Vineyard flats. The next place
was also a second floor flat but once again a decent size. I was taken by the kitchen which was once
again joined to the living area but both areas were large and there was a nice breakfast bar as a kind of
separator. I mentally noted this place as worth keeping in mind. At this point I was pretty close to George's flat so headed back,
my next viewing was in the same development as his flat. I met the estate agent and it actually turned out to the be the next
door down from George! Another second floor flat and this one was quite small despite the agent keep saying
she was impressed with the size of it. I've forgotten what this one was like as I wasn't at all taken!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next 2 viewings were in Botley and I noticed that they were the most expensive ones I was viewing, I didn't book
these! First one was yet another second floor apartment and was OK but the kitchen was utterly tiny and had quite a
lot of road noise. For the price I was majorly unimpressed and getting a bit worried that I wasn't going to find anywhere.
After this viewing I had a thrilling time sat in the car for an hour waiting for my next viewing. This viewing
was an actual house which I quite interested by. Upon walking to the door I could tell it was going to be fairly small, the house
is on the end of a block and the door is actually round the side not on the front like the other houses! We walked in and
I was instantly impressed with the layout, kitchen was a decent size and quite nice and it had a downstairs toilet too! The
main living area was very nice and spacious and had wooden floors. There was a small conservatory which was nice and a private
garden area which was gravel and paved with a shed, A SHED, this one I could actually bring my mtb to! Upstairs had 2 bedrooms
and a bathroom which all looked alright. After a bried chat with the agent he said that a small cat wouldn't be a problem
and that for the right tenatnts the landlady was prepared to knock 70 quid a month off the advertised price. Bingo, this
was very much on my radar now! Quite ideal location too with good access to both A34 and Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I popped back to Abingdon for the last viewing of the day. This property was another house but I can't remember
much about it now, I wasn't very excited by it especially the lack of white goods. I went into Oxford a bit early to pick George up as i'd arranged a chat with One Ltd
just to say hi and discuss what they do etc... They were really, really nice and we had a good laugh too, hopefully
I'll bump into them at hack days, geek nights etc... Friday morning I popped George into Oxford and headed back to Abingdon for
my final viewing, this was a ground floor flat and was quite big. Massive joint area for the main living space and
kitchen. 2 bedrooms, en-suite and a main bathroom. I decided that this would be a good backup flat as I wanted to try
get the one in Botley. I rang the agent and told him that we wanted it but he told me that there was another viewing
in the afternoon and that the landlady wanted to honour it, fair enough. I packed mine and George's stuff into the car
and headed off. I was at the farm when Maura called me to say that the landlady wanted the weekend to consider who
to take on as the other party who viewing had expressed an interest, made me nervous! In the evening I popped to the
lime kiln with Ben and drank about 4 pints more than planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I woke up feeling groggy but with a text from Maura saying that we had the property! I rang the agent
and got the fees paid straight away. So we're now sorted so long as we pass all the various checks that
the agents run on us. All very exciting and had to try to think of a way to find some furniture and hope Maura
gets a job in Oxford pretty quickly as we're going to be Ok but a bit low on spare cash otherwise. Whilst on the farm I also
took a look at the array of solar panels that Dad had installed on one of the sheds, pretty cool! Here's a picture of the shed
at the house we're hopefully going to be renting! I will be fortifying it A LOT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/posts/househunt.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category></entry><entry><title>Dyfi Pre-ride</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Apr/22/dyfi-pre-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-04-22:posts/2012/Apr/22/dyfi-pre-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dyfi Enduro is 2 weeks today so today marked the dyfi pre-ride where a group of
us ride the potential route. Dan turned up at my truck at around 9am so we packed up
and got on the way, planning to arrive early so that I could change wheel and make sure the
brakes were aligned OK. About halfway there we stopped at some traffic lights and found
the car in front was Dave, doesn't matter how early I am I never arrive before him!
We arrived at the Climach-x car park and discovered that we were pretty much the last to
arrive, a few faces that I recognised and a few that I didn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start saw us do the first climb of the enduro, not a fun climb! It's not too steep
though, just long so I sat and merrily span away until the top, at this point the weather
was spitting a bit. Once up that climb we continued up to the Elephant descent, no I have no
idea why it's called that. I somehow managed to be following Jon down it, he's pretty
terrifying to follow at the best of times. Before even reaching the big clay left hander he
managed to clip the edge of the rut and jump out of it, luckily without falling off.
Cue the big left hander and Jon on the floor, luckily unharmed. About another 100 metres
down the trail and I see Jon go through about 3 trees without bike, once again unharmed!
At this point I thought it best to overtake and had an uneventful rest of the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First descent done means time for another big ole climb, this one being largely more difficult!
After climbing up to the field I knew what was in store, a fairly steep offroad climb that
I'd never managed to do all in one go before let alone without dabbing. Success! For the
first time ever I managed the entire thing in one go without a single dab (though it came
close a couple of times!). That climb over it was time for another fun descent - Baileys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baileys is a steep, loose, exposed, rocky descent that's fast and fun! It'd worn down a bit since
the last time that I rode it so there were less little drops and it was smoother although
no less loose! Somehow I managed to be following Jon again, about half way down I saw him
go flying off to the left of the trail and stop, he looked fine so I continued on my way.
The big corner at the bottom has also worn away quite badly and there was a huge rut in it,
by chance I somehow wound up on the high line of it so avoided the rut. All down and accounted for
it turned out that Jon had lost a water bottle, not the most water bottle friendly place
the Dyfi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued along for a short distance up a very short incline before hitting the next downhill,
which I cannot for the life of me remember! The next climb was a fairly long, tiring fireroad slogleading us up to the trail known as
The Big Dipper. This trail starts off undulating with some vicious, short rocky climbs. I didn't make it up
a couple of them. There were also some fairly serious puddles, several totally englufed my pedals
and feet along with them, as well as a couple where I stopped in the middle and had to get off and walk
through them! Once this bit was out of the way the trail continued in normal dyfi fashion, rocky n steep!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once we didn't have to ride uphill post-descent as we rode straight into the World Cup descent,
a fantastic bit of trail. Starting out fast and fairly flowy with massive ruts all over the place and a
handul of jumps spotted about the place the trail transforms into very, very steep bedrock. Words can't
quite describe how fun this descent is and it's all over far too fast. Pete got a flat midway down so
we stopped for a breather whilst we waited for him to come down. The end of this descent also
marks the start of a very long slog which is fairly steep in places. After a brief break we started 
out on said climb. At the top of this climb is where the feed station is usually situated so we stopped
for a break and some food where the feed station would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward and steep and rocky the order of the day once again! Midway down the top of this descent I got caught between 2 lines
and a moment of indecision of whether to hold the high line or drop into a rut saw me on the floor.
Unscathed I let through the guys behind me and continued, just so happened that Dan had also stopped about 5 metres
away from me. Within 10 metres I saw Dan get completely sideways as he hit a muddy off camber
section of a rut, unfornately by this point I was already committed to his line! Luckily we both
rode it out and stopped at the next fireroad for a quick relieved laugh before continuing on
downhill with no more issues. At the bottom we discovered that Jon had once again lost
a bottle and was hiking back off up the trail to find it. Once we had regrouped it was back off uphill
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fairly short climb saw us at the top of the next descent, this one I usually have a moment or two on!
This is a (obviously) fairly steep trail that is covered in water and bedrock, Dan set off and I decided to
follow him, for some reason he decided to choose a line that was pretty much in a stream and I decided
to follow him. We reached the bottom with no issues and I knew what was coming. This was the only climb of the day
where I had to get off and walk, a quite steep, rocky, singletrack climb. I wasn't alone in my pushing efforts, a few of us
decided that it was the best plan of action. After a while this trail started to point back downhill,
a downhill that's (you guessed it) steep and rocky but also full of whoops, great fun! Once again got down to the bottom
with no problems and prepared myself for the next climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point my legs were starting to ache but I knew that the climb took us to the top of
3 in 1, a descent not far from the cars. After slogging away for a while I reached the top, most of the
group was already there! A brief discussion about the next course of action decided that everyone
would go down 3 in 1 and then split into 2 groups - 1 going back to the cars and the other climbing up to the
Dyfi final descent. At this point I was starting to think that heading back would be nice. We coninuted onto the 3 in 1
going around a massive puddle with mud all over everywhere. 3 in 1 is very muddy as
well as being steep, rocky and flowy and great fun and fast. I had a couple of moments as I wasn't
following anyone so could tear along at my own speed, I caught up to Dan near the bottom where the little beer
tent will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone down the group split into 2, I knew that Dan would want to continue and I wasn't feeling so bad now, I
decided that I could manage another climb. We said bye to the guys going home and cracked on, I had a good pace going on until
the climb got a bit steeper and I started to really feel it in my legs, luckily Dave pulled alongside me so
we had a chat which helped to forget about my legs. At the top of the worst bit Dave stopped to wait for the
others and make sure that they didn't go the wrong way so I continued on not really knowing where to go. Just as I
thought that I must have taken a wrong turning I saw 3 figures on the fireroad ahead a bit and descended down to
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dyfi final descent, I'd only done this trail once previously and could only really remember
1 big bed-rocky corner. Dan went off and I followed, he stopped within about 20 metres shouting something about
lock out so I passed him and razzed down a very fun bit of track before hitting 'that' corner.
I couldn't really see what line to take so just hit the rock and slid on down into the rut at the bottom,
no problems! After this it was very fast and a bit pedally, getting a bit drifty in a big right hander it was ace
fun. Unforntunately we then came across a digger taking up the entire track and loads of brash all
over the place. A brief walk to get round all that and the trail finished off with a fast, muddy section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once everyone was down it was grins all round and we set off along the road back to the carpark. Getting back upto
said car park is a steep climb. I was determined to do it and for the first time ever I got cramp in my leg!
None-the-less I managed to ride up the climb and was pretty happy. We stopped for a brief chat and said our goodbyes and
set off home. Ace ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ride was really, really excellent with a great group of people. It reminded me that the Dyfi
descents are a hoot and can be pretty dangerous if you don't keep your mind in the game.
This also marked my first ride post reducing the travel in the lyriks. I could certainly
tell the difference on the climbs, I rarely had issues with the front lifting and I don't
think that I noticed any difference on the descents. A mixture of the lower travel and being
much fitter than previously meant that I cleaned climbs that i haven't before and didn't
have to push up any fireroads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring on the Dyfi Enduro!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/83344479"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/83344479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Lyriks - travel reduction</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Apr/19/lyriks-travel-reduction/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-04-19:posts/2012/Apr/19/lyriks-travel-reduction/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It recently occured to me that it might make my life a bit easier on xc rides if I
was to drop the travel on the Lyriks (solo air) a tad - giving me a lower front end for the
steep stuff. The first step here was to consider the options available, two options
presented themselves to me. 1 - convert to coil uTurn, 2 - use Rock Shox all travel
spacers. The second step was to decide what travel I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option 1 was by far the more preferable here, uTurn allows for on the fly adjustment meaning
that I could easily wind the travel down when I wanted to and wind it back out for when I
go to the alps. This also means that I could play with different amounts of travel until
I got a length that I felt ideal. The major downside to this option is the price. If
the parts are sourced new then a coil is 55, top out spring is 22, uTurn adjuster is
25 and a sleeve for the coil (precent scratching the insides of the stanchions) is 7.
This puts the price of a conversion to over 100, quite a lot more than I was willing to pay,
coil can be sourced second hand but the rest is quite tricky to source unless buying new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end I opted for option 2 - all travel spacers. After getting in touch with tftuned to
make sure that these would work with my '08 Lyriks (they're labelled for models 2010 onward)
I ordered a set for 12, if I was to do this again I'd just buy a hand ful of nylon washers.
Much cheaper and does the same job. These spacers are fitted inside of the air cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So forks in bits I started the job of taking the air cart apart. This is not a fun job,
between the two ends of the circlip that holds the main body in the stanchion is a little tab.
The first step is to push down on the base plate and turn it to move this tab out of the way.
It rapidly became apparent that the circlip turns with the base plate, cue much swearing and
pissing about. Eventually I got the circlip off and was presented with a totally different
set of internals to the ones shown in the guide I was following (&lt;a href="http://cdn.sram.com/cdn/farfuture/Iyagqzgz8FKPfRtQtkQ7kGP6DaHWJx6hmeiu3n9ZPTA/mtime:1302539000/sites/default/files/techdocs/tm_my102.pdf"&gt;2010 manual&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major difference here is that the guide shows a negative air piston,
in the 08 model this piston is not present. Instead there is a little gromit that seals onto
the base plate to perform the same (or similar) job. This immediately made me question
where I was supposed to place the spacer(s). After a bit of searching I located the 
&lt;a href="http://www.sram.com/_media/pdf/rockshox/dealers/TM_MY08_E.pdf"&gt;2008 manual&lt;/a&gt;
which showed me that I need to put the spacer above the bumper for the top piston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/lyriks.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job done I put the forks back together (spending ages pissing about with that circlip again) and took
the chance to refresh all the oil and lube any seals. It's really quite a simple process
to change the travel and I now have fully working, fantastic feeling 140mm Lyriks!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="bike-maintenance"></category></entry><entry><title>Myherin - at last</title><link href="http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Apr/15/myherin-at-last/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-04-15:posts/2012/Apr/15/myherin-at-last/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally made it over to Myherin with the Ystwyth guys, well just Dave Reed. It's
pretty much everything that Dave told me that it would be but it still didn't fail
to surprise me with just how steep parts are. We started out with a bit of a climb on
a fireroad until reaching a descent that instantly screamed Dyfi at me. Steep &amp;amp; rocky
with woops to pump, very much like many of the Dyfi descents and formed in the same way
by 4x4s and moto bikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit more riding through some steep, muddy stuff that saw me pushing
and we came to what Dave described as the fireroad from hell, it started out fairly steep and then
continued to increase in steepness to the point that I couldn't ride it.
Sat down the front just lifted and stood up the rear just span, at one
point I found myself pointing back down the hill - that signalled time to get off and push.
At the top of this climb we were on top of the hill with the wind turbines, the largest in
Wales apparently, we counted 38 but I'm sure that there were more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After pootling along the top for a bit we came to the descent that we'd come out for.
Dave had told me that this would be steep but that didn't quite prepare me for just
how steep and loose it was! I didn't dare to let off the brakes for fear that I wouldn't
stop if I did. We both got down with no casualties although I did have a bit of moment
having decided to let off the brakes down some bedrock, I very quickly found the bike going sideways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having reached the bottom of this we continued going down on some quite mellow singletrack,
somehow this section saw the only off of the evening. Dave hit a rock and went OTB,
he got up fine but we quickly noticed that his brake lever had popped out of the
reservoir leaving him with no front brake. One more quick descent and a fair bit of climbing and
we were back at the cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a great ride and we barely even needed our lights, only using them for the
very end of the ride. The way that I would define the area is as an intense Dyfi forest.
Much like the Dyfi you're either going up or down and everything is steep, Myherin is just
steeper and more brutal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/81988716"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/81988716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry></feed>