<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link>chvck.co.uk/</link><description>Pointless, sometimes amusing and deeply, deeply uninteresting to 99.72998% of the population</description><atom:link href="chvck.co.uk/feeds/Photo-a-Day.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Photo a day 7th Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to write much about this here as I plan to write another post about the whole thing. This is my first batch
of meds and next Tuesday I find out how to use them, that Wednesday could be interesting... I even got given a bin though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meds" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-JYb2HhlaE3Y/UOsTJftcj5I/AAAAAAAABUA/rWFvSsH8QRc/s640/IMG_20130107_180630.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-07:posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 6th Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I went to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultimate_(sport)"&gt;Ultimate Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; training with Oxford Sharks. We chucked about
until enough people showed up and then did a couple of leading pass and throwing to beat the mark drills. After those we went straight
into pickup games - we were out for about 2 hours. It was pretty good fun, as usual, but my legs were really feeling shot after
playing yesterday and the turbo trainer during the week. Speed felt went down compared to normal and I just generally felt knackered and 
couldn't think right. Going to start going to fitness training some Thursdays though so hopefully that'll help with that! All in all though,
a good session and I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also finally managed to contact the Witney MTB club yesterday so as soon as my lights come I'll be on night rides with them too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frisbee" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-pAOb9U3aL04/UOmisrlFvtI/AAAAAAAABTw/79FijfPkGEQ/s640/IMG_20130106_155110.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-06:posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category><category>ultimate</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 5th Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes I know that I did a food photo yesterday too. I didn't do a lot of note today so I had to use something. I have a book
called "The Curry Secret" that I suspect is likely as old as I am. Pretty much all of the curries use the same base so I made
a couple of litres of that to freeze down and with some of it cooked a standard spicy curry. I only had 2 chicken thighs to use,
 I coated them in paprika and slowly fried them whilst I cooked some other bits, I also added in some potatoes. All in all
a good tasting curry, made completely from scratch, even if I say so myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Curry" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-emY_BTiXWFU/UOiFkBiFfQI/AAAAAAAABTI/5Eh5wfDG-nU/s640/IMG_20130105_194621.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-05:posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 4th Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Todays photo is something that I am rather fond of - food and cooking. I was pretty desperate for ideas so loaded up
&lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/"&gt;all recipes&lt;/a&gt; and whacked "sausages" and "squash" into the recipe finder. To my surprise there
were actually results, I settled on a recipe of &lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/recipe/chef-johns-stuffed-summer-squash/detail.aspx?event8=1&amp;amp;prop24=SR_Title&amp;amp;e8=Quick%20Search&amp;amp;event10=1&amp;amp;e7=Home%20Page&amp;amp;scale=5&amp;amp;ismetric=1"&gt;Chef John's Stuffed Summer Squash&lt;/a&gt;.
I had to make a couple of alterations, cheddar for goats cheese, butternut squash and I also added mushrooms and a couple of chillies; I also
decided to cook up some pasta to have with it. Oh, I also have no idea what Merguez sausages are so I just used standard
ones. As I had some stuffing left after filling the squashes I mixed it into the cooked pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stuffed Squashes" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-0GxFD2EN9SY/UOc19DVON5I/AAAAAAAABSk/d1_dh-fai6A/s640/IMG_20130104_200042.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-04:posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 3rd Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the cat is purely bonus material - the actual focus of the photo is the exercise mat. As a part of my getting fit
kick I'm doing a 30 minute body weight exercise programme thing, 90 seconds per exercise. It's pretty simple to do as it's
&lt;a href="http://dailyworkoutapps.com/dailyworkoutapps/Daily_Workouts.html"&gt;a mobile app&lt;/a&gt; that displays each exercise with
a timer and a video showing what to do. It has a variety of body weight exercises such as push ups, crunches, planks, squats
etc.. I'm doing this on the days that I'm not going on the turbo or doing something else.
So far it's going well, been on the turbo for the last 3 days and hoping that I get into a bit of a routine and it becomes
part of my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat n a Mat" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HM8mL_r0vKU/UOXtg2QezrI/AAAAAAAABRw/yRP2FB9tPjc/s640/IMG_20130103_203053.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-03:posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 2nd Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I picked up my new phone from work (it was delivered on Friday but I've been on leave), it's a Google Nexus 4.
I haven't had much of a play with it yet as I don't yet have a micro sim, I kind of overlooked that small detail. Luckily
one of the guys at work has a cutter and is bringing it in tomorrow. I've setup my Google account on it and whacked
it on our wifi. So far it seems great, I really like the latest versions of Android anyway. The build quality is more
than just a little better than my Wildfire, it feels solid and has a nice weight to it. It's also rather noticably faster.
I haven't tried the camera on it yet but will be doing so for tomorrows photo - here's hoping it's better than the one on
the Wildfire! As of tomorrow the Wildfire is going to Maura. Should also be interesting to see the battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nexus 4" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-SBA93yoj8rA/UOR_eUJh0WI/AAAAAAAABQk/YJnqcIEub7k/s640/IMG_20130102_183909.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-02:posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/</guid><category>photo-a-day</category></item><item><title>2013 Photo a Day</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The new year has rolled round and so I'm once again going to attempt to take a photo a day.
I've tried this for the past 2 years and just failed so this year I'm going to attempt
to write a short blog post about each photo to try to make myself think about what my photo will be.
Hopefully, this year I'll actually manage to do it!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/</guid><category>random</category><category>photo-a-day-2013</category></item><item><title>Photo a day 1st Jan</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Bikes. Since moving to Oxford I have done little on the biking front and this year I would very much like to
rectify that. I've reached out to a local MTB club to see how I go about joining them for rides and I'm
going to try to spend more time on the turbo to improve my general cardio. I should note that this is not
a new years resolution, I believe that making those is just setting yourself up to fail. As of next week I'm
going to have to pack in booze for the most part for medical reasons so getting back on the bike now seems like
an ideal time. Put in the effort now it'll be worth it for Summer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Machines" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-eWDhFsF-RpE/UOLmiAL8G2I/AAAAAAAABQE/F_jpJx1VxII/s640/IMG_20130101_132504.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/</guid><category>bikes</category><category>photo-a-day</category></item></channel></rss>