<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="chvck.co.uk/feeds/Photo-a-Day.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>chvck.co.uk/</id><updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Photo a day 17th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/17/photo-a-day-17th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-17:posts/2013/Jan/17/photo-a-day-17th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scotch eggs. I'm a big, big fan of scotch eggs and last night I decided to create my own. I followed a &lt;a href="http://allrecipes.co.uk/recipe/388/baked-scotch-eggs.aspx"&gt;really simple recipe&lt;/a&gt;
with nothing fancy in the sausage mix as it was my first time. Next time I'll throw some chopped chillies in and some
herbs, I also want to experiment with mini ones and fill them with black pudding and other various fillings. Instead of
buying sausage meat I also bought some OK quality sausages and just removed the skins, seems to have worked quite well.
They taste pretty damn good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scotch Eggs" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-6sbagkHPIQ8/UPhXgVRUDpI/AAAAAAAABck/-1Tdtws-ZdU/s640/IMG_20130117_193033.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 16th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/16/photo-a-day-16th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-16:posts/2013/Jan/16/photo-a-day-16th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another post lacking in any inspiration. This is my "office". So far this week I've managed to work from home 3 times what with
the hospital appointment and potential recovery. It's nothing fancy but gets the job done although it's bloody cold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Office" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-O0zBgziEOU4/UPb3PDQ2dKI/AAAAAAAABbM/zMAn-Hhors8/s640/IMG_20130116_183109.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 15th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/15/photo-a-day-15th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-15:posts/2013/Jan/15/photo-a-day-15th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the view from Neurologoical Out Patients at the John Radcliffe hospital. It appears that I've accidentally
managed to get some reflection from the window in it. Today I was there to get shown how to use my meds and to have my
first injection. It's actually really easy to do and there's a little tool that I use to do it, although I don't have to
and I can just use the needle directly if I want. It's also surprisingly not at all painful although afterward there is
a slight ache/stingy feeling but that went away pretty quickly. Unfortunately it seems that I'm one of the 90% who gets
the flu-like side effects although I just had a headache and raised temperature which made it a bit hard to sleep but nothing
I can't live with and get used to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-zBXNngNkoMs/UPWWphHvlAI/AAAAAAAABbE/mVydRbn62zk/s640/IMG_20130115_161315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 14th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/14/photo-a-day-14th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-14:posts/2013/Jan/14/photo-a-day-14th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This isn't a very exciting post. Last night it snowed a little so there was a fine dusting around. It was enough to
make everything look nice but not be annoying, it'd also all melted by lunch time. I'm not really a big fan of snow so if it doesn't
snow again this year then that suits me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-laqQH2CmAGs/UPR0PNk7HnI/AAAAAAAABao/DLKUJTFTDZw/s640/IMG_20130114_085226.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 13th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/13/photo-a-day-13th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-13:posts/2013/Jan/13/photo-a-day-13th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a night out last night to celebrate Ben's birthday we managed to fail to get out of bed until 10am. On the way to breakfast,
to stoke our engines ready for another ride, we decided to go have and visit the seafront. We didn't stay there long, the wind
was pretty chilling! Nice to be there though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Aberystwyth Seafront" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-QU01f1RSRDI/UPPGK4AjSeI/AAAAAAAABZ8/Hh6aBQa2eeg/s640/IMG_20130113_103755.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 12th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/12/photo-a-day-12th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-12:posts/2013/Jan/12/photo-a-day-12th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of Ben's Aberystwyth biking weekend. We did the Summit loop at nant-y-arian plus a few little extras.
This was the first time that I'd ever carried a hip flask on a ride, why have I never done that before?! It was a great ride and
I felt fitter than I have for quite some time although I was at full on pootle pace. This photo is from midway up the leg burner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Water" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-H1xBuP6ee1o/UPPFr9eHpaI/AAAAAAAABZw/cludjQEJ-_M/s640/IMG_20130112_144252.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 11th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/11/photo-a-day-11th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-11:posts/2013/Jan/11/photo-a-day-11th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend is about bikes. It was Ben's birthday on Monday so he's organised a weekend in Aberystwyth. I came to Rich's tonight as he lives closer and we have an early start. We decided that we'd do a night ride around the lickey hills. Prior to tonight I'd never even ridden here before. The ride was really muddy but really good fun, can't wait to ride here in summer! This was also the debut for the light and it was really good, very impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Night ride" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-7yF3dJ5w-8I/UPFA3AakCRI/AAAAAAAABWg/nsD3x0nqYkk/s640/IMG_20130111_210322.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category><category term="riding"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 10th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/10/photo-a-day-10th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-10:posts/2013/Jan/10/photo-a-day-10th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tiny, fatty cat. I got given a massive bean bag for christmas from my family, and I mean massive. It is ridiculously comfortable.
I'm not the only one who thinks this, it's become Tesla's favourite place to hang out; she loves it! Our current mission for the
next month or two is try get her to lose weight, about 1/2kg down to 4kg. On new years day we went along to our local
Pets At Home who run a free weight &amp;amp; nutrition clinic. The guy gave her a check over to check she looks OK and took her weight.
He then worked out a feeding plan for us, 30g twice a day, dropping to 25g twice a day after a while. Pretty good service and it
was free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-cg7eRm7PiYI/UO8vlWhv2CI/AAAAAAAABVk/i1tyO0DqnyE/s640/IMG_20130110_211413.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 9th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/09/photo-a-day-9th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-09:posts/2013/Jan/09/photo-a-day-9th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Iddy biddy coffee machine. As part of my mission, and yes it really is a mission, to get up earlier
in the mornings I purchased this tiny coffee machine. It's a filter drip so was a pretty safe bet as you can't really
go too far wrong with that! The two cups hold about the volume of 1.5 espressos each which is pretty good for a morning
wake up call. Hopefully I can persuade myself to wake up a bit earlier from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tiny coffee machine" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mpzq-v0R-IY/UO3g-Lj1A2I/AAAAAAAABVM/uW_x9DFO5AU/s640/IMG_20130109_203226.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 8th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/08/photo-a-day-8th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-08:posts/2013/Jan/08/photo-a-day-8th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my new mtb light arrived at the office and I picked it up today, given that it had an expected delivery date of
2nd Feb I was pretty surprised! It cost me £20 from &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006RHB41Y/ref=pe_217191_31005151_3p_dp_1"&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;.
At 20 quid I wasn't sure what to expect but 2 of my mates have the same unit and have had it for quite a while so I confident
that it was a good gamble. I was expecting it to be plastic and a bit rattley but it's actually metal and feels nicely solid.
The battery pack hasn't convinced me that it'll hold up to any serious rain but as i plan on throwing that in my backpack anyway
it isn't a big deal. Seems like it should be plenty bright enough - the case claims 1200 lumens but I know that's not
gonna happen. I'm fairly certain it's a cree T6 LED which has a theoretical maximum of 1200 lumens but I've also
seen lab results of tests on it, in ideal conditions in the lab they don't really even reach 1000 lumens! None-the-less
it looks like a good little unit and I can't wait to get out and use it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bike light" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-lT_-G7px7b0/UOxvoGHA7ZI/AAAAAAAABUk/lB_VTHidXjQ/s640/IMG_20130108_190939.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="bikes"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 7th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-07:posts/2013/Jan/07/photo-a-day-7th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to write much about this here as I plan to write another post about the whole thing. This is my first batch
of meds and next Tuesday I find out how to use them, that Wednesday could be interesting... I even got given a bin though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meds" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-JYb2HhlaE3Y/UOsTJftcj5I/AAAAAAAABUA/rWFvSsH8QRc/s640/IMG_20130107_180630.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 6th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-06:posts/2013/Jan/06/photo-a-day-6th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I went to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultimate_(sport)"&gt;Ultimate Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; training with Oxford Sharks. We chucked about
until enough people showed up and then did a couple of leading pass and throwing to beat the mark drills. After those we went straight
into pickup games - we were out for about 2 hours. It was pretty good fun, as usual, but my legs were really feeling shot after
playing yesterday and the turbo trainer during the week. Speed felt went down compared to normal and I just generally felt knackered and 
couldn't think right. Going to start going to fitness training some Thursdays though so hopefully that'll help with that! All in all though,
a good session and I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also finally managed to contact the Witney MTB club yesterday so as soon as my lights come I'll be on night rides with them too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frisbee" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-pAOb9U3aL04/UOmisrlFvtI/AAAAAAAABTw/79FijfPkGEQ/s640/IMG_20130106_155110.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category><category term="ultimate"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 5th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-05:posts/2013/Jan/05/photo-a-day-5th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes I know that I did a food photo yesterday too. I didn't do a lot of note today so I had to use something. I have a book
called "The Curry Secret" that I suspect is likely as old as I am. Pretty much all of the curries use the same base so I made
a couple of litres of that to freeze down and with some of it cooked a standard spicy curry. I only had 2 chicken thighs to use,
 I coated them in paprika and slowly fried them whilst I cooked some other bits, I also added in some potatoes. All in all
a good tasting curry, made completely from scratch, even if I say so myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Curry" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-emY_BTiXWFU/UOiFkBiFfQI/AAAAAAAABTI/5Eh5wfDG-nU/s640/IMG_20130105_194621.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 4th Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-04:posts/2013/Jan/04/photo-a-day-4th-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Todays photo is something that I am rather fond of - food and cooking. I was pretty desperate for ideas so loaded up
&lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/"&gt;all recipes&lt;/a&gt; and whacked "sausages" and "squash" into the recipe finder. To my surprise there
were actually results, I settled on a recipe of &lt;a href="http://allrecipes.com/recipe/chef-johns-stuffed-summer-squash/detail.aspx?event8=1&amp;amp;prop24=SR_Title&amp;amp;e8=Quick%20Search&amp;amp;event10=1&amp;amp;e7=Home%20Page&amp;amp;scale=5&amp;amp;ismetric=1"&gt;Chef John's Stuffed Summer Squash&lt;/a&gt;.
I had to make a couple of alterations, cheddar for goats cheese, butternut squash and I also added mushrooms and a couple of chillies; I also
decided to cook up some pasta to have with it. Oh, I also have no idea what Merguez sausages are so I just used standard
ones. As I had some stuffing left after filling the squashes I mixed it into the cooked pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stuffed Squashes" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-0GxFD2EN9SY/UOc19DVON5I/AAAAAAAABSk/d1_dh-fai6A/s640/IMG_20130104_200042.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 3rd Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-03:posts/2013/Jan/03/photo-a-day-3rd-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the cat is purely bonus material - the actual focus of the photo is the exercise mat. As a part of my getting fit
kick I'm doing a 30 minute body weight exercise programme thing, 90 seconds per exercise. It's pretty simple to do as it's
&lt;a href="http://dailyworkoutapps.com/dailyworkoutapps/Daily_Workouts.html"&gt;a mobile app&lt;/a&gt; that displays each exercise with
a timer and a video showing what to do. It has a variety of body weight exercises such as push ups, crunches, planks, squats
etc.. I'm doing this on the days that I'm not going on the turbo or doing something else.
So far it's going well, been on the turbo for the last 3 days and hoping that I get into a bit of a routine and it becomes
part of my day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat n a Mat" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HM8mL_r0vKU/UOXtg2QezrI/AAAAAAAABRw/yRP2FB9tPjc/s640/IMG_20130103_203053.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 2nd Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-02:posts/2013/Jan/02/photo-a-day-2nd-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I picked up my new phone from work (it was delivered on Friday but I've been on leave), it's a Google Nexus 4.
I haven't had much of a play with it yet as I don't yet have a micro sim, I kind of overlooked that small detail. Luckily
one of the guys at work has a cutter and is bringing it in tomorrow. I've setup my Google account on it and whacked
it on our wifi. So far it seems great, I really like the latest versions of Android anyway. The build quality is more
than just a little better than my Wildfire, it feels solid and has a nice weight to it. It's also rather noticably faster.
I haven't tried the camera on it yet but will be doing so for tomorrows photo - here's hoping it's better than the one on
the Wildfire! As of tomorrow the Wildfire is going to Maura. Should also be interesting to see the battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nexus 4" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-SBA93yoj8rA/UOR_eUJh0WI/AAAAAAAABQk/YJnqcIEub7k/s640/IMG_20130102_183909.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry><entry><title>2013 Photo a Day</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/2013-photo-a-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new year has rolled round and so I'm once again going to attempt to take a photo a day.
I've tried this for the past 2 years and just failed so this year I'm going to attempt
to write a short blog post about each photo to try to make myself think about what my photo will be.
Hopefully, this year I'll actually manage to do it!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="random"></category><category term="photo-a-day-2013"></category></entry><entry><title>Photo a day 1st Jan</title><link href="chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>chuck</name></author><id>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-01-01:posts/2013/Jan/01/photo-a-day-1st-jan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bikes. Since moving to Oxford I have done little on the biking front and this year I would very much like to
rectify that. I've reached out to a local MTB club to see how I go about joining them for rides and I'm
going to try to spend more time on the turbo to improve my general cardio. I should note that this is not
a new years resolution, I believe that making those is just setting yourself up to fail. As of next week I'm
going to have to pack in booze for the most part for medical reasons so getting back on the bike now seems like
an ideal time. Put in the effort now it'll be worth it for Summer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Machines" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-eWDhFsF-RpE/UOLmiAL8G2I/AAAAAAAABQE/F_jpJx1VxII/s640/IMG_20130101_132504.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bikes"></category><category term="photo-a-day"></category></entry></feed>