<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/</link><description>Pointless, sometimes amusing and deeply, deeply uninteresting to 99.72998% of the population</description><atom:link href="http://chvck.co.uk/feeds/review.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scoopfree Litter Tray</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/15/scoopfree-litter-tray/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a bit off the beaten path of bike related things that I usually write about. 
This post is about a cat litter tray system called &lt;a href="http://www.scoopfree.com/"&gt;Scoopfree&lt;/a&gt;, it's
one of those things that actually makes a difference. As the name suggests there's no scooping
cat poo with this machine, you simply insert a cartridge and off you go until it's time
to fit a new cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way that this thing works is that it has a sensor (light beam I think) that when crossed triggers
what I'd called an event. Once this event has occured then the litterbox counts down for 20 minutes (light
blinks to let you know) and then it self-cleans. The self-clean process is simply a rake that runs down the
tray and deposits the cat poo, dirty litter etc... in a compartment and then it runs back up. You'd think that
this would smell pretty bad but it doesn't! They send a special form of litter that absorbs the smell, obviously
it does start to get a bit stinky if you leave replacing the cartridge too long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cartidge lasts about a month for us with just Tesla to worry about and each one costs about a tenner
from &lt;a href="http://www.vetuk.co.uk/"&gt;Vets UK&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of a work day when you're tired it's nice to come home and not have to 
muck about with cat poo. It's expensive for what it is but I do like having it around, especially as Tesla still insists
on attacking it every time that it rakes! We've had it a few months now too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NWcrZGTnoco" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-15:posts/2013/Mar/15/scoopfree-litter-tray/</guid><category>bikes</category></item><item><title>KS Lev seatpost</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Mar/13/ks-lev-seatpost/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I ordered one of those from &lt;a href="http://superstarcomponents.com"&gt;Superstar&lt;/a&gt; yesterday and was pretty impressed
when it turned up today. It feels like a nice piece of kit and is well finished. I also go free
Haribo, yay! Anyway, on to the fitting, the instructions say to cut the outer into 2 pieces to 
enable you to fit a barrel adjuster, I chose not to bother and to see how it faired without it. 
Cutting the cables to size is slightly fiddly as the end piece has to be very exact and can't have
cable sticking out. It took me a good while to get this bit right and get it fitted but wasn't too difficult.
As a little bonus the lever can also act as a lock-on for an ODI compatible grip which is pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lever" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-XPK_98JvAgc/UUDtQONsDZI/AAAAAAAABtM/MturoBao0i4/s640/IMG_20130313_205850.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was the saddle, this is a lesson in why not to skip several pages of instructions as I wound
up with my saddle pointing 90 degrees to where it should have been so I had to take it back off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sideways Saddle" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HMMHSt-HgKM/UUDtLKgunVI/AAAAAAAABs8/SqD9Qm7M7yU/s640/IMG_20130313_204355.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that the cradle for the saddle can be turned to various positions, bonus. To do this you have to take the head
of the seatpost apart and unscrew the valve cap for the air - I took this opportunity to add a bit more air 
also. Once done I refitted the seatpost and wadda ya know, pointing in the correct direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works well and feels smooth going through the travel. Thus far impressed - can't wait to take it on a ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Saddle Up" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/--ioQA0FGlSY/UUDtNPulIRI/AAAAAAAABtE/aTFIWs8A0kE/s640/IMG_20130313_205828.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Saddle Down" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-uV6k3fFhzxE/UUDtSo6B1SI/AAAAAAAABtU/yO28V6RXxb8/s640/IMG_20130313_205843.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-03-13:posts/2013/Mar/13/ks-lev-seatpost/</guid><category>bikes</category></item><item><title>Superstar Excel Grips</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Feb/28/superstar-excel-grips/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I had to take to my old Oury grips with a hacksaw due one of the bolts on
a lock ring getting rounded. I took this as a sign that it was time for new grips
in my new colour scheme. I decided to give the superstar excel grips a go, went for
yellow cartridges (replacable too) with green lock rings; they also come with black
end caps. They arrived today and on first impressions they look good. The compound is soft
and they feel really grippy and nice n fat. They're also really, really long! The colours
are pretty vibrant and they look nice, the photo doesn't really do them justice on the vibrancy. 
For a tenner I think that they might be a bit of a steal,
time will tell how well they get on, the Oury's are going into the toolbox as spares just in
case. Only negative thing I can say is that I didn't get any Haribo with my order!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Superstar Excel Grips" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-x6CH10peUi8/US_AH7lvDoI/AAAAAAAABno/jKtrUPvhj_E/s640/IMG_20130228_203627.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-02-28:posts/2013/Feb/28/superstar-excel-grips/</guid><category>bikes</category></item></channel></rss>