<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/</link><description>Pointless, sometimes amusing and deeply, deeply uninteresting to 99.72998% of the population</description><atom:link href="http://chvck.co.uk/feeds/summary.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aberystwyth Easter Trip</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Apr/01/aberystwyth-easter-trip/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Easter weekend we had decided to rent out a caravan and do the nant-mach-nant ride. There would be Ben, Rich,
Jase, Pete, Rob and myself staying in the caravan and we'd do the ride with Dave and the ystwyth MTB crew.
We also planned to do a bit of Clarach and maybe Myherin too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early start, packed the car and was en-route to Ben's at 6.20am. The drive was good and I turned up
at 8.20, I had to wait 5 minutes for Ben to turn up but then we cracked on with the bike fettling. On my list of
things were to do were: cut down steerer, check damper circuit for fluid, change brake pads, perform volume
reduction mod on shock, bleed front brake and change chain ring. Not a huge list but these things always take time,
surprisingly we had an hour to spare before Rich turned up at about 11.30. A bit of fettling on his bike and we
were on our way to aber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fettling with my bike" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/5271_10151819648193765_874543417_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A bit of fettling with my bike!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shimming my shock" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/66853_10151819648513765_1327594937_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Adding a shim to my shock for the volume reduction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather on the drive over to aber was sunny the whole way and aber itself no different. We checked in at
&lt;a href="http://www.aberystwyth-holidays.co.uk/"&gt;Aberystwyth holiday village&lt;/a&gt; and headed over to the caravan to
get changed and drop stuff off. The caravan was pretty big. Basic but everything we needed. We did everything
that we needed and cracked on over to Clarach woods for some mini-DH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Driving to aber" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/543703_10151819649293765_892519870_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The drive over to aber&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trails were dry and riding brilliantly.
We spent a couple of hours there riding various tracks before heading back to the caravan. This was the first proper
downhill stuff that I'd ridden on my full sus and it was taking a bit of getting used to but felt really good.
We got back to the caravan park just after the other guys pulled in which worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Caravan" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/164983_10151819649823765_950997680_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The main living space in the caravan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Clarach" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/57959_10151819650313765_128179108_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Dry as a bone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Berms" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/521747_10151819651068765_1133602810_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Berms" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526561_10151819650758765_237109502_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/539242_10151819653353765_390480424_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/534124_10151819653938765_1899181661_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Clarach Bay" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/6746_10151819654173765_1866672761_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Bay" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/558936_442109679197562_1498288363_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;© Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big ride day. We were going to do the nant to mach and back with the ystwyth mtb guys. We managed to get to
Morrisons at about 9.15 to get some breakfast at the cafe and grab some riding food. The cafe food was somewhat
less than average! We turned up to Pendam car park at about 10 to find Dave and Pete already there ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/564739_10151819654738765_811641672_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A bit of breakfast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of faffing and we were off out away from nant on the conti loop. At this point I feel I should mention
that the fresh brake pads meant that my front wheel wasn't spinning freely at all! Anyway, we got to Anglers Retreat in fairly good
time but there was a bit of snow on the ground. Dave and Pete made the decision to try a different route out to the mach 3
as they expected too much snow on the other. We cracked on and were met with deep snow and icy conditions everywhere.
Dave floated the idea that we maybe abandon the plan as it'd just be a slog and not much fun. In the end we came
up with the idea to ride to the mach 3 and then back to nant on a slightly different route to make a bit of a loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lovely day" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/733889_10151819654963765_2082049772_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;A lovely day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nant-y-moch" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734492_10151819655828765_1119090350_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Looking out over nant-y-moch resevoir&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/48116_10151819656598765_31869313_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;It begins...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snow didn't improve, we spent quite a lot of time hiking the bikes through the snow with the odd bit of riding where
the snow was conpact enough to allow it or the trail went downhill. I had a nice lie down/slide on my arse going
round a corner and had thought I'd broken my lev but it turned out to be a bit of outer cabling had got stuck, phew!
We got back to Anglers Retreat via scaletrix and most of the ride back to the conti loop was actually ride-able. We did
the ace descent back down to the conti loop and returned to nant via sidewinder and hippity hop. At this point
Dave and Pete headed off home but Ben was keen to go do a bit more riding. There was a general lack of motivation
within the rest of the group though. I was shot but if everyone else wanted to keep going I was happy to do so on the conditions
that I'd probably have to walk the worst bits of climbs. In the end we decided to call it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A bit of a walk" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734571_10151819657043765_1569007908_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;There was plenty of this!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Blazing Bikes" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/46872_10151819657683765_475132321_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Represent&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sideways" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/392589_10151819658598765_876990918_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Jase getting it sideways&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dry" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/483697_10151819660983765_659377075_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;What, no snow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fantastic day out that, whilst it didn't go to plan, was still great fun and a bit of an adventure. Big thanks to
Dave and Pete for guiding us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we wound up in Lopburi Thai Restraunt for food and as always the food was top notch. I had a chicken
panang curry made "as hot as you can". It was most excellent. We popped along to spoons for a pint to start the night out.
After said pint we wound up going back to the caravan park due to everyone being knackered!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more photos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Frozen" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/305946_10151819656773765_2054192978_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/485160_10151819658158765_1498120005_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Log stack" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/488273_10151819658933765_1101820806_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/299168_10151819659258765_1853766489_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/65763_10151819660133765_2014661651_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/73358_10151819661123765_114172002_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nomad" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-g-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/537222_442109772530886_159775249_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;© Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Riding" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734533_442109969197533_241260023_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;© Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had no plans for Sunday other than to just ride something. We had a bit of a slow morning getting up late
and tidying the caravan/packing our stuff away. We wound up having a Spoons breakfast and we about ready to go
ride at midday, destination: Clarach. Having seen how dry it was on Friday and we had such a good laugh we decided that
we had to go back and to also show the other guys who hadn't been there before. We spent a good 4-5 hours in the woods
and had a brilliant time. Rob, Ben and I did the big double which was a big thing for Ben as it managed to get in his
head and he's spent about 3 years trying to get up to doing it. The trails were riding brilliant and were all
really fast, was a brilliant way to spend the afternoon and I think that the only crash was mine too! Luckily I got
out unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Eyeing up" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526546_10151819668003765_1073678688_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Classic stand and look at it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ben" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/734390_10151819673608765_1860750977_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ben overshooting it like a boss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jump" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/5344_10151819664933765_611946596_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drop" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/575815_10151819665633765_1139055512_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Me" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/58054_10151819665863765_1471258651_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Clarach" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/299198_10151819666248765_1339011001_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Rob" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-f-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/72696_10151819672993765_2081129368_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Me" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/483481_10151819673288765_2016999412_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Standing about" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-frc1/46888_10151819674083765_1709532522_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Corner" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-b-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/529170_10151819674618765_1533253125_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nomad" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/392723_442110122530851_413810993_n.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;© Copyright Rich Grundy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a brilliant weekend of bikes and big thanks to everyone who made it what it was.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-04-01:posts/2013/Apr/01/aberystwyth-easter-trip/</guid><category>bikes</category><category>riding</category></item><item><title>Catching up</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2013/Feb/18/catching-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly I'll start off with the demise of my photo a day. Quite simple - I just don't do enough varying things
in my day to day life. I found myself remembering that I hadn't taken a photo and having to hunt for something around the house.
That wasn't the way that I had wanted to do it, I'd wanted to just take a photo of something significant each day and not
had to think about taking the photo, just doing it. For that reason, I stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let's talk bikes, surprise surprise. The Intense is pretty awesome and I'm very much enjoying riding it. I recently did a ride around
Boars Hill which is local to me and has very little elevation. Despite being on a totally inappropriate bike it was still good fun
and the Intense pedals much better and easier than I had expected. I've also changed my drivetrain and accidentally bought an 11-32 cassette, this
hasn't been an issue yet either which surprised me a little. I really need to get the bike over to some Welsh trails I know well to give it a proper
good testing.
    As we're on the subject, a couple of weeks ago we went to Forest of Dean which was pretty rad. We started out doing the blue loop which was quite flowy
and undulating. The final descent of it is pretty awesome. We also rode a few of the DH tracks; really good too! The weekend just gone we went to explore
around Birdlip near Gloucs. That was not so great, really deep thick mud everywhere. We did 25km in over 4 hours! I also swear that we didn't even do a single
semi-decent descent. We did quite a bit of hiking with the bikes too, which really destroyed my legs where I've recently jabbed. It turned into one of those
rides where I just wanted to be back at the car. Best bit of the ride was a pint &amp;amp; fish n chips in the pub!
    On the jabs note, I recently discovered that my pack came with a cooling pad that lives in the fridge and you put on where you're about to jab.
Wow, I was pretty amazed at just how effective that thing is! Really takes away any pain at the time of doing it, doesn't stop it aching the next day mind but
that doesn't happen to me often anyway!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2013-02-18:posts/2013/Feb/18/catching-up/</guid><category>bikes</category><category>riding</category></item><item><title>I'm not dead!</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Been a little while since I made any posts, about 3 weeks in fact - feels a lot longer I can tell you.
May as well start at the beginning - the move. Well, actually there's not a lot to say on that front,
it all went rather well really. Everything was packed and in the vehicles (Ben came to help with his van) by about 2pm
I think. The drive itself was fine, no mishaps or owt. Upon arriving at the new house we pretty much just got everything
out of the vehicles and dumped it all in the house before shooting into Oxford for some food. Sunday we went and rode
Aston Hill, wow that place is slick in the wet! My brakes were still binding terribly so the push up was pretty damn
unenjoyable though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, 3.5 weeks on and the house is a bit more presentable and has a touch more furniture - we're still sleeping
on a sofa bed though. We managed to get a book cake and a bureau from one of my work colleagues and just yesterday we picked
up a small cupboard Maura spotted on freecycle. I have an office setup in the spare bedroom which is serving me well. (ha, we've just had a power cut
as I type this) The cat appears to have settled in no problems and has tackled the great outdoors of the back yard.
Not a lot else to say on this matter really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's happened in the time period since moving here? Actually, not really that much again. Seb got married the first
weekend which was pretty cool and was fun! I've been on one road ride with Jimbo and will hopefully increase the frequency
of the road rides by joining a local club called Zappi's. I went on the speed awareness course because I got caught speeding
(might actually write a post about that...). Most of the time has just been spent working or sitting around really!
But all is going well and hopefully Maura will find a job soon which will take the financial strain off!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-07-24:posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/</guid><category>random</category></item><item><title>Week Summary</title><link>http://chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the past week I've managed to get out on the mountain bike 3 times which isn't bad really! On Sunday
Ben and I drove to Rich's place after leaving the hotel from Seb's stag do. We spent quite a lot of time tinkering with
bikes and for once we didn't have to tinker with mine! We headed to the Wyre Forest, somewhere that I'd not been before.
After a bacon sandwich from the cafe we set off riding, this place reminded me quite a lot of Swinley Forest. The surface
was quite sandy and I could hear my drivetrain grinding as we were riding round. It was quite an enjoyable little blast,
none of the hills were particularly big but there were lots of short little descents and climbs which was quite fun. A few steep bits
but for the most part it was just flat out with very little tech, which suited me having had a few beers the night before. Ben
managed to have a pretty decent sized crash off the side of one of the trails that saw his bike go pinwheeling off down the
side of the hill but he was OK. Pretty fun place, good singletrack! Once again we managed to resemble a Cotic fanclub as
the image below shows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Brace of Cotics" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-4y1gahqJ_Fc/T7diyQyMf-I/AAAAAAAABHU/cl2cw2CntEo/s400/IMG_20120513_131943.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other two rides I've done this week have both been up Nant-y-arian. Wednesday night I popped up with Andy and
we did the usual Ystwyth loop, climbing up to Hippity Hop car park, doing the Summit loop and then back via White Fridge, my
favourite loop! It was a pretty uneventful ride but, as ever, top fun. I played the no pedal game down most of the descents
as I'm trying to develop my skills to gain speed from the trail and try to brake less. We managed to get round the 25km in just
under 2 hours which we were pretty happy with, we didn't ride especially quick we just didn't take any breaks. The other ride we
did on Friday night, again with Andy but this time with Tom too. We started at Hippity Hop and just did a standard Summit loop.
For some reason this was a really, really fun ride. We took our time (16km in just over 2 hours) and just generally messed about.
Following Andy really is great fun, he jumps off loads of little things and is very stylish to watch. Taking his lines and
trying to do all the little jumps that he does is ace! That boy really is rather good on a bike. We had a bit of a mechanical
midway up the leg burner when Tom's chain went bang but other than that it was fairly plain sailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nant-y-arian viewpoint" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jAxPNMnOOx8/T7di-TLRZfI/AAAAAAAABHc/TAeHUHXIPR0/s640/IMG_20120518_195035.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this week I've playing with nodejs for work. I'm pretty impressed, using the express framework I've managed to knock
something together for our platform pretty quickly and easily! I'm also very much loving using javascript on both the back and
front end. As a part of this I've also been learning to use Jade templates, this has meant no static pages and each page generated
on the fly. This has also enabled me to do some pretty funky stuff although unfortunately can't really go into detail.
I do have 1 tip for using couchdb. If you want to access it from anywhere that isn't localhost then you need to go into the
local config file and change the bindings to 0.0.0.0 from 127.0.0.1, this may be a little less secure as it opens couchdb up to
requests from any interface but it took me about 2 hours of trying to get a proxy to use work before finding that out! I also
wound up using this nodejs proxy server that is pretty simple and works: &lt;a href="http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/"&gt;http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-19:posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/</guid><category>bikes</category><category>riding</category><category>nant-y-arian</category><category>javascript</category></item></channel></rss>