<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>chvck.co.uk</title><link>chvck.co.uk/</link><description>Pointless, sometimes amusing and deeply, deeply uninteresting to 99.72998% of the population</description><atom:link href="chvck.co.uk/feeds/Summary.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>I'm not dead!</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Been a little while since I made any posts, about 3 weeks in fact - feels a lot longer I can tell you.
May as well start at the beginning - the move. Well, actually there's not a lot to say on that front,
it all went rather well really. Everything was packed and in the vehicles (Ben came to help with his van) by about 2pm
I think. The drive itself was fine, no mishaps or owt. Upon arriving at the new house we pretty much just got everything
out of the vehicles and dumped it all in the house before shooting into Oxford for some food. Sunday we went and rode
Aston Hill, wow that place is slick in the wet! My brakes were still binding terribly so the push up was pretty damn
unenjoyable though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, 3.5 weeks on and the house is a bit more presentable and has a touch more furniture - we're still sleeping
on a sofa bed though. We managed to get a book cake and a bureau from one of my work colleagues and just yesterday we picked
up a small cupboard Maura spotted on freecycle. I have an office setup in the spare bedroom which is serving me well. (ha, we've just had a power cut
as I type this) The cat appears to have settled in no problems and has tackled the great outdoors of the back yard.
Not a lot else to say on this matter really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what's happened in the time period since moving here? Actually, not really that much again. Seb got married the first
weekend which was pretty cool and was fun! I've been on one road ride with Jimbo and will hopefully increase the frequency
of the road rides by joining a local club called Zappi's. I went on the speed awareness course because I got caught speeding
(might actually write a post about that...). Most of the time has just been spent working or sitting around really!
But all is going well and hopefully Maura will find a job soon which will take the financial strain off!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-07-24:posts/2012/Jul/24/im-not-dead/</guid><category>random</category></item><item><title>Week Summary</title><link>chvck.co.uk/posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the past week I've managed to get out on the mountain bike 3 times which isn't bad really! On Sunday
Ben and I drove to Rich's place after leaving the hotel from Seb's stag do. We spent quite a lot of time tinkering with
bikes and for once we didn't have to tinker with mine! We headed to the Wyre Forest, somewhere that I'd not been before.
After a bacon sandwich from the cafe we set off riding, this place reminded me quite a lot of Swinley Forest. The surface
was quite sandy and I could hear my drivetrain grinding as we were riding round. It was quite an enjoyable little blast,
none of the hills were particularly big but there were lots of short little descents and climbs which was quite fun. A few steep bits
but for the most part it was just flat out with very little tech, which suited me having had a few beers the night before. Ben
managed to have a pretty decent sized crash off the side of one of the trails that saw his bike go pinwheeling off down the
side of the hill but he was OK. Pretty fun place, good singletrack! Once again we managed to resemble a Cotic fanclub as
the image below shows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/87844010&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Brace of Cotics" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-4y1gahqJ_Fc/T7diyQyMf-I/AAAAAAAABHU/cl2cw2CntEo/s400/IMG_20120513_131943.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other two rides I've done this week have both been up Nant-y-arian. Wednesday night I popped up with Andy and
we did the usual Ystwyth loop, climbing up to Hippity Hop car park, doing the Summit loop and then back via White Fridge, my
favourite loop! It was a pretty uneventful ride but, as ever, top fun. I played the no pedal game down most of the descents
as I'm trying to develop my skills to gain speed from the trail and try to brake less. We managed to get round the 25km in just
under 2 hours which we were pretty happy with, we didn't ride especially quick we just didn't take any breaks. The other ride we
did on Friday night, again with Andy but this time with Tom too. We started at Hippity Hop and just did a standard Summit loop.
For some reason this was a really, really fun ride. We took our time (16km in just over 2 hours) and just generally messed about.
Following Andy really is great fun, he jumps off loads of little things and is very stylish to watch. Taking his lines and
trying to do all the little jumps that he does is ace! That boy really is rather good on a bike. We had a bit of a mechanical
midway up the leg burner when Tom's chain went bang but other than that it was fairly plain sailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88520763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583"&gt;http://runkeeper.com/user/chvck/activity/88981583&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nant-y-arian viewpoint" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jAxPNMnOOx8/T7di-TLRZfI/AAAAAAAABHc/TAeHUHXIPR0/s640/IMG_20120518_195035.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this week I've playing with nodejs for work. I'm pretty impressed, using the express framework I've managed to knock
something together for our platform pretty quickly and easily! I'm also very much loving using javascript on both the back and
front end. As a part of this I've also been learning to use Jade templates, this has meant no static pages and each page generated
on the fly. This has also enabled me to do some pretty funky stuff although unfortunately can't really go into detail.
I do have 1 tip for using couchdb. If you want to access it from anywhere that isn't localhost then you need to go into the
local config file and change the bindings to 0.0.0.0 from 127.0.0.1, this may be a little less secure as it opens couchdb up to
requests from any interface but it took me about 2 hours of trying to get a proxy to use work before finding that out! I also
wound up using this nodejs proxy server that is pretty simple and works: &lt;a href="http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/"&gt;http://www.catonmat.net/http-proxy-in-nodejs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">chuck</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:chvck.co.uk,2012-05-19:posts/2012/May/19/week-summary/</guid><category>bikes</category><category>riding</category><category>nant-y-arian</category><category>javascript</category></item></channel></rss>